mm	O
&	O
m	O
's	O
top	O
health	O
technology	O
stories	O
of	O
2016	O
photo	O
credit	O
:	O
jon	ORG
simon/feature	ORG
photo	ORG
service	ORG
for	ORG
ibm	ORG
1	O
.	O
how	O
watson	O
for	O
oncology	O
is	O
advancing	O
cancer	O
care	O
three	O
years	O
ago	O
,	O
memorial	O
sloan-kettering	O
and	O
ibm	ORG
watson	O
formed	O
a	O
partnership	O
to	O
develop	O
watson	O
for	O
oncology	O
,	O
a	O
cognitive	O
computing	O
system	O
that	O
can	O
analyze	O
large	O
volumes	O
of	O
data	O
including	O
medical	O
literature	O
,	O
patient	O
health	O
records	O
,	O
and	O
clinical	O
trials	O
,	O
to	O
offer	O
personalized	O
,	O
evidence-based	O
treatment	O
recommendations	O
for	O
cancer	O
patients	O
.	O
photo	O
credit	O
:	O
klick	O
health	O
2	O
.	O
3	O
health	O
tech	O
innovations	O
experts	O
say	O
will	O
revolutionalize	O
healthcare	O
“	O
this	O
is	O
the	O
most	O
interesting	O
time	O
in	O
the	O
history	O
of	O
healthcare	O
and	O
medicine	O
,	O
”	O
says	O
zen	O
chu	O
,	O
md	O
of	O
accelerated	O
medical	O
ventures	O
and	O
senior	O
lecturer	O
at	O
the	O
mit	ORG
sloan	ORG
school	ORG
of	O
management	O
.	O
“	O
we	O
've	O
got	O
so	O
many	O
new	O
technologies	O
and	O
redesigned	O
experiences	O
impacting	O
both	O
the	O
value	O
we	O
deliver	O
,	O
and	O
also	O
the	O
value	O
patients	O
are	O
getting	O
from	O
healthcare.	O
”	O
photo	O
credit	O
:	O
facebook	ORG
3	O
.	O
10	O
things	O
for	O
pharma	ORG
marketers	O
to	O
know	O
about	O
facebook	ORG
and	O
instagram	ORG
“	O
when	O
you	O
think	O
back	O
in	O
the	O
day	O
,	O
people	O
used	O
to	O
have	O
really	O
personal	O
relationships	O
with	O
their	O
physician	O
and	O
pharmacist	O
.	O
we	O
got	O
a	O
little	O
away	O
from	O
that	O
,	O
but	O
we	O
believe	O
that	O
facebook	ORG
can	O
help	O
bring	O
that	O
back	O
and	O
help	O
pharma	ORG
reconnect	O
with	O
people	O
one-on-one	O
,	O
”	O
said	O
facebook	ORG
health	O
industry	O
manager	O
danielle	PERS
salowski	PERS
.	O
photo	O
credit	O
:	O
uncalno	ORG
tekno/creative	ORG
commons	ORG
4	O
.	O
8	O
ways	O
for	O
pharma	ORG
to	O
improve	O
the	O
way	O
it	O
uses	O
twitter	ORG
when	O
it	O
comes	O
to	O
incorporating	O
digital	O
and	O
social	O
media	O
in	O
their	O
marketing	O
strategies	O
,	O
drugmakers	O
'	O
efforts	O
are	O
still	O
overshadowed	O
by	O
fear	O
.	O
that	O
's	O
according	O
to	O
mary	PERS
ann	PERS
belliveau	PERS
,	O
twitter	ORG
's	O
national	O
health	O
and	O
wellness	O
director	O
.	O
there	O
's	O
a	O
misperception	O
that	O
drugmakers	O
ca	O
n't	O
use	O
the	O
platform	O
because	O
of	O
regulatory	O
limitations	O
but	O
in	O
fact	O
many	O
firms	O
are	O
doing	O
it	O
and	O
doing	O
it	O
well	O
,	O
she	O
noted	O
.	O
photo	O
credit	O
:	O
andy	ORG
de/creative	ORG
commons	ORG
5	O
.	O
pharma	ORG
turns	O
to	O
mobile	O
,	O
population	O
data	O
to	O
market	O
to	O
docs	O
there	O
are	O
myriad	O
reasons	O
doctors	O
tell	O
marketers	O
they	O
'd	O
like	O
to	O
be	O
approached	O
through	O
digital	O
channels	O
.	O
some	O
point	O
to	O
their	O
status	O
as	O
employees	O
of	O
a	O
system	O
or	O
organization	O
that	O
limits	O
(	O
or	O
even	O
bans	O
)	O
contact	O
with	O
sales	O
reps	O
,	O
while	O
others	O
merely	O
note	O
that	O
they	O
're	O
extremely	O
busy	O
.	O
but	O
for	O
many	O
others	O
,	O
perhaps	O
it	O
's	O
because	O
—	O
like	O
people	O
in	O
basically	O
every	O
other	O
profession	O
—	O
they	O
sure	O
love	O
them	O
some	O
digital	O
.	O
photo	O
credit	O
:	O
creative	O
commons/btnhd	O
production	O
6	O
.	O
pharma	ORG
companies	O
turn	O
to	O
wearables	O
to	O
improve	O
r	O
&	O
d	O
pfizer	ORG
,	O
ucb	ORG
,	O
apple	ORG
,	O
and	O
ibm	ORG
are	O
just	O
a	O
few	O
of	O
the	O
other	O
companies	O
testing	O
out	O
mobile	O
technology	O
for	O
patients	O
with	O
parkinson	O
's	O
.	O
apple	ORG
's	O
researchkit	O
and	O
pfizer	ORG
's	O
and	O
ibm	ORG
's	O
wearable	O
sensor	O
system	O
are	O
both	O
being	O
used	O
to	O
gather	O
data	O
in	O
real	O
time	O
to	O
better	O
understand	O
the	O
disease	O
.	O
7	O
.	O
healthcare	O
marketers	O
:	O
do	O
n't	O
forget	O
about	O
the	O
baby	O
boomers	O
this	O
is	O
a	O
ripe	O
demographic	O
for	O
digital	O
health	O
services	O
and	O
devices	O
.	O
in	O
fact	O
,	O
it	O
's	O
now	O
a	O
matter	O
of	O
urgency	O
:	O
boomers	O
are	O
less	O
healthy	O
and	O
more	O
costly	O
,	O
from	O
a	O
systemic	O
perspective	O
,	O
than	O
previous	O
generations	O
.	O
photo	O
credit	O
:	O
sermo	O
8	O
.	O
sermo	O
opens	O
up	O
platform	O
to	O
healthcare	O
marketers	O
sermo	O
,	O
a	O
social-networking	O
platform	O
for	O
physicians	O
,	O
launched	O
a	O
new	O
free	O
feature	O
that	O
allows	O
pharma	ORG
and	O
healthcare	O
marketers	O
to	O
engage	O
with	O
its	O
roughly	O
550,000	O
physician	O
members	O
.	O
photo	O
credit	O
:	O
insulet	O
9	O
.	O
devicemakers	O
eye	O
market	O
for	O
drug	O
adherence	O
a	O
number	O
of	O
new	O
companies	O
are	O
developing	O
technologies	O
that	O
seek	O
to	O
address	O
how	O
patients	O
take	O
their	O
medicines	O
,	O
as	O
part	O
of	O
a	O
broader	O
effort	O
to	O
improve	O
adherence	O
among	O
those	O
patients	O
.	O
insulet	O
is	O
one	O
example	O
.	O
the	O
company	O
produces	O
small	O
skin-adhesive	O
pods	O
called	O
omnipods	O
that	O
administer	O
the	O
delivery	O
of	O
subcutaneous	O
drugs	O
.	O
photo	O
credit	O
:	O
sproutel	O
10	O
.	O
how	O
a	O
startup	O
is	O
educating	O
kids	O
with	O
diabetes	O
with	O
a	O
teddy	O
bear	O
through	O
the	O
use	O
of	O
animated	O
books	O
and	O
sensors	O
installed	O
using	O
an	O
android	O
tablet	O
in	O
sproutel	O
's	O
jerry	O
the	O
bear	O
,	O
children	O
can	O
learn	O
more	O
about	O
their	O
condition	O
by	O
acting	O
as	O
caregivers	O
themselves	O
,	O
feeding	O
food	O
to	O
the	O
bear	O
,	O
administering	O
insulin	O
,	O
and	O
monitoring	O
his	O
blood	O
glucose	O
levels	O
.	O
medical	O
marketing	O
&	O
media	O
return	O
to	O
top	O
mm	O
&	O
m	O
's	O
top	O
health	O
technology	O
stories	O
of	O
2016	O
december	O
28	O
,	O
2016	O
photo	O
credit	O
:	O
jon	ORG
simon/feature	ORG
photo	ORG
service	ORG
for	ORG
ibm	ORG
1	O
.	O
how	O
watson	O
for	O
oncology	O
is	O
advancing	O
cancer	O
care	O
three	O
years	O
ago	O
,	O
memorial	O
sloan-kettering	O
and	O
ibm	O
watson	O
formed	O
a	O
partnership	O
to	O
develop	O
watson	O
for	O
oncology	O
,	O
a	O
cognitive	O
computing	O
system	O
that	O
can	O
analyze	O
large	O
volumes	O
of	O
data	O
including	O
medical	O
literature	O
,	O
patient	O
health	O
records	O
,	O
and	O
clinical	O
trials	O
,	O
to	O
offer	O
personalized	O
,	O
evidence-based	O
treatment	O
recommendations	O
for	O
cancer	O
patients	O
.	O
photo	O
credit	O
:	O
klick	O
health	O
2	O
.	O
3	O
health	O
tech	O
innovations	O
experts	O
say	O
will	O
revolutionalize	O
healthcare	O
“	O
this	O
is	O
the	O
most	O
interesting	O
time	O
in	O
the	O
history	O
of	O
healthcare	O
and	O
medicine	O
,	O
”	O
says	O
zen	O
chu	O
,	O
md	O
of	O
accelerated	O
medical	O
ventures	O
and	O
senior	O
lecturer	O
at	O
the	O
mit	ORG
sloan	ORG
school	ORG
of	O
management	O
.	O
“	O
we	O
've	O
got	O
so	O
many	O
new	O
technologies	O
and	O
redesigned	O
experiences	O
impacting	O
both	O
the	O
value	O
we	O
deliver	O
,	O
and	O
also	O
the	O
value	O
patients	O
are	O
getting	O
from	O
healthcare.	O
”	O
photo	O
credit	O
:	O
facebook	ORG
3	O
.	O
10	O
things	O
for	O
pharma	ORG
marketers	O
to	O
know	O
about	O
facebook	ORG
and	O
instagram	ORG
“	O
when	O
you	O
think	O
back	O
in	O
the	O
day	O
,	O
people	O
used	O
to	O
have	O
really	O
personal	O
relationships	O
with	O
their	O
physician	O
and	O
pharmacist	O
.	O
we	O
got	O
a	O
little	O
away	O
from	O
that	O
,	O
but	O
we	O
believe	O
that	O
facebook	ORG
can	O
help	O
bring	O
that	O
back	O
and	O
help	O
pharma	ORG
reconnect	O
with	O
people	O
one-on-one	O
,	O
”	O
said	O
facebook	ORG
health	O
industry	O
manager	O
danielle	PERS
salowski	PERS
.	O
photo	O
credit	O
:	O
uncalno	ORG
tekno/creative	ORG
commons	ORG
4	O
.	O
8	O
ways	O
for	O
pharma	ORG
to	O
improve	O
the	O
way	O
it	O
uses	O
twitter	ORG
when	O
it	O
comes	O
to	O
incorporating	O
digital	O
and	O
social	O
media	O
in	O
their	O
marketing	O
strategies	O
,	O
drugmakers	O
'	O
efforts	O
are	O
still	O
overshadowed	O
by	O
fear	O
.	O
that	O
's	O
according	O
to	O
mary	PERS
ann	PERS
belliveau	PERS
,	O
twitter	ORG
's	O
national	O
health	O
and	O
wellness	O
director	O
.	O
there	O
's	O
a	O
misperception	O
that	O
drugmakers	O
ca	O
n't	O
use	O
the	O
platform	O
because	O
of	O
regulatory	O
limitations	O
but	O
in	O
fact	O
many	O
firms	O
are	O
doing	O
it	O
and	O
doing	O
it	O
well	O
,	O
she	O
noted	O
.	O
photo	O
credit	O
:	O
andy	ORG
de/creative	ORG
commons	ORG
5	O
.	O
pharma	ORG
turns	O
to	O
mobile	O
,	O
population	O
data	O
to	O
market	O
to	O
docs	O
there	O
are	O
myriad	O
reasons	O
doctors	O
tell	O
marketers	O
they	O
'd	O
like	O
to	O
be	O
approached	O
through	O
digital	O
channels	O
.	O
some	O
point	O
to	O
their	O
status	O
as	O
employees	O
of	O
a	O
system	O
or	O
organization	O
that	O
limits	O
(	O
or	O
even	O
bans	O
)	O
contact	O
with	O
sales	O
reps	O
,	O
while	O
others	O
merely	O
note	O
that	O
they	O
're	O
extremely	O
busy	O
.	O
but	O
for	O
many	O
others	O
,	O
perhaps	O
it	O
's	O
because	O
—	O
like	O
people	O
in	O
basically	O
every	O
other	O
profession	O
—	O
they	O
sure	O
love	O
them	O
some	O
digital	O
.	O
photo	O
credit	O
:	O
creative	O
commons/btnhd	O
production	O
6	O
.	O
pharma	ORG
companies	O
turn	O
to	O
wearables	O
to	O
improve	O
r	O
&	O
d	O
pfizer	ORG
,	O
ucb	ORG
,	O
apple	ORG
,	O
and	O
ibm	O
are	O
just	O
a	O
few	O
of	O
the	O
other	O
companies	O
testing	O
out	O
mobile	O
technology	O
for	O
patients	O
with	O
parkinson	O
's	O
.	O
apple	ORG
's	O
researchkit	O
and	O
pfizer	ORG
's	O
and	O
ibm	O
's	O
wearable	O
sensor	O
system	O
are	O
both	O
being	O
used	O
to	O
gather	O
data	O
in	O
real	O
time	O
to	O
better	O
understand	O
the	O
disease	O
.	O
7	O
.	O
healthcare	O
marketers	O
:	O
do	O
n't	O
forget	O
about	O
the	O
baby	O
boomers	O
this	O
is	O
a	O
ripe	O
demographic	O
for	O
digital	O
health	O
services	O
and	O
devices	O
.	O
in	O
fact	O
,	O
it	O
's	O
now	O
a	O
matter	O
of	O
urgency	O
:	O
boomers	O
are	O
less	O
healthy	O
and	O
more	O
costly	O
,	O
from	O
a	O
systemic	O
perspective	O
,	O
than	O
previous	O
generations	O
.	O
photo	O
credit	O
:	O
sermo	O
8	O
.	O
sermo	O
opens	O
up	O
platform	O
to	O
healthcare	O
marketers	O
sermo	O
,	O
a	O
social-networking	O
platform	O
for	O
physicians	O
,	O
launched	O
a	O
new	O
free	O
feature	O
that	O
allows	O
pharma	ORG
and	O
healthcare	O
marketers	O
to	O
engage	O
with	O
its	O
roughly	O
550,000	O
physician	O
members	O
.	O
photo	O
credit	O
:	O
insulet	O
9	O
.	O
devicemakers	O
eye	O
market	O
for	O
drug	O
adherence	O
a	O
number	O
of	O
new	O
companies	O
are	O
developing	O
technologies	O
that	O
seek	O
to	O
address	O
how	O
patients	O
take	O
their	O
medicines	O
,	O
as	O
part	O
of	O
a	O
broader	O
effort	O
to	O
improve	O
adherence	O
among	O
those	O
patients	O
.	O
insulet	O
is	O
one	O
example	O
.	O
the	O
company	O
produces	O
small	O
skin-adhesive	O
pods	O
called	O
omnipods	O
that	O
administer	O
the	O
delivery	O
of	O
subcutaneous	O
drugs	O
.	O
photo	O
credit	O
:	O
sproutel	O
10	O
.	O
how	O
a	O
startup	O
is	O
educating	O
kids	O
with	O
diabetes	O
with	O
a	O
teddy	O
bear	O
through	O
the	O
use	O
of	O
animated	O
books	O
and	O
sensors	O
installed	O
using	O
an	O
android	O
tablet	O
in	O
sproutel	O
's	O
jerry	O
the	O
bear	O
,	O
children	O
can	O
learn	O
more	O
about	O
their	O
condition	O
by	O
acting	O
as	O
caregivers	O
themselves	O
,	O
feeding	O
food	O
to	O
the	O
bear	O
,	O
administering	O
insulin	O
,	O
and	O
monitoring	O
his	O
blood	O
glucose	O
levels	O
.	O
medical	O
marketing	O
&	O
media	O
return	O
to	O
top	O
japanese	O
drugmakers	O
lead	O
the	O
way	O
in	O
digital	O
innovation	O
january	O
09	O
,	O
2017	O
bob	PERS
oliver	PERS
is	O
president	O
and	O
ceo	O
of	O
otsuka	ORG
america	ORG
pharmaceutical	ORG
.	O
photo	O
credit	O
:	O
duncan	PERS
kendall	PERS
bob	PERS
oliver	PERS
is	O
not	O
the	O
type	O
of	O
person	O
who	O
calls	O
out	O
his	O
colleagues	O
.	O
he	O
's	O
not	O
big	O
on	O
trash	O
talking	O
or	O
monday	O
morning	O
quarterbacking	O
.	O
but	O
when	O
he	O
's	O
asked	O
what	O
separates	O
the	O
health-tech	O
zealots	O
from	O
the	O
pretenders	O
,	O
the	O
true	O
innovators	O
from	O
the	O
me-toos	O
,	O
oliver	O
is	O
quick	O
to	O
identify	O
an	O
obvious	O
tell	O
.	O
“	O
it	O
's	O
the	O
[	O
companies	O
]	O
that	O
say	O
,	O
‘	O
we	O
're	O
not	O
afraid	O
to	O
fail	O
.	O
we	O
tell	O
our	O
people	O
that	O
it	O
's	O
ok	O
to	O
fail	O
,	O
'	O
”	O
he	O
explains	O
.	O
“	O
when	O
you	O
're	O
dealing	O
with	O
something	O
as	O
new	O
as	O
a	O
lot	O
of	O
digital	O
medicine	O
and	O
health-tech	O
are	O
,	O
and	O
something	O
that	O
requires	O
you	O
to	O
think	O
differently	O
than	O
you	O
always	O
have	O
,	O
not	O
everything	O
is	O
going	O
to	O
work	O
.	O
of	O
course	O
you	O
're	O
going	O
to	O
fail	O
.	O
but	O
there	O
's	O
failing	O
and	O
moving	O
on	O
,	O
and	O
then	O
there	O
's	O
failing	O
and	O
learning	O
from	O
it.	O
”	O
see	O
also	O
:	O
shark	O
tank	O
's	O
herjavec	ORG
shares	O
his	O
tips	O
for	O
innovation	O
competitions	O
oliver	O
,	O
president	O
and	O
ceo	O
of	O
otsuka	ORG
america	ORG
pharmaceutical	ORG
,	O
has	O
more	O
credibility	O
than	O
most	O
to	O
critique	O
efforts	O
in	O
and	O
around	O
the	O
space	O
.	O
in	O
september	O
2015	O
,	O
the	O
company	O
became	O
the	O
first	O
to	O
have	O
a	O
new	O
drug	O
application	O
for	O
a	O
true	O
digital	O
medicine	O
—	O
abilify	O
embedded	O
with	O
an	O
ingestible	O
sensor	O
made	O
by	O
proteus	O
digital	O
health	O
—	O
accepted	O
by	O
the	O
fda	ORG
.	O
however	O
,	O
the	O
application	O
remains	O
in	O
flux	O
.	O
this	O
past	O
april	O
,	O
the	O
companies	O
received	O
a	O
complete	O
response	O
letter	O
(	O
crl	O
)	O
from	O
the	O
agency	O
withholding	O
approval	O
and	O
requesting	O
more	O
information	O
,	O
but	O
industry	O
response	O
to	O
the	O
filing	O
surprised	O
and	O
even	O
awed	O
oliver	O
.	O
“	O
we	O
'd	O
just	O
had	O
a	O
bunch	O
of	O
launches	O
and	O
approvals	O
,	O
but	O
the	O
interest	O
for	O
[	O
the	O
digital	O
medicine	O
]	O
was	O
10	O
times	O
what	O
we	O
usually	O
see	O
.	O
while	O
we	O
had	O
a	O
setback	O
with	O
the	O
crl	O
,	O
the	O
anticipation	O
is	O
undiminished	O
,	O
”	O
he	O
notes	O
.	O
there	O
are	O
other	O
pharma	O
players	O
who	O
have	O
similarly	O
pushed	O
back	O
against	O
the	O
industry	O
's	O
usual	O
wait-and-see	O
philosophy	O
in	O
regard	O
to	O
all	O
things	O
new	O
and	O
somewhat	O
scary	O
.	O
see	O
also	O
:	O
pharma	O
is	O
reluctant	O
to	O
adopt	O
digital	O
in	O
r	O
&	O
d	O
:	O
survey	O
tomotaro	PERS
nagakawa	PERS
,	O
lead	O
partner	O
in	O
deloitte	ORG
japan	O
's	O
life	O
sciences	O
practice	O
,	O
points	O
to	O
astellas	O
,	O
which	O
established	O
digitx	ORG
partners	ORG
in	O
july	O
,	O
a	O
digital	O
health	O
investment	O
company	O
alongside	O
life	O
sciences	O
vc	O
firm	O
mpm	ORG
capital	ORG
,	O
and	O
takeda	ORG
,	O
which	O
launched	O
ibdata	O
in	O
september	O
,	O
a	O
digital	O
program	O
designed	O
to	O
improve	O
diagnostics	O
,	O
measurement	O
,	O
and	O
treatment	O
of	O
inflammatory	O
bowel	O
disease	O
,	O
as	O
particularly	O
prescient	O
and	O
forward-minded	O
.	O
then	O
there	O
's	O
daiichi	ORG
sankyo	ORG
,	O
which	O
started	O
working	O
with	O
partners	O
healthcare	O
on	O
a	O
mobile	O
adherence	O
tool	O
for	O
atrial	O
fibrillation	O
patients	O
way	O
back	O
in	O
2014	O
.	O
notice	O
a	O
trend	O
?	O
otsuka	O
,	O
astellas	O
,	O
takeda	ORG
,	O
and	O
daiichi	ORG
sankyo	ORG
share	O
a	O
degree	O
of	O
adventurousness	O
and	O
forward-mindedness	O
in	O
the	O
digital	O
realm	O
,	O
but	O
they	O
similarly	O
share	O
a	O
country	O
of	O
origin	O
.	O
is	O
there	O
something	O
that	O
japanese-based	O
pharma	O
companies	O
get	O
about	O
health-tech	O
that	O
ones	O
based	O
elsewhere	O
do	O
n't	O
?	O
if	O
so	O
,	O
what	O
are	O
the	O
lessons	O
the	O
have-nots	O
might	O
learn	O
from	O
the	O
digital	O
successes	O
of	O
these	O
organizations	O
?	O
an	O
innovation	O
gap	O
?	O
you	O
wo	O
n't	O
get	O
too	O
many	O
execs	O
at	O
u.s.	O
or	O
european	O
companies	O
to	O
go	O
on	O
the	O
record	O
about	O
a	O
possible	O
health-tech	O
innovation	O
or	O
attitude	O
gap	O
.	O
but	O
if	O
those	O
execs	O
do	O
n't	O
believe	O
such	O
a	O
gap	O
exists	O
,	O
their	O
off-the-cuff	O
comments	O
suggest	O
otherwise	O
.	O
they	O
speak	O
enviously	O
about	O
some	O
of	O
the	O
business	O
philosophies	O
,	O
such	O
as	O
the	O
willingness	O
to	O
tackle	O
problems	O
in	O
an	O
offbeat	O
manner	O
and	O
the	O
celebration	O
of	O
diverse	O
thinking	O
,	O
that	O
japanese	O
pharma	O
companies	O
embrace	O
more	O
openly	O
than	O
their	O
counterparts	O
.	O
they	O
compare	O
such	O
approaches	O
favorably	O
to	O
their	O
own	O
,	O
almost	O
resigned	O
that	O
infighting	O
and	O
overthinking	O
will	O
continue	O
to	O
hobble	O
them	O
as	O
they	O
attempt	O
to	O
keep	O
pace	O
with	O
the	O
industry	O
's	O
historic	O
transformation	O
.	O
see	O
also	O
:	O
what	O
10	O
innovation	O
teams	O
look	O
like	O
some	O
of	O
their	O
comments	O
ring	O
hollow	O
—	O
one	O
imagines	O
that	O
legal	O
and	O
regulatory	O
teams	O
at	O
japanese	O
companies	O
are	O
n't	O
exactly	O
waving	O
through	O
every	O
proposed	O
health-tech	O
initiative	O
with	O
a	O
grin	O
and	O
a	O
thumbs-up	O
—	O
but	O
the	O
point	O
remains	O
:	O
many	O
execs	O
believe	O
they	O
can	O
,	O
and	O
should	O
,	O
model	O
their	O
digital	O
modus	O
operandi	O
on	O
what	O
they	O
've	O
seen	O
from	O
companies	O
otsuka	O
,	O
astellas	O
,	O
takeda	ORG
,	O
and	O
daiichi	ORG
sankyo	ORG
.	O
tellingly	O
,	O
leaders	O
at	O
these	O
companies	O
do	O
n't	O
hold	O
themselves	O
up	O
as	O
health-tech	O
visionaries	O
.	O
rather	O
,	O
they	O
view	O
pushing	O
the	O
digital	O
envelope	O
as	O
merely	O
another	O
component	O
of	O
their	O
overarching	O
mission	O
to	O
better	O
support	O
patients	O
,	O
which	O
companies	O
say	O
ranks	O
among	O
their	O
biggest	O
catalysts	O
for	O
change	O
.	O
“	O
when	O
takeda	ORG
started	O
on	O
its	O
digital	O
journey	O
,	O
we	O
realized	O
we	O
had	O
pockets	O
of	O
experience	O
and	O
pockets	O
of	O
innocence	O
,	O
”	O
recalls	O
bruno	PERS
villetelle	PERS
,	O
the	O
company	O
's	O
chief	O
digital	O
officer	O
.	O
“	O
every	O
organization	O
is	O
facing	O
challenges	O
.	O
when	O
you	O
're	O
going	O
into	O
uncharted	O
territory	O
,	O
as	O
digital	O
and	O
digital	O
health	O
still	O
is	O
,	O
it	O
's	O
about	O
a	O
commitment	O
to	O
experimentation.	O
”	O
bruno	PERS
villetelle	PERS
is	O
takeda	ORG
's	O
chief	O
digital	O
officer	O
.	O
many	O
also	O
admit	O
they	O
ca	O
n't	O
tackle	O
the	O
digital	O
era	O
alone	O
.	O
mark	PERS
reisenauer	PERS
,	O
astellas	O
svp	O
of	O
oncology	O
,	O
believes	O
his	O
company	O
is	O
structured	O
in	O
a	O
way	O
that	O
facilitates	O
digital	O
innovation	O
and	O
is	O
philosophically	O
aligned	O
around	O
the	O
idea	O
that	O
fostering	O
this	O
innovation	O
is	O
a	O
must-do	O
.	O
still	O
,	O
he	O
says	O
astellas	O
oncology	O
's	O
finest	O
recent	O
moment	O
occurred	O
when	O
it	O
threw	O
its	O
weight	O
behind	O
the	O
c3	O
prize	O
competition	O
,	O
designed	O
to	O
address	O
gaps	O
in	O
the	O
nontreatment	O
aspects	O
of	O
cancer	O
care	O
—	O
adherence	O
,	O
care-coordination	O
,	O
and	O
more	O
.	O
“	O
i	O
've	O
been	O
in	O
oncology	O
for	O
22	O
years	O
,	O
so	O
i	O
thought	O
i	O
had	O
a	O
good	O
perspective	O
on	O
what	O
patients	O
were	O
facing	O
.	O
but	O
when	O
i	O
had	O
to	O
live	O
with	O
it	O
through	O
my	O
father	O
,	O
who	O
had	O
neck	O
cancer	O
,	O
it	O
became	O
obvious	O
how	O
much	O
we	O
do	O
n't	O
know	O
about	O
the	O
patient	O
experience	O
,	O
”	O
reisenauer	O
explains	O
.	O
“	O
one	O
thing	O
we	O
learned	O
was	O
the	O
importance	O
and	O
power	O
of	O
sourcing	O
innovation	O
externally	O
from	O
people	O
close	O
to	O
the	O
problem	O
.	O
you	O
learn	O
things	O
you	O
would	O
never	O
have	O
thought	O
of	O
in	O
50	O
years.	O
”	O
4	O
lessons	O
for	O
western	O
pharma	O
partner	O
up	O
.	O
that	O
is	O
the	O
first	O
lesson	O
digital-health	O
wannabes	O
might	O
learn	O
from	O
their	O
japanese	O
peers	O
:	O
those	O
who	O
go	O
it	O
alone	O
will	O
find	O
it	O
harder	O
to	O
gain	O
traction	O
than	O
those	O
who	O
embrace	O
nontraditional	O
partnerships	O
,	O
whether	O
with	O
entrepreneurs	O
,	O
vc	O
players	O
,	O
or	O
anyone	O
else	O
with	O
a	O
half-baked	O
idea	O
.	O
of	O
course	O
,	O
the	O
problem	O
is	O
medicine	O
manufacturers	O
have	O
n't	O
played	O
well	O
with	O
others	O
over	O
the	O
years	O
,	O
in	O
part	O
because	O
there	O
was	O
no	O
compelling	O
reason	O
for	O
them	O
to	O
do	O
so	O
.	O
if	O
the	O
industry	O
's	O
continuing	O
transformation	O
does	O
n't	O
prompt	O
a	O
swift	O
reconsideration	O
of	O
such	O
self-limiting	O
attitudes	O
,	O
it	O
's	O
unlikely	O
anything	O
will	O
.	O
dr.	O
joseph	PERS
kvedar	PERS
,	O
vp	O
,	O
connected	O
health	O
at	O
partners	O
healthcare	O
,	O
says	O
the	O
ability	O
and	O
willingness	O
to	O
collaborate	O
varies	O
wildly	O
from	O
pharma	O
company	O
to	O
pharma	O
company	O
.	O
see	O
also	O
:	O
pfizer	ORG
's	O
smoking-cessation	O
app	O
came	O
from	O
internal	O
competition	O
“	O
one	O
of	O
the	O
big	O
differentiators	O
is	O
how	O
much	O
of	O
a	O
vision	O
the	O
company	O
has	O
for	O
the	O
role	O
of	O
digital	O
tools	O
going	O
forward	O
,	O
versus	O
as	O
an	O
extension	O
of	O
already	O
existing	O
marketing	O
,	O
”	O
he	O
explains	O
.	O
“	O
that	O
's	O
one	O
of	O
the	O
things	O
daiichi	ORG
sankyo	ORG
got	O
from	O
the	O
outset	O
.	O
they	O
did	O
n't	O
act	O
the	O
way	O
you	O
might	O
expect	O
when	O
big	O
pharma	O
corporations	O
are	O
involved	O
,	O
which	O
is	O
,	O
‘	O
well	O
,	O
what	O
about	O
the	O
milestone	O
?	O
stick	O
to	O
the	O
plan	O
.	O
'	O
”	O
which	O
is	O
n't	O
to	O
say	O
these	O
partnerships	O
should	O
assume	O
the	O
form	O
of	O
a	O
casual	O
date	O
.	O
“	O
let	O
's	O
figure	O
it	O
out	O
as	O
we	O
go	O
along	O
”	O
agendas	O
have	O
even	O
less	O
place	O
in	O
health-tech	O
than	O
they	O
did	O
in	O
the	O
bygone	O
multiple	O
high	O
silos	O
era	O
.	O
“	O
it	O
is	O
often	O
the	O
case	O
that	O
a	O
pharma	O
company	O
is	O
having	O
discussions	O
with	O
potential	O
partners	O
without	O
a	O
clear	O
image	O
of	O
their	O
to-be	O
state	O
and-or	O
services	O
they	O
would	O
like	O
to	O
provide	O
by	O
using	O
digital	O
health	O
technologies	O
,	O
”	O
deloitte	ORG
's	O
nagakawa	O
notes	O
.	O
disband	O
the	O
digital	O
team	O
.	O
at	O
daiichi	ORG
sankyo	ORG
,	O
takeda	ORG
,	O
astellas	O
,	O
and	O
otsuka	O
,	O
there	O
's	O
no	O
such	O
thing	O
as	O
a	O
digital	O
team	O
.	O
otsuka	O
,	O
in	O
fact	O
,	O
has	O
spun	O
off	O
otsuka	O
digital	O
health	O
as	O
a	O
joint	O
venture	O
with	O
ibm	ORG
japan	ORG
.	O
and	O
while	O
the	O
inner	O
structural	O
workings	O
of	O
most	O
pharma	O
companies	O
are	O
sufficiently	O
opaque	O
as	O
to	O
prevent	O
overarching	O
statements	O
about	O
the	O
prevalence	O
of	O
such	O
units	O
,	O
it	O
's	O
fair	O
to	O
say	O
many	O
non-japanese-based	O
entities	O
have	O
n't	O
eliminated	O
them	O
.	O
see	O
also	O
:	O
the	O
fda	ORG
,	O
astellas	O
,	O
and	O
accenture	O
use	O
innovation	O
competitions	O
to	O
help	O
address	O
business	O
challenges	O
the	O
problem	O
seems	O
to	O
have	O
something	O
to	O
do	O
with	O
internal	O
politics	O
.	O
rather	O
than	O
impressing	O
the	O
need	O
to	O
change	O
with	O
the	O
times	O
upon	O
long-established	O
groups	O
and	O
divisions	O
,	O
many	O
companies	O
have	O
taken	O
the	O
easy	O
way	O
out	O
:	O
they	O
've	O
assembled	O
distinct	O
digital	O
teams	O
,	O
feisty	O
bands	O
of	O
upstarts	O
charged	O
with	O
imposing	O
their	O
digital	O
will	O
.	O
in	O
doing	O
so	O
,	O
they	O
've	O
essentially	O
made	O
digital	O
transformation	O
an	O
optional	O
activity	O
.	O
oliver	O
,	O
for	O
one	O
,	O
doubts	O
“	O
digital	O
dna	O
”	O
can	O
readily	O
be	O
embedded	O
into	O
a	O
company	O
's	O
genetic	O
sequence	O
.	O
“	O
[	O
digital	O
and	O
health-tech	O
]	O
are	O
things	O
that	O
were	O
traditionally	O
outside	O
our	O
core	O
,	O
but	O
now	O
they	O
're	O
as	O
essential	O
as	O
anything	O
in	O
our	O
core	O
,	O
”	O
he	O
explains	O
.	O
“	O
it	O
takes	O
intentionality	O
.	O
it	O
takes	O
intense	O
focus	O
.	O
you	O
ca	O
n't	O
just	O
say	O
to	O
a	O
few	O
people	O
,	O
‘	O
ok	O
,	O
go	O
tell	O
everybody	O
to	O
do	O
this	O
.	O
'	O
”	O
villetelle	O
agrees	O
.	O
“	O
digital	O
and	O
digital	O
health	O
does	O
n't	O
work	O
if	O
it	O
's	O
led	O
by	O
a	O
remnant	O
of	O
digital	O
natives	O
.	O
you	O
need	O
to	O
bring	O
everyone	O
on	O
the	O
journey	O
,	O
which	O
maybe	O
is	O
n't	O
so	O
common	O
in	O
this	O
industry.	O
”	O
start	O
early	O
.	O
in	O
his	O
time	O
at	O
partners	O
healthcare	O
,	O
kvedar	O
has	O
worked	O
with	O
companies	O
at	O
the	O
beginning	O
of	O
their	O
digital	O
transformation	O
and	O
ones	O
well	O
into	O
their	O
metamorphosis	O
.	O
what	O
separates	O
the	O
successful	O
from	O
the	O
less	O
successful	O
,	O
he	O
believes	O
,	O
is	O
a	O
depth	O
of	O
vision	O
.	O
for	O
the	O
collaboration	O
with	O
daiichi	ORG
sankyo	ORG
,	O
kvedar	O
and	O
his	O
team	O
were	O
brought	O
in	O
early	O
,	O
which	O
allowed	O
the	O
brands	O
to	O
align	O
philosophically	O
and	O
mechanically	O
.	O
“	O
i	O
do	O
n't	O
know	O
that	O
this	O
is	O
exclusive	O
to	O
companies	O
such	O
as	O
daiichi	ORG
sankyo	ORG
,	O
but	O
the	O
ideal	O
situation	O
in	O
pharma	O
is	O
doing	O
digital	O
as	O
much	O
more	O
than	O
a	O
late	O
add-on	O
,	O
”	O
kvedar	O
explains	O
.	O
“	O
you	O
want	O
the	O
company	O
to	O
come	O
in	O
thinking	O
,	O
‘	O
we	O
have	O
a	O
molecule	O
and	O
want	O
to	O
build	O
some	O
kind	O
of	O
digital	O
wraparound	O
or	O
something	O
that	O
adds	O
value	O
to	O
it	O
.	O
'	O
it	O
's	O
when	O
you	O
start	O
planning	O
midway	O
through	O
that	O
you	O
get	O
in	O
trouble.	O
”	O
see	O
also	O
:	O
how	O
a	O
startup	O
is	O
educating	O
kids	O
with	O
diabetes	O
with	O
a	O
teddy	O
bear	O
early	O
digital	O
planning	O
for	O
and	O
around	O
new	O
drugs	O
and	O
other	O
pharma	O
initiatives	O
should	O
also	O
help	O
the	O
industry	O
evolve	O
toward	O
what	O
might	O
come	O
next	O
.	O
“	O
we	O
think	O
that	O
someday	O
pharma	O
companies	O
will	O
be	O
in	O
the	O
software	O
business	O
,	O
either	O
in	O
addition	O
to	O
the	O
molecule	O
business	O
or	O
in	O
place	O
of	O
it	O
,	O
”	O
kvedar	O
continues	O
.	O
“	O
digital	O
tools	O
can	O
have	O
remarkable	O
therapeutic	O
effects	O
on	O
their	O
own.	O
”	O
pick	O
your	O
spots	O
.	O
villetelle	O
believes	O
takeda	ORG
's	O
successes	O
in	O
the	O
digital	O
realm	O
have	O
everything	O
to	O
do	O
with	O
an	O
approach	O
that	O
is	O
as	O
relentless	O
as	O
it	O
is	O
selective	O
.	O
for	O
example	O
,	O
takeda	ORG
in	O
mid-november	O
was	O
running	O
40	O
health-tech	O
experiments	O
across	O
geographies	O
,	O
brands	O
,	O
and	O
therapeutic	O
areas	O
.	O
some	O
are	O
destined	O
to	O
“	O
fail	O
fast	O
,	O
”	O
as	O
villetelle	O
puts	O
it	O
,	O
while	O
others	O
could	O
morph	O
into	O
something	O
entirely	O
different	O
than	O
first	O
envisioned	O
.	O
ultimately	O
,	O
though	O
,	O
it	O
's	O
not	O
just	O
about	O
the	O
success	O
of	O
a	O
given	O
project	O
.	O
an	O
important	O
side	O
benefit	O
comes	O
in	O
the	O
form	O
of	O
encouraging	O
people	O
at	O
all	O
levels	O
of	O
the	O
organization	O
to	O
prioritize	O
digital	O
thinking	O
and	O
empowering	O
them	O
to	O
translate	O
those	O
thoughts	O
into	O
action	O
.	O
see	O
also	O
:	O
uber	ORG
partners	O
with	O
startup	O
to	O
take	O
patients	O
to	O
the	O
doctor	O
“	O
small	O
,	O
lean	O
teams	O
exploring	O
new	O
areas	O
—	O
that	O
's	O
what	O
commitment	O
to	O
experimentation	O
looks	O
like	O
,	O
”	O
he	O
adds	O
.	O
“	O
i	O
do	O
n't	O
believe	O
there	O
's	O
such	O
a	O
thing	O
as	O
‘	O
digital	O
culture	O
'	O
or	O
‘	O
digital	O
mindset	O
.	O
'	O
you	O
learn	O
by	O
doing.	O
”	O
takeda	ORG
's	O
ibdata	O
program	O
satisfies	O
just	O
about	O
every	O
criteria	O
health-tech	O
leaders	O
at	O
the	O
japanese	O
companies	O
recommend	O
.	O
it	O
was	O
developed	O
in	O
partnership	O
with	O
two	O
important	O
allies	O
,	O
vanderbilt	ORG
university	ORG
medical	ORG
center	ORG
and	O
texas	O
digestive	O
disease	O
consultants	O
.	O
its	O
development	O
coincided	O
with	O
takeda	ORG
's	O
growth	O
within	O
the	O
ibd	O
category	O
.	O
it	O
developed	O
organically	O
,	O
rather	O
than	O
under	O
the	O
thumb	O
of	O
a	O
digital	O
leader	O
or	O
squadron	O
.	O
and	O
it	O
lends	O
itself	O
easily	O
to	O
an	O
elevator	O
pitch	O
:	O
patients	O
can	O
track	O
their	O
symptoms	O
and	O
lifestyle	O
factors	O
using	O
wearable	O
watch	O
technology	O
.	O
villetelle	O
has	O
high	O
hopes	O
for	O
this	O
and	O
other	O
digital	O
experiments	O
,	O
whether	O
efforts	O
to	O
show	O
the	O
mode	O
of	O
action	O
for	O
takeda	ORG
products	O
using	O
virtual	O
reality	O
or	O
a	O
program	O
alongside	O
wechat	O
in	O
china	O
to	O
bolster	O
patient	O
education	O
about	O
chronic	O
disease	O
.	O
he	O
believes	O
the	O
company	O
's	O
work	O
will	O
foster	O
a	O
sense	O
of	O
adventure	O
.	O
“	O
i	O
was	O
listening	O
to	O
entrepreneur	O
elon	PERS
musk	O
give	O
an	O
interview	O
recently	O
and	O
he	O
said	O
something	O
that	O
stuck	O
with	O
me	O
,	O
”	O
villetelle	O
says	O
.	O
“	O
it	O
was	O
something	O
along	O
the	O
lines	O
of	O
,	O
‘	O
life	O
needs	O
to	O
be	O
about	O
more	O
than	O
solving	O
problems	O
every	O
day	O
.	O
'	O
we	O
need	O
to	O
be	O
excited	O
about	O
the	O
future	O
.	O
[	O
digital	O
health	O
]	O
gets	O
us	O
to	O
that	O
place.	O
”	O
oliver	O
,	O
on	O
the	O
other	O
hand	O
,	O
recalls	O
a	O
business-magazine	O
article	O
from	O
years	O
ago	O
that	O
likened	O
the	O
pharma	O
industry	O
to	O
the	O
steel	O
industry	O
.	O
“	O
that	O
's	O
very	O
sobering	O
.	O
that	O
's	O
not	O
the	O
comparison	O
we	O
want	O
,	O
”	O
he	O
recalls	O
.	O
“	O
the	O
point	O
was	O
the	O
last	O
real	O
shakeup	O
in	O
pharma	O
was	O
when	O
the	O
fda	ORG
was	O
formed	O
,	O
130	O
years	O
ago	O
,	O
and	O
now	O
there	O
's	O
very	O
real	O
disruption	O
.	O
you	O
can	O
go	O
two	O
ways	O
when	O
that	O
happens	O
:	O
disrupt	O
yourself	O
or	O
be	O
disrupted	O
by	O
external	O
forces	O
.	O
having	O
the	O
courage	O
to	O
disrupt	O
themselves	O
is	O
what	O
's	O
going	O
to	O
make	O
or	O
break	O
a	O
lot	O
of	O
companies	O
in	O
the	O
next	O
decade.	O
”	O
from	O
the	O
january	O
2017	O
issue	O
of	O
mmm	O
»	O
medical	O
marketing	O
&	O
media	O
return	O
to	O
top	O
japanese	O
drugmakers	O
lead	O
the	O
way	O
in	O
digital	O
innovation	O
bob	PERS
oliver	PERS
is	O
president	O
and	O
ceo	O
of	O
otsuka	ORG
america	ORG
pharmaceutical	ORG
.	O
photo	O
credit	O
:	O
duncan	PERS
kendall	PERS
bob	PERS
oliver	PERS
is	O
not	O
the	O
type	O
of	O
person	O
who	O
calls	O
out	O
his	O
colleagues	O
.	O
he	O
's	O
not	O
big	O
on	O
trash	O
talking	O
or	O
monday	O
morning	O
quarterbacking	O
.	O
but	O
when	O
he	O
's	O
asked	O
what	O
separates	O
the	O
health-tech	O
zealots	O
from	O
the	O
pretenders	O
,	O
the	O
true	O
innovators	O
from	O
the	O
me-toos	O
,	O
oliver	O
is	O
quick	O
to	O
identify	O
an	O
obvious	O
tell	O
.	O
“	O
it	O
's	O
the	O
[	O
companies	O
]	O
that	O
say	O
,	O
‘	O
we	O
're	O
not	O
afraid	O
to	O
fail	O
.	O
we	O
tell	O
our	O
people	O
that	O
it	O
's	O
ok	O
to	O
fail	O
,	O
'	O
”	O
he	O
explains	O
.	O
“	O
when	O
you	O
're	O
dealing	O
with	O
something	O
as	O
new	O
as	O
a	O
lot	O
of	O
digital	O
medicine	O
and	O
health-tech	O
are	O
,	O
and	O
something	O
that	O
requires	O
you	O
to	O
think	O
differently	O
than	O
you	O
always	O
have	O
,	O
not	O
everything	O
is	O
going	O
to	O
work	O
.	O
of	O
course	O
you	O
're	O
going	O
to	O
fail	O
.	O
but	O
there	O
's	O
failing	O
and	O
moving	O
on	O
,	O
and	O
then	O
there	O
's	O
failing	O
and	O
learning	O
from	O
it.	O
”	O
see	O
also	O
:	O
shark	O
tank	O
's	O
herjavec	ORG
shares	O
his	O
tips	O
for	O
innovation	O
competitions	O
oliver	O
,	O
president	O
and	O
ceo	O
of	O
otsuka	ORG
america	ORG
pharmaceutical	ORG
,	O
has	O
more	O
credibility	O
than	O
most	O
to	O
critique	O
efforts	O
in	O
and	O
around	O
the	O
space	O
.	O
in	O
september	O
2015	O
,	O
the	O
company	O
became	O
the	O
first	O
to	O
have	O
a	O
new	O
drug	O
application	O
for	O
a	O
true	O
digital	O
medicine	O
—	O
abilify	O
embedded	O
with	O
an	O
ingestible	O
sensor	O
made	O
by	O
proteus	O
digital	O
health	O
—	O
accepted	O
by	O
the	O
fda	ORG
.	O
however	O
,	O
the	O
application	O
remains	O
in	O
flux	O
.	O
this	O
past	O
april	O
,	O
the	O
companies	O
received	O
a	O
complete	O
response	O
letter	O
(	O
crl	O
)	O
from	O
the	O
agency	O
withholding	O
approval	O
and	O
requesting	O
more	O
information	O
,	O
but	O
industry	O
response	O
to	O
the	O
filing	O
surprised	O
and	O
even	O
awed	O
oliver	O
.	O
“	O
we	O
'd	O
just	O
had	O
a	O
bunch	O
of	O
launches	O
and	O
approvals	O
,	O
but	O
the	O
interest	O
for	O
[	O
the	O
digital	O
medicine	O
]	O
was	O
10	O
times	O
what	O
we	O
usually	O
see	O
.	O
while	O
we	O
had	O
a	O
setback	O
with	O
the	O
crl	O
,	O
the	O
anticipation	O
is	O
undiminished	O
,	O
”	O
he	O
notes	O
.	O
there	O
are	O
other	O
pharma	O
players	O
who	O
have	O
similarly	O
pushed	O
back	O
against	O
the	O
industry	O
's	O
usual	O
wait-and-see	O
philosophy	O
in	O
regard	O
to	O
all	O
things	O
new	O
and	O
somewhat	O
scary	O
.	O
see	O
also	O
:	O
pharma	O
is	O
reluctant	O
to	O
adopt	O
digital	O
in	O
r	O
&	O
d	O
:	O
survey	O
tomotaro	PERS
nagakawa	PERS
,	O
lead	O
partner	O
in	O
deloitte	ORG
japan	O
's	O
life	O
sciences	O
practice	O
,	O
points	O
to	O
astellas	O
,	O
which	O
established	O
digitx	ORG
partners	ORG
in	O
july	O
,	O
a	O
digital	O
health	O
investment	O
company	O
alongside	O
life	O
sciences	O
vc	O
firm	O
mpm	ORG
capital	ORG
,	O
and	O
takeda	ORG
,	O
which	O
launched	O
ibdata	O
in	O
september	O
,	O
a	O
digital	O
program	O
designed	O
to	O
improve	O
diagnostics	O
,	O
measurement	O
,	O
and	O
treatment	O
of	O
inflammatory	O
bowel	O
disease	O
,	O
as	O
particularly	O
prescient	O
and	O
forward-minded	O
.	O
then	O
there	O
's	O
daiichi	ORG
sankyo	ORG
,	O
which	O
started	O
working	O
with	O
partners	O
healthcare	O
on	O
a	O
mobile	O
adherence	O
tool	O
for	O
atrial	O
fibrillation	O
patients	O
way	O
back	O
in	O
2014	O
.	O
notice	O
a	O
trend	O
?	O
otsuka	O
,	O
astellas	O
,	O
takeda	ORG
,	O
and	O
daiichi	ORG
sankyo	ORG
share	O
a	O
degree	O
of	O
adventurousness	O
and	O
forward-mindedness	O
in	O
the	O
digital	O
realm	O
,	O
but	O
they	O
similarly	O
share	O
a	O
country	O
of	O
origin	O
.	O
is	O
there	O
something	O
that	O
japanese-based	O
pharma	O
companies	O
get	O
about	O
health-tech	O
that	O
ones	O
based	O
elsewhere	O
do	O
n't	O
?	O
if	O
so	O
,	O
what	O
are	O
the	O
lessons	O
the	O
have-nots	O
might	O
learn	O
from	O
the	O
digital	O
successes	O
of	O
these	O
organizations	O
?	O
an	O
innovation	O
gap	O
?	O
you	O
wo	O
n't	O
get	O
too	O
many	O
execs	O
at	O
u.s.	O
or	O
european	O
companies	O
to	O
go	O
on	O
the	O
record	O
about	O
a	O
possible	O
health-tech	O
innovation	O
or	O
attitude	O
gap	O
.	O
but	O
if	O
those	O
execs	O
do	O
n't	O
believe	O
such	O
a	O
gap	O
exists	O
,	O
their	O
off-the-cuff	O
comments	O
suggest	O
otherwise	O
.	O
they	O
speak	O
enviously	O
about	O
some	O
of	O
the	O
business	O
philosophies	O
,	O
such	O
as	O
the	O
willingness	O
to	O
tackle	O
problems	O
in	O
an	O
offbeat	O
manner	O
and	O
the	O
celebration	O
of	O
diverse	O
thinking	O
,	O
that	O
japanese	O
pharma	O
companies	O
embrace	O
more	O
openly	O
than	O
their	O
counterparts	O
.	O
they	O
compare	O
such	O
approaches	O
favorably	O
to	O
their	O
own	O
,	O
almost	O
resigned	O
that	O
infighting	O
and	O
overthinking	O
will	O
continue	O
to	O
hobble	O
them	O
as	O
they	O
attempt	O
to	O
keep	O
pace	O
with	O
the	O
industry	O
's	O
historic	O
transformation	O
.	O
see	O
also	O
:	O
what	O
10	O
innovation	O
teams	O
look	O
like	O
some	O
of	O
their	O
comments	O
ring	O
hollow	O
—	O
one	O
imagines	O
that	O
legal	O
and	O
regulatory	O
teams	O
at	O
japanese	O
companies	O
are	O
n't	O
exactly	O
waving	O
through	O
every	O
proposed	O
health-tech	O
initiative	O
with	O
a	O
grin	O
and	O
a	O
thumbs-up	O
—	O
but	O
the	O
point	O
remains	O
:	O
many	O
execs	O
believe	O
they	O
can	O
,	O
and	O
should	O
,	O
model	O
their	O
digital	O
modus	O
operandi	O
on	O
what	O
they	O
've	O
seen	O
from	O
companies	O
otsuka	O
,	O
astellas	O
,	O
takeda	ORG
,	O
and	O
daiichi	ORG
sankyo	ORG
.	O
tellingly	O
,	O
leaders	O
at	O
these	O
companies	O
do	O
n't	O
hold	O
themselves	O
up	O
as	O
health-tech	O
visionaries	O
.	O
rather	O
,	O
they	O
view	O
pushing	O
the	O
digital	O
envelope	O
as	O
merely	O
another	O
component	O
of	O
their	O
overarching	O
mission	O
to	O
better	O
support	O
patients	O
,	O
which	O
companies	O
say	O
ranks	O
among	O
their	O
biggest	O
catalysts	O
for	O
change	O
.	O
“	O
when	O
takeda	ORG
started	O
on	O
its	O
digital	O
journey	O
,	O
we	O
realized	O
we	O
had	O
pockets	O
of	O
experience	O
and	O
pockets	O
of	O
innocence	O
,	O
”	O
recalls	O
bruno	PERS
villetelle	PERS
,	O
the	O
company	O
's	O
chief	O
digital	O
officer	O
.	O
“	O
every	O
organization	O
is	O
facing	O
challenges	O
.	O
when	O
you	O
're	O
going	O
into	O
uncharted	O
territory	O
,	O
as	O
digital	O
and	O
digital	O
health	O
still	O
is	O
,	O
it	O
's	O
about	O
a	O
commitment	O
to	O
experimentation.	O
”	O
bruno	PERS
villetelle	PERS
is	O
takeda	ORG
's	O
chief	O
digital	O
officer	O
.	O
many	O
also	O
admit	O
they	O
ca	O
n't	O
tackle	O
the	O
digital	O
era	O
alone	O
.	O
mark	PERS
reisenauer	PERS
,	O
astellas	O
svp	O
of	O
oncology	O
,	O
believes	O
his	O
company	O
is	O
structured	O
in	O
a	O
way	O
that	O
facilitates	O
digital	O
innovation	O
and	O
is	O
philosophically	O
aligned	O
around	O
the	O
idea	O
that	O
fostering	O
this	O
innovation	O
is	O
a	O
must-do	O
.	O
still	O
,	O
he	O
says	O
astellas	O
oncology	O
's	O
finest	O
recent	O
moment	O
occurred	O
when	O
it	O
threw	O
its	O
weight	O
behind	O
the	O
c3	O
prize	O
competition	O
,	O
designed	O
to	O
address	O
gaps	O
in	O
the	O
nontreatment	O
aspects	O
of	O
cancer	O
care	O
—	O
adherence	O
,	O
care-coordination	O
,	O
and	O
more	O
.	O
“	O
i	O
've	O
been	O
in	O
oncology	O
for	O
22	O
years	O
,	O
so	O
i	O
thought	O
i	O
had	O
a	O
good	O
perspective	O
on	O
what	O
patients	O
were	O
facing	O
.	O
but	O
when	O
i	O
had	O
to	O
live	O
with	O
it	O
through	O
my	O
father	O
,	O
who	O
had	O
neck	O
cancer	O
,	O
it	O
became	O
obvious	O
how	O
much	O
we	O
do	O
n't	O
know	O
about	O
the	O
patient	O
experience	O
,	O
”	O
reisenauer	O
explains	O
.	O
“	O
one	O
thing	O
we	O
learned	O
was	O
the	O
importance	O
and	O
power	O
of	O
sourcing	O
innovation	O
externally	O
from	O
people	O
close	O
to	O
the	O
problem	O
.	O
you	O
learn	O
things	O
you	O
would	O
never	O
have	O
thought	O
of	O
in	O
50	O
years.	O
”	O
4	O
lessons	O
for	O
western	O
pharma	O
partner	O
up	O
.	O
that	O
is	O
the	O
first	O
lesson	O
digital-health	O
wannabes	O
might	O
learn	O
from	O
their	O
japanese	O
peers	O
:	O
those	O
who	O
go	O
it	O
alone	O
will	O
find	O
it	O
harder	O
to	O
gain	O
traction	O
than	O
those	O
who	O
embrace	O
nontraditional	O
partnerships	O
,	O
whether	O
with	O
entrepreneurs	O
,	O
vc	O
players	O
,	O
or	O
anyone	O
else	O
with	O
a	O
half-baked	O
idea	O
.	O
of	O
course	O
,	O
the	O
problem	O
is	O
medicine	O
manufacturers	O
have	O
n't	O
played	O
well	O
with	O
others	O
over	O
the	O
years	O
,	O
in	O
part	O
because	O
there	O
was	O
no	O
compelling	O
reason	O
for	O
them	O
to	O
do	O
so	O
.	O
if	O
the	O
industry	O
's	O
continuing	O
transformation	O
does	O
n't	O
prompt	O
a	O
swift	O
reconsideration	O
of	O
such	O
self-limiting	O
attitudes	O
,	O
it	O
's	O
unlikely	O
anything	O
will	O
.	O
dr.	O
joseph	PERS
kvedar	PERS
,	O
vp	O
,	O
connected	O
health	O
at	O
partners	O
healthcare	O
,	O
says	O
the	O
ability	O
and	O
willingness	O
to	O
collaborate	O
varies	O
wildly	O
from	O
pharma	O
company	O
to	O
pharma	O
company	O
.	O
see	O
also	O
:	O
pfizer	ORG
's	O
smoking-cessation	O
app	O
came	O
from	O
internal	O
competition	O
“	O
one	O
of	O
the	O
big	O
differentiators	O
is	O
how	O
much	O
of	O
a	O
vision	O
the	O
company	O
has	O
for	O
the	O
role	O
of	O
digital	O
tools	O
going	O
forward	O
,	O
versus	O
as	O
an	O
extension	O
of	O
already	O
existing	O
marketing	O
,	O
”	O
he	O
explains	O
.	O
“	O
that	O
's	O
one	O
of	O
the	O
things	O
daiichi	ORG
sankyo	ORG
got	O
from	O
the	O
outset	O
.	O
they	O
did	O
n't	O
act	O
the	O
way	O
you	O
might	O
expect	O
when	O
big	O
pharma	O
corporations	O
are	O
involved	O
,	O
which	O
is	O
,	O
‘	O
well	O
,	O
what	O
about	O
the	O
milestone	O
?	O
stick	O
to	O
the	O
plan	O
.	O
'	O
”	O
which	O
is	O
n't	O
to	O
say	O
these	O
partnerships	O
should	O
assume	O
the	O
form	O
of	O
a	O
casual	O
date	O
.	O
“	O
let	O
's	O
figure	O
it	O
out	O
as	O
we	O
go	O
along	O
”	O
agendas	O
have	O
even	O
less	O
place	O
in	O
health-tech	O
than	O
they	O
did	O
in	O
the	O
bygone	O
multiple	O
high	O
silos	O
era	O
.	O
“	O
it	O
is	O
often	O
the	O
case	O
that	O
a	O
pharma	O
company	O
is	O
having	O
discussions	O
with	O
potential	O
partners	O
without	O
a	O
clear	O
image	O
of	O
their	O
to-be	O
state	O
and-or	O
services	O
they	O
would	O
like	O
to	O
provide	O
by	O
using	O
digital	O
health	O
technologies	O
,	O
”	O
deloitte	ORG
's	O
nagakawa	O
notes	O
.	O
disband	O
the	O
digital	O
team	O
.	O
at	O
daiichi	ORG
sankyo	ORG
,	O
takeda	ORG
,	O
astellas	O
,	O
and	O
otsuka	O
,	O
there	O
's	O
no	O
such	O
thing	O
as	O
a	O
digital	O
team	O
.	O
otsuka	O
,	O
in	O
fact	O
,	O
has	O
spun	O
off	O
otsuka	O
digital	O
health	O
as	O
a	O
joint	O
venture	O
with	O
ibm	ORG
japan	ORG
.	O
and	O
while	O
the	O
inner	O
structural	O
workings	O
of	O
most	O
pharma	O
companies	O
are	O
sufficiently	O
opaque	O
as	O
to	O
prevent	O
overarching	O
statements	O
about	O
the	O
prevalence	O
of	O
such	O
units	O
,	O
it	O
's	O
fair	O
to	O
say	O
many	O
non-japanese-based	O
entities	O
have	O
n't	O
eliminated	O
them	O
.	O
see	O
also	O
:	O
the	O
fda	ORG
,	O
astellas	O
,	O
and	O
accenture	ORG
use	O
innovation	O
competitions	O
to	O
help	O
address	O
business	O
challenges	O
the	O
problem	O
seems	O
to	O
have	O
something	O
to	O
do	O
with	O
internal	O
politics	O
.	O
rather	O
than	O
impressing	O
the	O
need	O
to	O
change	O
with	O
the	O
times	O
upon	O
long-established	O
groups	O
and	O
divisions	O
,	O
many	O
companies	O
have	O
taken	O
the	O
easy	O
way	O
out	O
:	O
they	O
've	O
assembled	O
distinct	O
digital	O
teams	O
,	O
feisty	O
bands	O
of	O
upstarts	O
charged	O
with	O
imposing	O
their	O
digital	O
will	O
.	O
in	O
doing	O
so	O
,	O
they	O
've	O
essentially	O
made	O
digital	O
transformation	O
an	O
optional	O
activity	O
.	O
oliver	O
,	O
for	O
one	O
,	O
doubts	O
“	O
digital	O
dna	O
”	O
can	O
readily	O
be	O
embedded	O
into	O
a	O
company	O
's	O
genetic	O
sequence	O
.	O
“	O
[	O
digital	O
and	O
health-tech	O
]	O
are	O
things	O
that	O
were	O
traditionally	O
outside	O
our	O
core	O
,	O
but	O
now	O
they	O
're	O
as	O
essential	O
as	O
anything	O
in	O
our	O
core	O
,	O
”	O
he	O
explains	O
.	O
“	O
it	O
takes	O
intentionality	O
.	O
it	O
takes	O
intense	O
focus	O
.	O
you	O
ca	O
n't	O
just	O
say	O
to	O
a	O
few	O
people	O
,	O
‘	O
ok	O
,	O
go	O
tell	O
everybody	O
to	O
do	O
this	O
.	O
'	O
”	O
villetelle	O
agrees	O
.	O
“	O
digital	O
and	O
digital	O
health	O
does	O
n't	O
work	O
if	O
it	O
's	O
led	O
by	O
a	O
remnant	O
of	O
digital	O
natives	O
.	O
you	O
need	O
to	O
bring	O
everyone	O
on	O
the	O
journey	O
,	O
which	O
maybe	O
is	O
n't	O
so	O
common	O
in	O
this	O
industry.	O
”	O
start	O
early	O
.	O
in	O
his	O
time	O
at	O
partners	O
healthcare	O
,	O
kvedar	O
has	O
worked	O
with	O
companies	O
at	O
the	O
beginning	O
of	O
their	O
digital	O
transformation	O
and	O
ones	O
well	O
into	O
their	O
metamorphosis	O
.	O
what	O
separates	O
the	O
successful	O
from	O
the	O
less	O
successful	O
,	O
he	O
believes	O
,	O
is	O
a	O
depth	O
of	O
vision	O
.	O
for	O
the	O
collaboration	O
with	O
daiichi	ORG
sankyo	ORG
,	O
kvedar	O
and	O
his	O
team	O
were	O
brought	O
in	O
early	O
,	O
which	O
allowed	O
the	O
brands	O
to	O
align	O
philosophically	O
and	O
mechanically	O
.	O
“	O
i	O
do	O
n't	O
know	O
that	O
this	O
is	O
exclusive	O
to	O
companies	O
such	O
as	O
daiichi	ORG
sankyo	ORG
,	O
but	O
the	O
ideal	O
situation	O
in	O
pharma	O
is	O
doing	O
digital	O
as	O
much	O
more	O
than	O
a	O
late	O
add-on	O
,	O
”	O
kvedar	O
explains	O
.	O
“	O
you	O
want	O
the	O
company	O
to	O
come	O
in	O
thinking	O
,	O
‘	O
we	O
have	O
a	O
molecule	O
and	O
want	O
to	O
build	O
some	O
kind	O
of	O
digital	O
wraparound	O
or	O
something	O
that	O
adds	O
value	O
to	O
it	O
.	O
'	O
it	O
's	O
when	O
you	O
start	O
planning	O
midway	O
through	O
that	O
you	O
get	O
in	O
trouble.	O
”	O
see	O
also	O
:	O
how	O
a	O
startup	O
is	O
educating	O
kids	O
with	O
diabetes	O
with	O
a	O
teddy	O
bear	O
early	O
digital	O
planning	O
for	O
and	O
around	O
new	O
drugs	O
and	O
other	O
pharma	O
initiatives	O
should	O
also	O
help	O
the	O
industry	O
evolve	O
toward	O
what	O
might	O
come	O
next	O
.	O
“	O
we	O
think	O
that	O
someday	O
pharma	O
companies	O
will	O
be	O
in	O
the	O
software	O
business	O
,	O
either	O
in	O
addition	O
to	O
the	O
molecule	O
business	O
or	O
in	O
place	O
of	O
it	O
,	O
”	O
kvedar	O
continues	O
.	O
“	O
digital	O
tools	O
can	O
have	O
remarkable	O
therapeutic	O
effects	O
on	O
their	O
own.	O
”	O
pick	O
your	O
spots	O
.	O
villetelle	O
believes	O
takeda	ORG
's	O
successes	O
in	O
the	O
digital	O
realm	O
have	O
everything	O
to	O
do	O
with	O
an	O
approach	O
that	O
is	O
as	O
relentless	O
as	O
it	O
is	O
selective	O
.	O
for	O
example	O
,	O
takeda	ORG
in	O
mid-november	O
was	O
running	O
40	O
health-tech	O
experiments	O
across	O
geographies	O
,	O
brands	O
,	O
and	O
therapeutic	O
areas	O
.	O
some	O
are	O
destined	O
to	O
“	O
fail	O
fast	O
,	O
”	O
as	O
villetelle	O
puts	O
it	O
,	O
while	O
others	O
could	O
morph	O
into	O
something	O
entirely	O
different	O
than	O
first	O
envisioned	O
.	O
ultimately	O
,	O
though	O
,	O
it	O
's	O
not	O
just	O
about	O
the	O
success	O
of	O
a	O
given	O
project	O
.	O
an	O
important	O
side	O
benefit	O
comes	O
in	O
the	O
form	O
of	O
encouraging	O
people	O
at	O
all	O
levels	O
of	O
the	O
organization	O
to	O
prioritize	O
digital	O
thinking	O
and	O
empowering	O
them	O
to	O
translate	O
those	O
thoughts	O
into	O
action	O
.	O
see	O
also	O
:	O
uber	ORG
partners	O
with	O
startup	O
to	O
take	O
patients	O
to	O
the	O
doctor	O
“	O
small	O
,	O
lean	O
teams	O
exploring	O
new	O
areas	O
—	O
that	O
's	O
what	O
commitment	O
to	O
experimentation	O
looks	O
like	O
,	O
”	O
he	O
adds	O
.	O
“	O
i	O
do	O
n't	O
believe	O
there	O
's	O
such	O
a	O
thing	O
as	O
‘	O
digital	O
culture	O
'	O
or	O
‘	O
digital	O
mindset	O
.	O
'	O
you	O
learn	O
by	O
doing.	O
”	O
takeda	ORG
's	O
ibdata	O
program	O
satisfies	O
just	O
about	O
every	O
criteria	O
health-tech	O
leaders	O
at	O
the	O
japanese	O
companies	O
recommend	O
.	O
it	O
was	O
developed	O
in	O
partnership	O
with	O
two	O
important	O
allies	O
,	O
vanderbilt	ORG
university	ORG
medical	ORG
center	ORG
and	O
texas	O
digestive	O
disease	O
consultants	O
.	O
its	O
development	O
coincided	O
with	O
takeda	ORG
's	O
growth	O
within	O
the	O
ibd	O
category	O
.	O
it	O
developed	O
organically	O
,	O
rather	O
than	O
under	O
the	O
thumb	O
of	O
a	O
digital	O
leader	O
or	O
squadron	O
.	O
and	O
it	O
lends	O
itself	O
easily	O
to	O
an	O
elevator	O
pitch	O
:	O
patients	O
can	O
track	O
their	O
symptoms	O
and	O
lifestyle	O
factors	O
using	O
wearable	O
watch	O
technology	O
.	O
villetelle	O
has	O
high	O
hopes	O
for	O
this	O
and	O
other	O
digital	O
experiments	O
,	O
whether	O
efforts	O
to	O
show	O
the	O
mode	O
of	O
action	O
for	O
takeda	ORG
products	O
using	O
virtual	O
reality	O
or	O
a	O
program	O
alongside	O
wechat	O
in	O
china	O
to	O
bolster	O
patient	O
education	O
about	O
chronic	O
disease	O
.	O
he	O
believes	O
the	O
company	O
's	O
work	O
will	O
foster	O
a	O
sense	O
of	O
adventure	O
.	O
“	O
i	O
was	O
listening	O
to	O
entrepreneur	O
elon	PERS
musk	O
give	O
an	O
interview	O
recently	O
and	O
he	O
said	O
something	O
that	O
stuck	O
with	O
me	O
,	O
”	O
villetelle	O
says	O
.	O
“	O
it	O
was	O
something	O
along	O
the	O
lines	O
of	O
,	O
‘	O
life	O
needs	O
to	O
be	O
about	O
more	O
than	O
solving	O
problems	O
every	O
day	O
.	O
'	O
we	O
need	O
to	O
be	O
excited	O
about	O
the	O
future	O
.	O
[	O
digital	O
health	O
]	O
gets	O
us	O
to	O
that	O
place.	O
”	O
oliver	O
,	O
on	O
the	O
other	O
hand	O
,	O
recalls	O
a	O
business-magazine	O
article	O
from	O
years	O
ago	O
that	O
likened	O
the	O
pharma	O
industry	O
to	O
the	O
steel	O
industry	O
.	O
“	O
that	O
's	O
very	O
sobering	O
.	O
that	O
's	O
not	O
the	O
comparison	O
we	O
want	O
,	O
”	O
he	O
recalls	O
.	O
“	O
the	O
point	O
was	O
the	O
last	O
real	O
shakeup	O
in	O
pharma	O
was	O
when	O
the	O
fda	ORG
was	O
formed	O
,	O
130	O
years	O
ago	O
,	O
and	O
now	O
there	O
's	O
very	O
real	O
disruption	O
.	O
you	O
can	O
go	O
two	O
ways	O
when	O
that	O
happens	O
:	O
disrupt	O
yourself	O
or	O
be	O
disrupted	O
by	O
external	O
forces	O
.	O
having	O
the	O
courage	O
to	O
disrupt	O
themselves	O
is	O
what	O
's	O
going	O
to	O
make	O
or	O
break	O
a	O
lot	O
of	O
companies	O
in	O
the	O
next	O
decade.	O
”	O
from	O
the	O
january	O
2017	O
issue	O
of	O
mmm	O
»	O
medical	O
marketing	O
&	O
media	O
return	O
to	O
top	O
correlation	O
between	O
pik3ca	O
mutations	O
in	O
cell-free	O
dna	O
and	O
everolimus	O
efficacy	O
in	O
hr+	O
,	O
her2−	O
advanced	O
breast	O
cancer	O
:	O
results	O
from	O
bolero-2	O
free	O
1department	O
of	O
medicine	O
,	O
memorial	ORG
sloan	ORG
kettering	ORG
cancer	ORG
center	ORG
,	O
new	O
york	O
,	O
ny	O
10065	O
,	O
usa	O
2oncology	O
precision	O
medicine	O
,	O
novartis	ORG
pharmaceuticals	ORG
corporation	ORG
,	O
east	O
hanover	O
,	O
nj	O
07936	O
,	O
usa	O
3global	O
medical	O
affairs	O
,	O
novartis	ORG
pharma	ORG
ag	ORG
,	O
basel	O
ch-4002	O
,	O
switzerland	O
4department	O
of	O
breast	O
medical	O
oncology	O
,	O
the	ORG
university	ORG
of	O
texas	ORG
md	ORG
anderson	ORG
cancer	ORG
center	ORG
,	O
houston	O
,	O
tx	O
77030	O
,	O
usa	O
correspondence	O
:	O
dr	O
me	O
moynahan	PERS
,	O
e-mail	O
:	O
moynaham	O
@	O
mskcc.org	O
advance	O
online	O
publication	O
9	O
february	O
2017	O
presented	O
as	O
poster	O
at	O
the	O
2016	O
american	ORG
society	ORG
of	ORG
clinical	ORG
oncology	ORG
(	O
asco	O
)	O
annual	O
meeting	O
;	O
3–7	O
june	O
2016	O
;	O
chicago	O
,	O
il	O
,	O
usa	O
.	O
abstract	O
background	O
:	O
the	O
current	O
analysis	O
was	O
performed	O
to	O
evaluate	O
the	O
impact	O
of	O
pik3ca	O
hotspot	O
mutations	O
on	O
everolimus	O
efficacy	O
in	O
bolero-2	O
participants	O
,	O
using	O
cell-free	O
dna	O
(	O
cfdna	O
)	O
from	O
plasma	O
samples	O
collected	O
at	O
the	O
time	O
of	O
patient	O
randomisation	O
.	O
methods	O
:	O
pik3ca	O
h1047r	O
,	O
e545k	O
,	O
and	O
e542k	O
mutations	O
in	O
plasma-derived	O
cfdna	O
were	O
analysed	O
by	O
droplet	O
digital	O
pcr	O
(	O
ddpcr	O
)	O
.	O
median	O
pfs	O
was	O
estimated	O
for	O
patient	O
subgroups	O
defined	O
by	O
pik3ca	O
mutations	O
in	O
each	O
treatment	O
arm	O
.	O
results	O
:	O
among	O
550	O
patients	O
included	O
in	O
cfdna	O
analysis	O
,	O
median	O
pfs	O
in	O
everolimus	O
vs	O
placebo	O
arms	O
was	O
similar	O
in	O
patients	O
with	O
tumours	O
that	O
had	O
wild-type	O
or	O
mutant	O
pik3ca	O
(	O
hazard	O
ratio	O
(	O
hr	O
)	O
,	O
0.43	O
and	O
0.37	O
,	O
respectively	O
)	O
.	O
everolimus	O
also	O
prolonged	O
median	O
pfs	O
in	O
patients	O
with	O
pik3ca	O
h1047r	O
(	O
hr	O
,	O
0.37	O
)	O
and	O
e545k/e542k	O
mutations	O
(	O
hr=0.30	O
)	O
with	O
a	O
similar	O
magnitude	O
.	O
conclusions	O
:	O
mutation	O
analysis	O
of	O
plasma-derived	O
cfdna	O
by	O
ddpcr	O
suggests	O
that	O
pfs	O
benefit	O
of	O
everolimus	O
was	O
maintained	O
irrespective	O
of	O
pik3ca	O
genotypes	O
,	O
consistent	O
with	O
the	O
previous	O
analysis	O
of	O
archival	O
tumour	O
dna	O
by	O
next-generation	O
sequencing	O
.	O
keywords	O
:	O
bolero-2	O
;	O
pik3ca	O
;	O
cfdna	O
;	O
everolimus	O
;	O
hr+	O
breast	O
cancer	O
aberrant	O
signalling	O
through	O
the	O
pi3k/akt/mtor	O
pathway	O
has	O
been	O
implicated	O
in	O
tumorigenesis	O
,	O
progression	O
,	O
and	O
therapeutic	O
resistance	O
in	O
various	O
cancers	O
(	O
rodon	O
et	O
al	O
,	O
2013	O
;	O
thorpe	O
et	O
al	O
,	O
2015	O
)	O
.	O
pik3ca	O
mutations	O
result	O
in	O
constitutive	O
activation	O
of	O
p110α	O
,	O
which	O
in	O
turn	O
activates	O
akt1	O
and	O
its	O
downstream	O
target	O
mtor	O
.	O
somatic	O
pik3ca	O
mutations	O
are	O
frequent	O
in	O
human	O
breast	O
cancer	O
,	O
occurring	O
in	O
up	O
to	O
45	O
%	O
of	O
luminal	O
a	O
tumours	O
(	O
cancer	ORG
genome	ORG
atlas	ORG
network	ORG
,	O
2012	O
)	O
;	O
the	O
majority	O
are	O
missense	O
mutations	O
clustering	O
in	O
the	O
helical	O
(	O
e524k	O
and	O
e545k	O
)	O
and	O
catalytic	O
(	O
h1047r	O
)	O
domains	O
(	O
kalinsky	PERS
et	O
al	O
,	O
2009	O
)	O
.	O
in	O
the	O
phase	O
3	O
bolero-2	O
trial	O
,	O
everolimus	O
plus	O
exemestane	O
prolonged	O
the	O
progression-free	O
survival	O
(	O
pfs	O
)	O
vs	O
placebo	O
plus	O
exemestane	O
(	O
median	O
pfs	O
,	O
7.8	O
vs	O
3.2	O
months	O
;	O
hazard	O
ratio	O
(	O
hr	O
)	O
,	O
0.45	O
;	O
p	O
<	O
0.0001	O
)	O
in	O
patients	O
with	O
hormone	O
receptor	O
positive	O
(	O
hr+	O
)	O
,	O
human	O
epidermal	O
growth	O
factor	O
receptor-2	O
negative	O
(	O
her2−	O
)	O
metastatic	O
breast	O
cancer	O
(	O
mbc	O
)	O
progressing	O
after	O
a	O
non-steroidal	O
aromatase	O
inhibitor	O
(	O
nsai	O
)	O
(	O
yardley	O
et	O
al	O
,	O
2013	O
)	O
.	O
an	O
exploratory	O
analysis	O
of	O
predominantly	O
primary	O
tumour	O
samples	O
from	O
roughly	O
40	O
%	O
of	O
the	O
bolero-2	O
trial	O
population	O
suggested	O
that	O
the	O
pfs	O
benefit	O
from	O
everolimus	O
was	O
largely	O
maintained	O
irrespective	O
of	O
pik3ca	O
genotype	O
(	O
hortobagyi	PERS
et	O
al	O
,	O
2016	O
)	O
.	O
however	O
,	O
given	O
that	O
differences	O
between	O
primary	O
and	O
mbc	O
may	O
arise	O
,	O
we	O
performed	O
an	O
analysis	O
of	O
pik3ca	O
hotspot	O
(	O
hs	O
)	O
mutations	O
by	O
droplet	O
digital	O
pcr	O
(	O
ddpcr	O
)	O
using	O
cell-free	O
dna	O
(	O
cfdna	O
)	O
from	O
plasma	O
samples	O
collected	O
at	O
the	O
time	O
of	O
patient	O
randomisation	O
and	O
evaluated	O
their	O
impact	O
on	O
everolimus	O
efficacy	O
in	O
76	O
%	O
of	O
the	O
bolero-2	O
participants	O
.	O
materials	O
and	O
methods	O
patients	O
and	O
cfdna	O
analysis	O
bolero-2	O
study	O
design	O
has	O
been	O
described	O
previously	O
(	O
baselga	O
et	O
al	O
,	O
2012	O
)	O
.	O
briefly	O
,	O
patients	O
with	O
hr+	O
,	O
her2−	O
mbc	O
recurring/progressing	O
on/after	O
nsai	O
were	O
randomised	O
2	O
:	O
1	O
to	O
everolimus	O
plus	O
exemestane	O
or	O
placebo	O
plus	O
exemestane	O
.	O
plasma	O
collection	O
,	O
cfdna	O
extraction	O
,	O
and	O
quantification	O
and	O
analysis	O
by	O
ddpcr	O
for	O
detection	O
were	O
performed	O
as	O
described	O
previously	O
(	O
chandarlapaty	PERS
et	O
al	O
,	O
2016	O
)	O
.	O
pik3ca	O
mutations	O
in	O
cfdna	O
were	O
detected	O
by	O
ddpcr	O
in	O
singleplex	O
assays	O
using	O
inventoried	O
assays	O
for	O
pik3ca	O
h1047r	O
(	O
dhsacp2000077	O
)	O
,	O
e545k	O
(	O
dhsacp2000075	O
)	O
,	O
and	O
e542k	O
(	O
dhsacp2000073	O
)	O
(	O
biorad	O
,	O
hercules	O
,	O
ca	O
,	O
usa	O
)	O
on	O
a	O
biorad	O
qx200	O
droplet	O
digital	O
pcr	O
system	O
.	O
each	O
assay	O
run	O
included	O
mutation	O
positive	O
template	O
,	O
wild-type	O
template	O
,	O
and	O
no	O
template	O
controls	O
.	O
the	O
fractional	O
abundance	O
for	O
the	O
pik3ca	O
mutation	O
was	O
calculated	O
from	O
the	O
number	O
of	O
fam-positive	O
events	O
(	O
mutation	O
positive	O
)	O
over	O
total	O
positive	O
events	O
(	O
both	O
fam	O
and	O
hex	O
positive	O
for	O
mutation	O
and	O
wild	O
type	O
,	O
respectively	O
)	O
using	O
quantasoft	O
version	O
1.7.4.0917	O
(	O
biorad	O
)	O
.	O
mutation	O
analyses	O
were	O
performed	O
on	O
anonymised	O
samples	O
.	O
written	O
informed	O
consent	O
was	O
obtained	O
from	O
all	O
patients	O
included	O
in	O
the	O
study	O
.	O
the	O
study	O
was	O
undertaken	O
in	O
accordance	O
with	O
the	O
good	O
clinical	O
practice	O
guidelines	O
and	O
the	O
declaration	O
of	O
helsinki	O
.	O
the	O
study	O
protocol	O
was	O
approved	O
by	O
an	O
independent	O
ethics	O
committee	O
or	O
institutional	O
review	O
board	O
at	O
each	O
site	O
.	O
statistical	O
analysis	O
median	O
pfs	O
was	O
estimated	O
by	O
kaplan–meier	O
method	O
in	O
patient	O
subgroups	O
defined	O
by	O
pik3ca	O
mutations	O
in	O
each	O
treatment	O
arm	O
.	O
hazard	O
ratios	O
with	O
95	O
%	O
confidence	O
intervals	O
(	O
cis	O
)	O
were	O
calculated	O
using	O
cox	O
proportional	O
hazards	O
model	O
for	O
treatment	O
vs	O
placebo	O
arm	O
in	O
the	O
wild-type	O
and	O
mutant	O
subgroups	O
.	O
multivariate	O
analysis	O
was	O
performed	O
to	O
adjust	O
for	O
the	O
potential	O
effects	O
of	O
prior	O
hormonal	O
therapy	O
,	O
visceral	O
disease	O
,	O
and	O
eastern	ORG
cooperative	ORG
oncology	ORG
group	ORG
status	O
.	O
results	O
pik3ca	O
mutation	O
frequency	O
of	O
the	O
724	O
patients	O
in	O
bolero-2	O
,	O
550	O
patients	O
(	O
76	O
%	O
)	O
underwent	O
pik3ca	O
cfdna	O
analysis	O
.	O
the	O
baseline	O
characteristics	O
and	O
clinical	O
outcomes	O
were	O
similar	O
between	O
the	O
cfdna	O
and	O
overall	O
population	O
(	O
supplementary	O
table	O
1	O
)	O
.	O
pik3ca	O
hs	O
mutations	O
were	O
identified	O
in	O
238	O
patients	O
(	O
43.3	O
%	O
)	O
;	O
the	O
most	O
prevalent	O
was	O
h1047r	O
(	O
25.1	O
%	O
)	O
,	O
followed	O
by	O
e545k	O
(	O
11.1	O
%	O
)	O
and	O
e542k	O
(	O
7.1	O
%	O
)	O
.	O
four	O
patients	O
had	O
multiple	O
hs	O
mutations	O
;	O
three	O
,	O
of	O
which	O
,	O
were	O
dual	O
helical	O
mutations	O
.	O
prevalence	O
of	O
total	O
and	O
domain-specific	O
pik3ca	O
mutations	O
was	O
higher	O
in	O
the	O
everolimus	O
arm	O
(	O
47.3	O
%	O
)	O
than	O
the	O
placebo	O
arm	O
(	O
35.8	O
%	O
;	O
table	O
1	O
)	O
.	O
full	O
table	O
concordance	O
between	O
mutations	O
detected	O
in	O
cfdna	O
and	O
archival	O
tumour	O
samples	O
plasma-derived	O
cfdna	O
samples	O
were	O
available	O
in	O
247	O
of	O
the	O
302	O
patients	O
who	O
underwent	O
mutation	O
analysis	O
on	O
archival	O
tumour	O
samples	O
(	O
198	O
primary	O
;	O
49	O
metastatic	O
)	O
by	O
next-generation	O
sequencing	O
(	O
ngs	O
)	O
(	O
hortobagyi	PERS
et	O
al	O
,	O
2016	O
)	O
.	O
the	O
overall	O
concordance	O
in	O
pik3ca	O
mutation	O
status	O
between	O
archival	O
tumour	O
and	O
cfdna	O
sample	O
pairs	O
was	O
70.4	O
%	O
,	O
with	O
a	O
higher	O
concordance	O
(	O
81.6	O
%	O
)	O
for	O
metastatic	O
lesions	O
.	O
for	O
concordant	O
samples	O
,	O
the	O
cfdna	O
mutant	O
fractional	O
abundance	O
was	O
generally	O
higher	O
than	O
in	O
the	O
discordant	O
samples	O
where	O
mutations	O
were	O
detected	O
only	O
by	O
ddpcr	O
in	O
cfdna	O
(	O
supplementary	O
figure	O
1	O
)	O
.	O
correlation	O
between	O
pik3ca	O
genotypes	O
and	O
everolimus	O
efficacy	O
clinical	O
benefit	O
with	O
everolimus	O
as	O
measured	O
by	O
pfs	O
was	O
similar	O
in	O
patients	O
with	O
tumours	O
that	O
had	O
wild-type	O
or	O
mutant	O
pik3ca	O
(	O
hr	O
,	O
0.43	O
(	O
95	O
%	O
ci	O
,	O
0.34–0.56	O
)	O
and	O
0.37	O
(	O
95	O
%	O
ci	O
,	O
0.27–0.51	O
)	O
,	O
respectively	O
)	O
(	O
table	O
2	O
;	O
figure	O
1a	O
)	O
.	O
a	O
multivariate	O
analysis	O
yielded	O
similar	O
results	O
(	O
hrs	O
for	O
pfs	O
:	O
pik3ca	O
wild-type	O
hr	O
,	O
0.39	O
(	O
95	O
%	O
ci	O
,	O
0.30–0.51	O
)	O
;	O
pik3ca-mutant	O
hr	O
,	O
0.35	O
(	O
95	O
%	O
ci	O
,	O
0.25–0.49	O
)	O
)	O
(	O
supplementary	O
table	O
3	O
)	O
.	O
kaplan-meier	O
plot	O
of	O
progression-free	O
survival	O
by	O
pik3ca	O
mutation	O
status	O
.	O
(	O
a	O
)	O
pik3ca	O
wild-type	O
vs	O
hotspot	O
mutations	O
.	O
(	O
b	O
)	O
pik3ca	O
wild-type	O
vs	O
domain-specific	O
hotspot	O
mutations	O
.	O
full	O
table	O
to	O
examine	O
the	O
role	O
of	O
domain-specific	O
mutations	O
in	O
pik3ca	O
on	O
everolimus	O
efficacy	O
,	O
patients	O
were	O
categorised	O
by	O
mutation	O
site	O
,	O
h1047r	O
in	O
the	O
catalytic	O
domain	O
,	O
and	O
e545k	O
and	O
e542k	O
in	O
the	O
helical	O
domain	O
.	O
everolimus	O
prolonged	O
median	O
pfs	O
vs	O
placebo	O
in	O
patients	O
with	O
pik3ca	O
h1047r	O
mutation	O
(	O
hr	O
,	O
0.37	O
;	O
95	O
%	O
ci	O
,	O
0.24–0.56	O
)	O
and	O
e545k/e542k	O
mutations	O
(	O
hr	O
,	O
0.30	O
;	O
95	O
%	O
ci	O
,	O
0.18–0.51	O
)	O
with	O
a	O
similar	O
magnitude	O
(	O
table	O
2	O
;	O
figure	O
1b	O
)	O
.	O
these	O
data	O
suggest	O
that	O
pfs	O
benefit	O
of	O
everolimus	O
was	O
maintained	O
irrespective	O
of	O
pik3ca	O
genotypes	O
.	O
in	O
the	O
placebo	O
arm	O
,	O
patients	O
with	O
e545k/e542k	O
mutation	O
had	O
shorter	O
pfs	O
and	O
overall	O
survival	O
than	O
those	O
with	O
wild-type	O
pik3ca	O
(	O
supplementary	O
table	O
2	O
)	O
,	O
suggesting	O
that	O
pik3ca	O
mutations	O
in	O
the	O
helical	O
domain	O
might	O
play	O
a	O
role	O
in	O
resistance	O
to	O
hormone	O
therapy	O
.	O
however	O
,	O
this	O
analysis	O
by	O
mutation	O
site	O
involved	O
small	O
numbers	O
and	O
was	O
highly	O
exploratory	O
.	O
discussion	O
the	O
advent	O
of	O
cfdna	O
analyses	O
has	O
facilitated	O
the	O
analysis	O
of	O
large	O
clinical	O
trial	O
populations	O
through	O
minimally	O
invasive	O
technologies	O
.	O
we	O
recently	O
determined	O
the	O
feasibility	O
for	O
detection	O
of	O
esr1	O
mutations	O
in	O
cfdna	O
by	O
ddpcr	O
on	O
stored	O
plasma	O
samples	O
from	O
the	O
bolero-2	O
clinical	O
trial	O
(	O
chandarlapaty	PERS
et	O
al	O
,	O
2016	O
)	O
.	O
notably	O
,	O
collection	O
of	O
these	O
plasma	O
samples	O
began	O
in	O
mid-2009	O
at	O
trial	O
enrolment	O
in	O
the	O
absence	O
of	O
a	O
plan	O
for	O
subsequent	O
cfdna	O
analysis	O
.	O
thus	O
,	O
data	O
from	O
large	O
,	O
mature	O
clinical	O
trials	O
can	O
be	O
extended	O
through	O
the	O
use	O
of	O
this	O
emerging	O
technology	O
.	O
in	O
this	O
report	O
,	O
we	O
assessed	O
the	O
impact	O
of	O
three	O
most	O
prevalent	O
pik3ca-activating	O
mutations	O
on	O
everolimus	O
efficacy	O
in	O
>	O
75	O
%	O
of	O
the	O
bolero-2	O
trial	O
population	O
,	O
thus	O
enabling	O
a	O
robust	O
mutation	O
analysis	O
that	O
demonstrates	O
everolimus	O
efficacy	O
regardless	O
of	O
pik3ca	O
genotypes	O
.	O
in	O
the	O
bolero-2	O
analysis	O
,	O
patients	O
with	O
tumours	O
harbouring	O
hs	O
mutations	O
in	O
both	O
helical	O
and	O
catalytic	O
domains	O
of	O
pik3ca	O
benefit	O
from	O
the	O
addition	O
of	O
everolimus	O
.	O
interestingly	O
,	O
in	O
the	O
placebo	O
arm	O
,	O
there	O
is	O
a	O
suggestion	O
of	O
inferior	O
clinical	O
outcome	O
in	O
the	O
small	O
group	O
harbouring	O
e545k/e542k	O
mutations	O
.	O
this	O
is	O
in	O
contrast	O
to	O
a	O
favourable	O
prognosis	O
associated	O
with	O
these	O
mutations	O
in	O
early-stage	O
cancer	O
(	O
kalinsky	PERS
et	O
al	O
,	O
2009	O
;	O
sabine	O
et	O
al	O
,	O
2014	O
)	O
,	O
no	O
effect	O
on	O
prognosis	O
in	O
patients	O
with	O
mbc	O
undergoing	O
first-line	O
hormonal	O
therapy	O
with	O
tamoxifen	O
and	O
an	O
improved	O
outcome	O
in	O
patients	O
with	O
mbc	O
with	O
first-line	O
aromatase	O
inhibitor	O
therapy	O
(	O
ramirez-ardila	O
et	O
al	O
,	O
2013	O
)	O
.	O
from	O
a	O
biologic	O
perspective	O
,	O
mutation	O
site-specific	O
differences	O
are	O
noted	O
for	O
interacting	O
proteins	O
(	O
zhao	O
and	O
vogt	O
,	O
2008	O
;	O
hao	O
et	O
al	O
,	O
2013	O
)	O
,	O
oncogenic	O
potency	O
and	O
behaviour	O
(	O
bader	O
et	O
al	O
,	O
2006	O
;	O
pang	O
et	O
al	O
,	O
2009	O
)	O
,	O
and	O
the	O
phosphoproteome	O
(	O
wu	O
et	O
al	O
,	O
2014	O
;	O
zahari	O
et	O
al	O
,	O
2015	O
)	O
that	O
may	O
be	O
clinically	O
important	O
and	O
deserve	O
further	O
analysis	O
in	O
clinical	O
studies	O
and	O
preclinical	O
modelling	O
.	O
approximately	O
,	O
70	O
%	O
concordance	O
for	O
pik3ca	O
genotype	O
by	O
pik3ca	O
analysis	O
of	O
archival	O
tumour	O
dna	O
by	O
ngs	O
and	O
contemporaneous	O
plasma-derived	O
cfdna	O
by	O
ddpcr	O
is	O
similar	O
to	O
that	O
reported	O
for	O
beaming	O
of	O
cfdna	O
and	O
sequencing	O
of	O
archival	O
tumour	O
(	O
higgins	PERS
et	O
al	O
,	O
2012	O
)	O
.	O
there	O
are	O
several	O
potential	O
biologic	O
and	O
technical	O
reasons	O
for	O
this	O
degree	O
of	O
discordance	O
.	O
ddpcr	O
of	O
plasma	O
cfdna	O
is	O
more	O
sensitive	O
for	O
mutation	O
detection	O
than	O
tumour	O
sequencing	O
(	O
guttery	PERS
et	O
al	O
,	O
2015	O
;	O
schiavon	O
et	O
al	O
,	O
2015	O
;	O
chu	O
et	O
al	O
,	O
2016	O
)	O
with	O
mutant	O
allele	O
fraction	O
(	O
maf	O
)	O
<	O
1–3	O
%	O
not	O
detected	O
by	O
ngs	O
(	O
guttery	PERS
et	O
al	O
,	O
2015	O
)	O
.	O
when	O
both	O
concurrent	O
biopsy	O
and	O
plasma	O
collection	O
are	O
performed	O
and	O
the	O
material	O
is	O
analysed	O
by	O
the	O
same	O
highly	O
sensitive	O
methodology	O
,	O
concordance	O
is	O
quite	O
high	O
(	O
higgins	PERS
et	O
al	O
,	O
2012	O
)	O
.	O
in	O
breast	O
cancer	O
,	O
pik3ca	O
mutation	O
is	O
thought	O
to	O
be	O
truncal	O
,	O
identified	O
in	O
dcis	O
,	O
primary	O
breast	O
cancer	O
,	O
and	O
selected	O
for	O
in	O
metastatic	O
tumour	O
(	O
kalinsky	PERS
et	O
al	O
,	O
2011	O
)	O
.	O
however	O
,	O
compelling	O
evidence	O
from	O
tumour	O
genome	O
sequencing	O
highlights	O
that	O
reliance	O
on	O
a	O
single	O
analysis	O
of	O
the	O
primary	O
tumour	O
may	O
not	O
be	O
suitable	O
for	O
guiding	O
therapy	O
in	O
patients	O
with	O
metastatic	O
disease	O
.	O
genomic	O
heterogeneity	O
in	O
multifocal	O
primary	O
tumours	O
identifies	O
pik3ca	O
mutations	O
occurring	O
in	O
~44	O
%	O
of	O
patients	O
,	O
but	O
in	O
only	O
half	O
is	O
the	O
mutation	O
identified	O
in	O
all	O
tumours	O
(	O
desmedt	O
et	O
al	O
,	O
2015	O
)	O
.	O
even	O
in	O
metastatic	O
disease	O
,	O
emergence	O
of	O
a	O
pik3ca	O
e545k	O
mutation	O
during	O
progression	O
has	O
been	O
reported	O
by	O
serial	O
cfdna	O
analysis	O
(	O
guttery	PERS
et	O
al	O
,	O
2015	O
)	O
.	O
conversely	O
,	O
absence	O
of	O
an	O
h1047r	O
mutation	O
in	O
hepatic	O
metastasis	O
and	O
cfdna	O
is	O
reported	O
,	O
when	O
present	O
in	O
the	O
primary	O
tumour	O
at	O
a	O
high	O
maf	O
of	O
40	O
%	O
(	O
butler	O
et	O
al	O
,	O
2015	O
)	O
.	O
in	O
larger	O
data	O
sets	O
of	O
paired	O
samples	O
,	O
both	O
the	O
loss	O
and	O
gain	O
of	O
pik3ca	O
mutation	O
in	O
metastatic	O
progression	O
is	O
observed	O
(	O
dupont	PERS
jensen	PERS
et	O
al	O
,	O
2011	O
;	O
arthur	O
et	O
al	O
,	O
2014	O
;	O
markou	O
et	O
al	O
,	O
2014	O
)	O
.	O
thus	O
,	O
although	O
selection	O
for	O
a	O
pik3ca-activating	O
mutation	O
is	O
expected	O
,	O
more	O
dominant	O
subclonal	O
populations	O
may	O
give	O
rise	O
to	O
the	O
metastatic	O
tumour	O
.	O
scientists	O
gear	O
up	O
to	O
run	O
for	O
office	O
in	O
a	O
world	O
of	O
“	O
alternate	O
facts	O
”	O
greetings	O
,	O
daily	O
readers	O
.	O
this	O
is	O
sy	O
taking	O
over	O
for	O
cliff	O
.	O
it	O
’	O
s	O
2017	O
and	O
we	O
live	O
in	O
a	O
world	O
of	O
“	O
alternate	O
facts	O
”	O
and	O
fake	O
news	O
.	O
the	O
nascent	O
trump	PERS
administration	O
has	O
wasted	O
little	O
time	O
in	O
challenging	O
well-established	O
science	O
,	O
including	O
the	O
reality	O
of	O
man-made	O
climate	O
change	O
and	O
the	O
safety	O
of	O
vaccines	O
.	O
the	O
president	O
’	O
s	O
decision	O
to	O
impose	O
a	O
gag	O
order	O
on	O
numerous	O
federal	O
agencies	O
,	O
including	O
the	O
u.s.	ORG
department	ORG
of	ORG
agriculture	ORG
and	ORG
environmental	ORG
protection	ORG
agency	ORG
,	O
stunned	O
many	O
observers	O
and	O
cut	O
off	O
vital	O
lines	O
of	O
communication	O
with	O
journalists	O
.	O
(	O
the	O
epa	O
has	O
also	O
been	O
ordered	O
to	O
freeze	O
all	O
grants	O
and	O
contracts	O
until	O
further	O
notice	O
.	O
)	O
at	O
times	O
,	O
it	O
can	O
seem	O
like	O
objective	O
truth	O
itself	O
is	O
under	O
assault	O
.	O
but	O
one	O
group	O
isn	O
’	O
t	O
ready	O
to	O
let	O
reality	O
slip	O
away	O
without	O
a	O
fight	O
.	O
the	O
atlantic	O
has	O
a	O
fascinating	O
piece	O
out	O
on	O
314	O
action	ORG
,	O
a	O
newly	O
formed	O
nonprofit	O
that	O
’	O
s	O
attempting	O
to	O
promote	O
science	O
to	O
the	O
public	O
and	O
elected	O
officials	O
alike	O
(	O
the	O
“	O
314	O
”	O
is	O
a	O
reference	O
to	O
pi	O
)	O
.	O
“	O
314	O
action	ORG
is	O
concerned	O
that	O
stem	O
education	O
in	O
the	O
united	LOC
states	LOC
is	O
falling	O
further	O
and	O
further	O
behind	O
the	O
rest	O
of	O
the	O
world	O
,	O
that	O
our	O
political	O
leaders	O
continue	O
to	O
deny	O
scientific	O
facts	O
and	O
that	O
congress	ORG
fails	O
to	O
fully	O
fund	O
scientific	O
research	O
so	O
we	O
can	O
solve	O
pressing	O
environmental	O
issues	O
like	O
climate	O
change	O
and	O
social	O
problems	O
like	O
gun	O
violence	O
,	O
”	O
says	O
the	O
group	O
on	O
its	O
website	O
.	O
one	O
of	O
314	O
action	ORG
’	O
s	O
biggest	O
goals	O
is	O
to	O
get	O
stem	O
leaders	O
into	O
elected	O
office	O
so	O
that	O
they	O
can	O
change	O
the	O
course	O
of	O
the	O
debate	O
from	O
the	O
inside	O
.	O
“	O
a	O
lot	O
of	O
scientists	O
traditionally	O
feel	O
that	O
science	O
is	O
above	O
politics	O
but	O
we	O
're	O
seeing	O
that	O
politics	O
is	O
not	O
above	O
getting	O
involved	O
in	O
science	O
,	O
”	O
said	O
shaughnessy	PERS
naughton	PERS
,	O
the	O
group	O
’	O
s	O
founder	O
,	O
in	O
an	O
interview	O
with	O
the	O
atlantic	O
.	O
“	O
we	O
're	O
losing	O
,	O
and	O
the	O
only	O
way	O
to	O
stop	O
that	O
is	O
to	O
get	O
more	O
people	O
with	O
scientific	O
backgrounds	O
at	O
the	O
table.	O
”	O
congress	ORG
is	O
overwhelmingly	O
filled	O
with	O
lawyers	O
and	O
business	O
people	O
.	O
the	O
closest	O
thing	O
there	O
is	O
to	O
a	O
scientific	O
contingent	O
is	O
the	O
smattering	O
of	O
physicians	O
in	O
the	O
house	ORG
and	O
senate	ORG
.	O
but	O
even	O
many	O
of	O
these	O
individuals	O
have	O
professed	O
some	O
controversial	O
views	O
on	O
scientific	O
issues	O
,	O
including	O
on	O
climate	O
change	O
and	O
vaccine	O
safety	O
.	O
314	O
action	ORG
’	O
s	O
science-driven	O
goal	O
may	O
be	O
noble	O
.	O
but	O
achieving	O
it	O
will	O
be	O
an	O
uphill	O
battle	O
.	O
and	O
as	O
the	O
scientists-turned-politicians	O
who	O
get	O
an	O
assist	O
from	O
the	O
group	O
will	O
soon	O
learn	O
,	O
it	O
’	O
s	O
one	O
thing	O
to	O
have	O
the	O
facts	O
–	O
convincing	O
constituents	O
and	O
the	O
public	O
at	O
large	O
that	O
they	O
’	O
re	O
right	O
is	O
another	O
matter	O
entirely	O
.	O
read	O
on	O
for	O
the	O
day	O
’	O
s	O
news	O
.	O
sy	PERS
mukherjee	PERS
@	O
the_sy_guy	O
sayak.mukherjee	O
@	O
fortune.com	O
digital	O
health	O
shark	O
tank-funded	O
smartphone	O
breathalyzer	O
slammed	O
by	O
ftc	O
for	O
false	O
claims	O
.	O
breathometer	ORG
,	O
the	O
digital	O
startup	O
that	O
wowed	O
shark	O
tank	O
investors	O
like	O
mark	PERS
cuban	PERS
with	O
its	O
smartphone-connected	O
breathalyzer	O
accessories	O
,	O
has	O
reached	O
a	O
settlement	O
with	O
the	O
federal	ORG
trade	ORG
commission	ORG
over	O
inaccurate	O
marketing	O
claims	O
.	O
the	O
company	O
had	O
advertised	O
its	O
products	O
as	O
comparable	O
to	O
those	O
used	O
by	O
law	O
enforcement	O
and	O
said	O
they	O
'd	O
undergone	O
government-grade	O
testing	O
;	O
the	O
ftc	O
alleged	O
that	O
neither	O
of	O
these	O
claims	O
were	O
actually	O
true	O
and	O
that	O
the	O
devices	O
often	O
underrepresented	O
blood	O
alcohol	O
levels	O
.	O
breathometer	ORG
will	O
have	O
to	O
issue	O
full	O
refunds	O
to	O
customers	O
who	O
bought	O
the	O
product	O
and	O
the	O
company	O
is	O
barred	O
from	O
making	O
similar	O
claims	O
in	O
the	O
future	O
absent	O
rigorous	O
testing	O
.	O
(	O
fortune	O
)	O
big	O
pharmas	O
band	O
together	O
to	O
give	O
health	O
care	O
providers	O
easy	O
digital	O
access	O
to	O
drug	O
info	O
.	O
a	O
consortium	O
of	O
six	O
pharmaceutical	O
giants	O
-	O
allergan	ORG
,	O
astrazeneca	ORG
,	O
biogen	ORG
,	O
glaxosmithkline	ORG
,	O
novartis	ORG
,	O
and	O
pfizer	ORG
-	O
are	O
joining	O
forces	O
with	O
life	O
sciences	O
it	O
firm	O
veeva	ORG
systems	ORG
to	O
create	O
a	O
group	O
called	O
align	O
biopharma	O
.	O
its	O
purpose	O
?	O
providing	O
doctors	O
and	O
health	O
care	O
providers	O
with	O
a	O
simple	O
way	O
to	O
digitally	O
access	O
information	O
about	O
drugs	O
.	O
this	O
is	O
a	O
hotly	O
sought	O
solution	O
in	O
physicians	O
'	O
offices	O
as	O
the	O
number	O
of	O
in-person	O
sales	O
rep	O
visits	O
dwindle	O
and	O
the	O
number	O
of	O
available	O
medicines	O
continues	O
to	O
balloon	O
.	O
doctors	O
must	O
often	O
maintain	O
scores	O
of	O
logins	O
for	O
various	O
pharmaceutical	O
companies	O
'	O
informational	O
websites	O
for	O
health	O
care	O
providers	O
.	O
align	O
wants	O
to	O
bring	O
that	O
number	O
down	O
to	O
a	O
single	O
login	O
that	O
opens	O
up	O
data	O
on	O
thousands	O
of	O
drugs	O
.	O
(	O
fiercepharma	O
)	O
indications	O
novartis	ORG
unveils	O
ambitious	O
cancer	O
immunotherapy	O
,	O
late-stage	O
pipeline	O
plans	O
.	O
pharma	ORG
giant	O
novartis	ORG
is	O
building	O
itself	O
quite	O
the	O
experimental	O
drug	O
pipeline	O
.	O
and	O
during	O
its	O
fourth	O
quarter	O
earnings	O
call	O
this	O
morning	O
,	O
the	O
company	O
asserted	O
its	O
belief	O
that	O
it	O
has	O
no	O
less	O
than	O
13	O
potential	O
blockbuster	O
medicines	O
in	O
late-stage	O
trials	O
.	O
and	O
one	O
new	O
addition	O
to	O
the	O
list	O
is	O
particularly	O
intriguing	O
:	O
ctl019	O
,	O
its	O
chimeric	O
antigen	O
receptor	O
t-cell	O
(	O
car-t	O
)	O
therapy	O
.	O
as	O
daily	O
readers	O
know	O
,	O
car-t	O
is	O
one	O
of	O
the	O
most	O
closely-watched	O
new	O
technologies	O
in	O
cancer	O
therapeutics	O
.	O
it	O
involves	O
extracting	O
killer	O
immune	O
t-cells	O
and	O
turning	O
them	O
into	O
cancer-targeting	O
machines	O
before	O
pumping	O
them	O
back	O
into	O
a	O
patient	O
's	O
body	O
.	O
novartis	ORG
,	O
kite	ORG
pharma	ORG
,	O
and	O
a	O
number	O
of	O
other	O
drug	O
makers	O
are	O
in	O
a	O
race	O
to	O
get	O
the	O
first	O
approved	O
car-t	O
therapy	O
on	O
the	O
market	O
.	O
and	O
novartis	ORG
'	O
update	O
today	O
shows	O
that	O
it	O
thinks	O
the	O
drugs	O
have	O
massive	O
market	O
potential	O
.	O
shkreli	PERS
hits	O
back	O
hard	O
at	O
phrma	O
over	O
drug	O
pricing	O
hypocrisy	O
.	O
biopharma	O
's	O
drug	O
pricing	O
black	O
sheep	O
is	O
on	O
a	O
mission	O
to	O
show	O
that	O
he	O
's	O
just	O
one	O
of	O
the	O
flock	O
.	O
martin	PERS
shkreli	PERS
,	O
who	O
in	O
some	O
ways	O
helped	O
nationalize	O
the	O
drug	O
price	O
hike	O
uproar	O
,	O
has	O
launched	O
a	O
new	O
website	O
called	O
``	O
pharma	ORG
skeletons	O
''	O
that	O
outlines	O
numerous	O
pharmaceutical	O
research	O
and	O
manufacturers	O
of	O
america	LOC
(	O
phrma	O
)	O
member	O
companies	O
that	O
have	O
indulged	O
in	O
extravagant	O
price	O
increases	O
.	O
shkreli	PERS
felt	O
compelled	O
to	O
hit	O
back	O
at	O
phrma	O
(	O
which	O
kicked	O
out	O
both	O
him	O
and	O
his	O
former	O
company	O
turing	ORG
after	O
the	O
5,000	O
%	O
price	O
hike	O
that	O
put	O
shkreli	PERS
on	O
the	O
map	O
)	O
because	O
its	O
president	O
and	O
ceo	O
,	O
stephen	PERS
ubl	PERS
,	O
called	O
out	O
shkreli	PERS
as	O
unrepresentative	O
of	O
the	O
industry	O
while	O
discussing	O
a	O
massive	O
new	O
phrma	O
pr	O
campaign	O
meant	O
to	O
win	O
over	O
hearts	O
and	O
minds	O
.	O
(	O
fortune	O
)	O
could	O
gilead	O
's	O
hepatitis	O
c	O
superstars	O
have	O
a	O
safety	O
problem	O
?	O
a	O
new	O
report	O
published	O
by	O
the	O
institute	ORG
for	ORG
safe	ORG
medication	ORG
practices	ORG
today	O
raises	O
safety	O
concerns	O
about	O
nine	O
antiviral	O
drugs	O
that	O
are	O
used	O
to	O
treat	O
hepatitis	O
c	O
-	O
including	O
gilead	O
's	O
game-changing	O
hep	O
c	O
cures	O
sovaldi	O
and	O
harvoni	O
.	O
the	O
report	O
is	O
far	O
from	O
conclusive	O
and	O
the	O
number	O
of	O
patients	O
experiencing	O
the	O
adverse	O
events	O
is	O
small	O
(	O
the	O
report	O
also	O
states	O
that	O
it	O
's	O
unclear	O
if	O
it	O
's	O
the	O
drugs	O
themselves	O
that	O
are	O
causing	O
the	O
side	O
effects	O
)	O
.	O
but	O
the	O
safety	O
issues	O
that	O
are	O
present	O
are	O
quite	O
serious	O
,	O
including	O
liver	O
failure	O
.	O
(	O
new	ORG
york	ORG
times	ORG
)	O
the	O
big	O
picture	O
arizona	LOC
children	O
at	O
risk	O
of	O
coverage	O
loss	O
under	O
obamacare	O
repeal	O
.	O
the	O
obamacare	O
repeal	O
drama	O
has	O
mostly	O
focused	O
on	O
what	O
nixing	O
the	O
health	O
law	O
will	O
mean	O
for	O
adults	O
who	O
buy	O
coverage	O
on	O
the	O
individual	O
insurance	O
marketplace	O
(	O
and	O
the	O
working	O
poor	O
who	O
might	O
lose	O
their	O
insurance	O
if	O
the	O
medicaid	ORG
expansion	O
is	O
rolled	O
back	O
)	O
.	O
but	O
in	O
at	O
least	O
one	O
state	O
,	O
children	O
's	O
health	O
care	O
is	O
at	O
stake	O
,	O
too	O
.	O
that	O
's	O
because	O
arizona	LOC
's	O
kidscare	O
-	O
the	O
state	O
's	O
version	O
of	O
the	O
children	O
's	O
health	O
insurance	O
program	O
(	O
chip	O
)	O
,	O
which	O
covers	O
kids	O
from	O
families	O
who	O
are	O
n't	O
quite	O
poor	O
enough	O
to	O
qualify	O
for	O
medicaid	ORG
-	O
is	O
funded	O
by	O
obamacare	O
.	O
the	O
program	O
was	O
frozen	O
by	O
arizona	LOC
lawmakers	O
in	O
2010	O
but	O
reinstated	O
with	O
the	O
passage	O
of	O
the	O
health	O
law	O
through	O
at	O
least	O
the	O
end	O
of	O
2017	O
.	O
its	O
future	O
is	O
now	O
decidedly	O
uncertain	O
.	O
(	O
npr	ORG
)	O
required	O
reading	O
why	O
trump	PERS
ditching	O
the	O
tpp	O
could	O
hit	O
drug	O
makers	O
where	O
it	O
hurts	O
,	O
by	O
sy	PERS
mukherjee	PERS
big	ORG
investors	ORG
are	O
betting	O
president	O
trump	PERS
wo	O
n't	O
be	O
able	O
to	O
dump	O
obamacare	O
,	O
by	O
reuters	ORG
apple	ORG
and	O
fitbit	ORG
dominated	O
holiday	O
sales	O
of	O
wearables	O
,	O
by	O
aaron	PERS
pressman	PERS
the	O
dow	ORG
just	O
hit	O
20,000	O
for	O
the	O
first	O
time	O
in	O
history	O
,	O
by	O
lucinda	PERS
shen	PERS
[	O
ceo_attribution	O
author=	O
''	O
produced	O
by	O
sy	PERS
mukherjee	PERS
''	O
email=	O
''	O
sayak.mukherjee	O
@	O
fortune.com	O
''	O
twitter=	O
''	O
the_sy_guy	O
''	O
]	O
find	O
past	O
coverage	O
.	O
sign	O
up	O
for	O
other	O
fortune	O
newsletters	O
.	O
why	O
the	O
trump	PERS
drug	O
rally	O
won	O
’	O
t	O
last	O
the	O
stock	O
market	PERS
has	O
been	O
a	O
lousy	O
prognosticator	O
of	O
late	O
.	O
prior	O
to	O
the	O
election	O
,	O
mr.	O
market	PERS
seemed	O
utterly	O
convinced	O
of	O
a	O
clinton	PERS
win	O
.	O
(	O
it	O
did	O
n't	O
happen	O
.	O
)	O
then	O
,	O
as	O
the	O
outcome	O
looked	O
clear	O
,	O
it	O
predicted	O
panic	O
--	O
then	O
galloped	O
giddily	O
into	O
euphoria	O
.	O
(	O
hapless	O
traders	O
trying	O
to	O
chase	O
these	O
ups	O
and	O
downs	O
no	O
doubt	O
mistimed	O
them	O
--	O
because	O
,	O
well	O
,	O
it	O
's	O
a	O
sucker	O
's	O
game	O
to	O
try	O
to	O
time	O
the	O
market	PERS
.	O
but	O
then	O
you	O
knew	O
that	O
...	O
)	O
that	O
said	O
,	O
the	O
market	PERS
has	O
seemed	O
to	O
send	O
a	O
more	O
consistent	O
message	O
regarding	O
the	O
pharma	O
and	O
biotech	O
industries	O
.	O
after	O
the	O
news	O
of	O
trump	PERS
's	O
victory	O
,	O
stocks	O
of	O
drug	O
makers	O
shot	O
up	O
--	O
a	O
sharp	O
reversal	O
from	O
the	O
previous	O
few	O
months	O
of	O
mostly	O
steady	O
decline	O
when	O
,	O
to	O
many	O
,	O
a	O
clinton	PERS
presidency	O
seemed	O
inevitable	O
.	O
shareholders	O
were	O
also	O
buoyed	O
by	O
the	O
defeat	O
of	O
prop	O
61	O
,	O
the	O
california	LOC
ballot	O
initiative	O
that	O
promised	O
to	O
lower	O
drug	O
prices	O
by	O
pegging	O
what	O
state	O
agencies	O
paid	O
to	O
prices	O
negotiated	O
by	O
the	O
u.s.	ORG
department	ORG
of	ORG
veterans	ORG
affairs	ORG
--	O
an	O
effort	O
the	O
drug	O
industry	O
reportedly	O
spent	O
$	O
109	O
million	O
to	O
defeat	O
.	O
and	O
on	O
first	O
glance	O
,	O
the	O
recent	O
enthusiasm	O
makes	O
sense	O
:	O
clinton	PERS
signaled	O
that	O
she	O
would	O
come	O
down	O
hard	O
on	O
drug	O
company	O
``	O
price	O
gouging	O
''	O
in	O
september	O
,	O
which	O
sent	O
stocks	O
reeling	O
.	O
(	O
favorite	O
hyperbolic	O
headline	O
:	O
``	O
clinton	PERS
delivers	O
poison	O
pill	O
to	O
biotech	O
etfs	O
``	O
)	O
.	O
trump	PERS
,	O
for	O
his	O
part	O
,	O
has	O
said	O
little	O
on	O
the	O
matter	O
.	O
clinton	PERS
looked	O
as	O
if	O
she	O
would	O
continue	O
a	O
cautious	O
regulatory	O
approach	O
at	O
the	O
fda	ORG
.	O
trump	PERS
has	O
said	O
he	O
wants	O
to	O
cut	O
``	O
the	O
red	O
tape	O
at	O
the	O
fda	ORG
,	O
''	O
claiming	O
``	O
there	O
are	O
over	O
4,000	O
drugs	O
awaiting	O
approval	O
,	O
and	O
we	O
especially	O
want	O
to	O
speed	O
the	O
approval	O
of	O
life-saving	O
medications	O
.	O
''	O
(	O
no	O
,	O
the	O
``	O
4,000	O
''	O
drug	O
backlog	O
does	O
n't	O
refer	O
to	O
what	O
you	O
think	O
--	O
and	O
is	O
n't	O
true	O
in	O
any	O
case	O
.	O
)	O
clinton	PERS
would	O
largely	O
keep	O
obamacare	O
;	O
and	O
trump	PERS
,	O
well	O
,	O
i	O
wrote	O
about	O
this	O
on	O
nov.	O
9	O
.	O
which	O
brings	O
me	O
to	O
whether	O
our	O
friend	O
mr.	O
market	PERS
is	O
right	O
or	O
wrong	O
on	O
pharma	O
's	O
future	O
in	O
the	O
trump	PERS
era	O
.	O
the	O
answer	O
is	O
neither	O
.	O
(	O
psst	O
--	O
it	O
does	O
n't	O
know	O
.	O
)	O
the	O
confusion	O
does	O
n't	O
just	O
center	O
over	O
what	O
happens	O
(	O
and	O
when	O
)	O
to	O
the	O
aca	O
--	O
or	O
on	O
any	O
prospective	O
new	O
drug-pricing	O
regulation	O
,	O
for	O
that	O
matter	O
.	O
trump	PERS
has	O
said	O
he	O
favors	O
introducing	O
more	O
competition	O
into	O
the	O
healthcare	O
marketplace	O
,	O
including	O
letting	O
medicare	ORG
negotiate	O
on	O
drug	O
prices	O
.	O
and	O
market	PERS
competition	O
will	O
do	O
more	O
to	O
lower	O
prices	O
than	O
anything	O
.	O
a	O
case	O
in	O
point	O
:	O
gilead	O
's	O
steep	O
stock	O
drop	O
in	O
october	O
had	O
nothing	O
to	O
do	O
with	O
any	O
political	O
rhetoric	O
on	O
sky-high	O
drug	O
costs	O
,	O
but	O
rather	O
with	O
the	O
fact	O
that	O
its	O
$	O
80,000	O
or	O
so	O
hep	O
c	O
combination	O
therapy	O
(	O
harvoni	O
)	O
might	O
face	O
pricing	O
pressure	O
from	O
rivals	O
j	O
&	O
j	O
and	O
abbvie	ORG
--	O
adding	O
another	O
challenge	O
to	O
a	O
company	O
already	O
facing	O
a	O
drop	O
in	O
its	O
hcv	O
drug	O
sales	O
.	O
nor	O
will	O
a	O
change	O
at	O
the	O
helm	O
at	O
fda	ORG
do	O
much	O
to	O
alter	O
the	O
pharma	O
horizon	O
.	O
the	O
drags	O
on	O
the	O
industry	O
today	O
revolve	O
around	O
a	O
paucity	O
of	O
innovation	O
and	O
the	O
expensive	O
,	O
late-stage	O
failures	O
of	O
drugs	O
that	O
continue	O
to	O
plague	O
it	O
.	O
those	O
are	O
two	O
problems	O
that	O
drug	O
makers	O
will	O
have	O
to	O
fix	O
on	O
their	O
own	O
.	O
more	O
news	O
below	O
.	O
clifton	PERS
leaf	PERS
@	O
cliftonleaf	O
clifton.leaf	O
@	O
fortune.com	O
digital	O
health	O
the	O
nih	O
is	O
funding	O
a	O
study	O
of	O
an	O
artificial	O
pancreas	O
.	O
in	O
late	O
september	O
,	O
the	O
food	ORG
and	ORG
drug	ORG
administration	ORG
green	O
lighted	O
the	O
first-ever	O
``	O
artificial	O
pancreas	O
,	O
''	O
medtronic	ORG
's	O
minimed	O
670g	O
.	O
now	O
,	O
the	O
national	ORG
institutes	ORG
of	ORG
health	ORG
(	O
nih	O
)	O
funded	O
international	O
diabetes	O
closed	O
loop	O
trial	O
is	O
enlisting	O
dexcom	O
,	O
tandem	O
diabetes	O
care	O
,	O
and	O
the	O
digital	O
health	O
firm	O
typezero	ORG
technologies	ORG
to	O
create	O
a	O
``	O
closed-loop	O
''	O
insulin	O
delivery	O
system	O
to	O
treat	O
type	O
1	O
diabetes	O
.	O
the	O
experimental	O
system	O
will	O
incorporate	O
a	O
glucose	O
sensor	O
made	O
by	O
dexcom	O
,	O
an	O
insulin	O
pump	O
from	O
tandem	O
,	O
and	O
a	O
smartphone	O
app	O
developed	O
by	O
typezero	ORG
.	O
with	O
an	O
artificial	O
pancreas	O
,	O
insulin	O
levels	O
can	O
be	O
adjusted	O
continuously	O
in	O
response	O
to	O
changes	O
in	O
blood	O
sugar	O
,	O
which	O
are	O
monitored	O
by	O
the	O
system	O
.	O
and	O
the	O
device	O
will	O
also	O
give	O
users	O
the	O
option	O
to	O
manually	O
administer	O
higher	O
doses	O
,	O
such	O
as	O
before	O
meals	O
.	O
(	O
fiercepharma	O
,	O
fortune	O
)	O
google	ORG
honors	O
insulin	O
pioneer	O
frederick	PERS
banting	PERS
.	O
google	ORG
regularly	O
pays	O
respects	O
to	O
scientific	O
luminaries	O
.	O
and	O
on	O
monday	O
,	O
the	O
company	O
's	O
search	O
engine	O
homepage	O
has	O
a	O
``	O
doodle	O
''	O
featuring	O
sir	O
frederick	PERS
banting	PERS
,	O
a	O
nobel	O
laureate	O
in	O
medicine	O
who	O
was	O
the	O
first	O
person	O
to	O
use	O
insulin	O
in	O
humans	O
.	O
banting	PERS
was	O
able	O
to	O
isolate	O
insulin	O
from	O
the	O
pancreases	O
of	O
dogs	O
and	O
calves	O
alongside	O
his	O
partners	O
dr.	O
charles	PERS
best	PERS
(	O
with	O
whom	O
banting	PERS
would	O
eventually	O
share	O
his	O
nobel	O
prize	O
money	O
)	O
and	O
j.j.r	O
.	O
macleod	O
,	O
with	O
whom	O
he	O
shared	O
the	O
prize	O
itself	O
.	O
himss	ORG
health	O
it	O
conference	O
will	O
feature	O
ibm	ORG
chief	O
and	O
former	O
house	ORG
speaker	O
boehner	PERS
.	O
the	O
healthcare	ORG
information	ORG
and	ORG
management	ORG
systems	ORG
society	ORG
(	O
himss	ORG
)	O
annual	O
meeting	O
is	O
arguably	O
the	O
most	O
important	O
health	O
it	O
conference	O
to	O
take	O
place	O
each	O
year	O
.	O
in	O
2017	O
,	O
it	O
's	O
going	O
to	O
feature	O
an	O
all-star	O
roster	O
of	O
keynote	O
speakers	O
including	O
ibm	ORG
ceo	O
ginni	PERS
rometty	PERS
,	O
former	O
house	ORG
speaker	O
john	PERS
boehner	PERS
,	O
and	O
shark	O
tank	O
investors	O
robert	PERS
herjavec	PERS
and	O
kevin	PERS
o'leary	PERS
.	O
after	O
stepping	O
down	O
as	O
speaker	O
,	O
boehner	PERS
joined	O
the	O
board	O
of	O
tobacco	O
giant	O
reynolds	ORG
american	ORG
and	O
the	O
d.c.	LOC
law	O
firm	O
squire	ORG
patton	ORG
boggs	ORG
.	O
himss	ORG
2017	O
will	O
run	O
from	O
february	O
19-23	O
,	O
2017	O
,	O
in	O
florida	LOC
and	O
will	O
focus	O
on	O
a	O
host	O
of	O
topics	O
including	O
interoperability	O
,	O
cybersecurity	O
,	O
health	O
data	O
analytics	O
,	O
and	O
more	O
.	O
(	O
healthcare	O
it	O
news	O
)	O
fda	ORG
proposes	O
studying	O
a	O
key	O
issue	O
in	O
pharma	O
's	O
digital	O
marketing	O
.	O
the	O
regulations	O
surrounding	O
drug	O
marketing	O
have	O
n't	O
exactly	O
kept	O
up	O
with	O
the	O
digital	O
age	O
.	O
since	O
2009	O
,	O
biopharma	O
firms	O
have	O
had	O
trouble	O
promoting	O
their	O
products	O
on	O
platforms	O
like	O
twitter	ORG
because	O
u.s.	LOC
rules	O
require	O
all	O
drug	O
ads	O
to	O
present	O
comprehensive	O
(	O
and	O
lengthy	O
)	O
safety	O
and	O
side	O
effect	O
information	O
.	O
companies	O
figured	O
that	O
including	O
an	O
outside	O
link	O
to	O
safety	O
information	O
in	O
social	O
media	O
drug	O
ads	O
would	O
suffice	O
;	O
the	O
fda	ORG
disagreed	O
.	O
but	O
the	O
agency	O
in	O
now	O
proposing	O
a	O
study	O
to	O
see	O
whether	O
or	O
not	O
these	O
links	O
can	O
be	O
just	O
as	O
effective	O
for	O
giving	O
patients	O
the	O
information	O
they	O
need	O
.	O
and	O
if	O
regulators	O
eventually	O
conclude	O
that	O
drug	O
makers	O
can	O
use	O
this	O
tactic	O
in	O
their	O
social	O
media	O
marketing	O
,	O
it	O
could	O
open	O
up	O
an	O
entirely	O
new	O
horizon	O
in	O
digital	O
medicine	O
promotion	O
.	O
(	O
fiercepharma	O
)	O
indications	O
ptc	ORG
therapeutics	ORG
can	O
keep	O
its	O
controversial	O
duchenne	O
drug	O
on	O
the	O
market	PERS
.	O
ptc	ORG
therapeutics	ORG
got	O
a	O
massive	O
break	O
on	O
friday	O
when	O
european	O
regulators	O
decided	O
to	O
allow	O
translarna	ORG
,	O
the	O
company	O
's	O
controversial	O
treatment	O
for	O
duchenne	O
muscular	O
dystrophy	O
,	O
a	O
devastating	O
genetic	O
disorder	O
that	O
leads	O
to	O
loss	O
of	O
motor	O
function	O
,	O
to	O
remain	O
on	O
the	O
market	PERS
.	O
many	O
analysts	O
had	O
expected	O
the	O
drug	O
's	O
marketing	O
approval	O
to	O
be	O
revoked	O
given	O
its	O
checkered	O
efficacy	O
.	O
but	O
the	O
advisory	O
body	O
to	O
the	O
european	ORG
medicines	ORG
agency	ORG
is	O
recommending	O
that	O
sales	O
be	O
allowed	O
to	O
continue	O
as	O
long	O
as	O
ptc	ORG
can	O
prove	O
significant	O
efficacy	O
through	O
a	O
pair	O
of	O
larger	O
studies	O
(	O
which	O
wo	O
n't	O
conclude	O
until	O
2021	O
)	O
.	O
ptc	ORG
shares	O
soared	O
more	O
than	O
88	O
%	O
in	O
friday	O
trading	O
and	O
is	O
up	O
about	O
another	O
9	O
%	O
in	O
early	O
monday	O
trading	O
.	O
(	O
fortune	O
)	O
novartis	ORG
may	O
snap	O
up	O
generic	O
drug	O
maker	O
amneal	ORG
for	O
$	O
8	O
billion	O
.	O
sources	O
tell	O
bloomberg	ORG
that	O
pharma	O
giant	O
novartis	ORG
may	O
be	O
close	O
to	O
hammering	O
out	O
a	O
deal	O
for	O
the	O
closely	O
held	O
u.s.	LOC
generics	O
firm	O
amneal	ORG
pharmaceuticals	ORG
,	O
which	O
could	O
be	O
valued	O
at	O
as	O
much	O
as	O
$	O
8	O
billion	O
.	O
the	O
company	O
makes	O
generic	O
treatments	O
for	O
conditions	O
like	O
herpes	O
and	O
epilepsy	O
,	O
and	O
novartis	ORG
'	O
generic	O
drug	O
unit	O
sandoz	ORG
could	O
get	O
a	O
boost	O
from	O
an	O
acquisition	O
--	O
especially	O
in	O
light	O
of	O
teva	O
's	O
$	O
40.5	O
billion	O
buyout	O
of	O
allergan	O
's	O
generic	O
drug	O
portfolio	O
.	O
still	O
,	O
as	O
bloomberg	ORG
notes	O
,	O
the	O
deal	O
could	O
come	O
at	O
a	O
difficult	O
time	O
for	O
the	O
generic	O
industry	O
given	O
ongoing	O
justice	ORG
department	ORG
investigations	O
into	O
potential	O
widescale	O
price	O
fixing	O
and	O
collusion	O
on	O
copycat	O
medicines	O
.	O
(	O
bloomberg	ORG
,	O
fortune	O
)	O
fda	ORG
rejects	O
dynavax	ORG
's	O
hepatitis	O
b	O
vaccine	O
(	O
again	O
)	O
.	O
shares	O
of	O
dynavax	ORG
plummeted	O
63	O
%	O
in	O
early	O
monday	O
trading	O
after	O
the	O
company	O
announced	O
that	O
the	O
food	ORG
and	ORG
drug	ORG
administration	ORG
had	O
,	O
once	O
again	O
,	O
declined	O
to	O
approve	O
its	O
hepatitis	O
b	O
vaccine	O
heplisav-b	O
.	O
dynavax	ORG
's	O
stock	O
has	O
been	O
on	O
a	O
bit	O
of	O
a	O
roller	O
coaster	O
this	O
year	O
;	O
shares	O
flew	O
in	O
early	O
2016	O
on	O
the	O
strength	O
of	O
late-stage	O
clinical	O
trials	O
demonstrating	O
heplisav-b	O
's	O
efficacy	O
.	O
but	O
the	O
firm	O
is	O
now	O
in	O
dire	O
straits	O
with	O
the	O
latest	O
fda	ORG
setback	O
--	O
and	O
ceo	O
eddie	PERS
gray	PERS
says	O
that	O
the	O
embattled	O
biotech	O
will	O
need	O
a	O
partner	O
to	O
help	O
get	O
the	O
experimental	O
treatment	O
to	O
market	PERS
.	O
``	O
[	O
t	O
]	O
he	O
time	O
and	O
resources	O
that	O
will	O
be	O
required	O
to	O
gain	O
approval	O
leads	O
us	O
to	O
consider	O
that	O
we	O
may	O
not	O
be	O
able	O
to	O
advance	O
this	O
program	O
on	O
our	O
own	O
and	O
we	O
are	O
moving	O
swiftly	O
to	O
identify	O
a	O
potential	O
pharmaceutical	O
or	O
financial	O
partner	O
,	O
''	O
he	O
said	O
in	O
a	O
statement	O
.	O
(	O
endpoints	O
)	O
the	O
big	O
picture	O
president-elect	O
trump	PERS
may	O
keep	O
some	O
major	O
parts	O
of	O
obamacare	O
.	O
in	O
a	O
seemingly	O
stunning	O
reversal	O
,	O
president-elect	O
donald	PERS
trump	PERS
told	O
both	O
the	O
wall	ORG
street	ORG
journal	ORG
and	O
60	O
minutes	O
that	O
he	O
's	O
open	O
to	O
keeping	O
some	O
of	O
obamacare	O
's	O
most	O
popular	O
provisions	O
,	O
including	O
guaranteed	O
insurance	O
coverage	O
for	O
americans	O
with	O
pre-existing	O
conditions	O
and	O
allowing	O
young	O
people	O
to	O
remain	O
on	O
their	O
parents	O
'	O
health	O
policies	O
up	O
until	O
the	O
age	O
of	O
26	O
.	O
it	O
's	O
unclear	O
how	O
that	O
would	O
work	O
in	O
tandem	O
with	O
trump	PERS
's	O
and	O
the	O
congressional	O
gop	ORG
's	O
promises	O
to	O
dismantle	O
the	O
law	O
,	O
including	O
repeal	O
of	O
its	O
mandate	O
requiring	O
americans	O
to	O
purchase	O
insurance	O
.	O
that	O
provision	O
is	O
meant	O
to	O
prevent	O
adverse	O
selection	O
in	O
the	O
market	PERS
,	O
since	O
otherwise	O
consumers	O
could	O
simply	O
wait	O
until	O
they	O
got	O
sick	O
to	O
buy	O
coverage	O
.	O
and	O
trump	PERS
's	O
transition	O
website	O
endorses	O
the	O
use	O
of	O
high-risk	O
pools	O
for	O
people	O
with	O
pre-existing	O
conditions	O
,	O
which	O
would	O
n't	O
be	O
necessary	O
with	O
guaranteed	O
issue	O
(	O
although	O
it	O
's	O
possible	O
that	O
's	O
what	O
trump	PERS
is	O
referring	O
to	O
when	O
he	O
says	O
he	O
likes	O
the	O
pre-existing	O
condition	O
provision	O
)	O
.	O
trump	PERS
said	O
that	O
his	O
oval	ORG
office	ORG
sit	O
down	O
with	O
president	O
obama	PERS
helped	O
convince	O
him	O
to	O
consider	O
keeping	O
those	O
parts	O
of	O
the	O
law	O
.	O
(	O
fortune	O
)	O
there	O
are	O
new	O
bird	O
flu	O
outbreaks	O
in	O
germany	LOC
,	O
switzerland	LOC
,	O
and	O
austria	LOC
.	O
europe	LOC
's	O
bird	O
flu	O
problem	O
got	O
worse	O
over	O
the	O
weekend	O
as	O
germany	LOC
,	O
switzerland	LOC
,	O
and	O
austria	LOC
all	O
announced	O
new	O
outbreaks	O
of	O
h5n8	O
,	O
a	O
dangerous	O
and	O
severe	O
bird	O
flu	O
strain	O
that	O
's	O
also	O
popped	O
up	O
in	O
the	LOC
netherlands	LOC
,	O
denmark	LOC
,	O
hungary	LOC
,	O
and	O
poland	LOC
,	O
in	O
poultry	O
.	O
regulators	O
and	O
food	O
safety	O
officials	O
announced	O
that	O
they	O
would	O
be	O
culling	O
tens	O
of	O
thousands	O
of	O
chickens	O
at	O
affected	O
farms	O
and	O
set	O
up	O
a	O
safety	O
radius	O
of	O
1.2	O
square	O
miles	O
surrounding	O
the	O
affected	O
regions	O
.	O
(	O
fortune	O
)	O
trump	PERS
's	O
win	O
is	O
fueling	O
a	O
huge	O
demand	O
for	O
iuds	O
and	O
donations	O
to	O
planned	ORG
parenthood	ORG
.	O
trump	PERS
's	O
election	O
last	O
week	O
helped	O
fuel	O
a	O
massive	O
surge	O
in	O
obamacare	O
enrollment	O
on	O
wednesday	O
.	O
it	O
's	O
also	O
leading	O
to	O
substantial	O
donations	O
to	O
planned	ORG
parenthood	ORG
and	O
huge	O
demand	O
for	O
iuds	O
out	O
of	O
fear	O
that	O
a	O
republican	O
congress	ORG
will	O
de-fund	O
the	O
family	O
planning	O
services	O
provider	O
over	O
abortion	O
procedures	O
.	O
the	O
planned	ORG
parenthood	ORG
federation	ORG
of	ORG
america	ORG
has	O
received	O
more	O
than	O
80,000	O
new	O
donations	O
from	O
across	O
the	O
country	O
following	O
trump	PERS
's	O
victory	O
,	O
and	O
several	O
local	O
planned	ORG
parenthood	ORG
affiliates	O
have	O
reported	O
big	O
spikes	O
in	O
appointment	O
requests	O
for	O
long-acting	O
contraceptives	O
such	O
as	O
iuds	O
.	O
(	O
fortune	O
)	O
required	O
reading	O
5	O
tech	O
gadgets	O
that	O
help	O
me	O
manage	O
my	O
life	O
,	O
by	O
greg	PERS
spencer	PERS
it	O
's	O
time	O
to	O
get	O
real	O
about	O
artificial	O
intelligence	O
,	O
by	O
adam	PERS
lashinsky	PERS
trump	PERS
and	O
the	O
supreme	ORG
court	ORG
:	O
5	O
big	O
questions	O
,	O
by	O
jeff	PERS
john	PERS
roberts	PERS
pfizer	ORG
's	O
celebrex	O
shown	O
to	O
be	O
as	O
safe	O
as	O
other	O
painkillers	O
,	O
by	O
reuters	ORG
[	O
ceo_attribution	O
author=	O
''	O
produced	O
by	O
sy	PERS
mukherjee	PERS
''	O
email=	O
''	O
sayak.mukherjee	O
@	O
fortune.com	O
''	O
twitter=	O
''	O
the_sy_guy	O
''	O
]	O
find	O
past	O
coverage	O
.	O
sign	O
up	O
for	O
other	O
fortune	O
newsletters	O
.	O
getting	O
real	O
about	O
addiction—finally	O
the	O
u.s	O
.	O
surgeon	O
general	O
released	O
a	O
remarkable	O
report	O
yesterday	O
,	O
entitled	O
facing	O
addiction	O
in	O
america	LOC
.	O
it	O
's	O
hard	O
to	O
believe	O
that	O
this	O
is	O
that	O
office	O
's	O
first-ever	O
comprehensive	O
study	O
of	O
substance	O
misuse	O
in	O
the	O
u.s.	LOC
--	O
but	O
what	O
the	O
government	O
lacks	O
in	O
response	O
time	O
it	O
has	O
made	O
up	O
for	O
in	O
thoroughness	O
.	O
the	O
report	O
is	O
powerful	O
,	O
candid	O
,	O
and	O
surprisingly	O
well	O
written	O
.	O
(	O
i	O
read	O
about	O
200	O
pages	O
of	O
it	O
last	O
night	O
,	O
though	O
admittedly	O
a	O
good	O
chunk	O
was	O
in	O
the	O
form	O
of	O
tables	O
.	O
)	O
in	O
case	O
it	O
was	O
n't	O
obvious	O
from	O
the	O
headlines	O
greeting	O
us	O
everyday	O
:	O
``	O
the	O
united	ORG
states	LOC
has	O
a	O
serious	O
substance	O
misuse	O
problem	O
.	O
''	O
and	O
that	O
misuse	O
--	O
66.7	O
million	O
americans	O
acknowledge	O
binge	O
drinking	O
in	O
the	O
past	O
month	O
;	O
more	O
than	O
27	O
million	O
americans	O
currently	O
use	O
illicit	O
drugs	O
or	O
misuse	O
prescription	O
meds	O
like	O
painkillers	O
--	O
has	O
a	O
profound	O
cost	O
for	O
the	O
nation	O
.	O
but	O
the	O
sg	O
's	O
report	O
does	O
n't	O
just	O
make	O
a	O
definitive	O
case	O
about	O
the	O
reality	O
and	O
stakes	O
of	O
the	O
crisis	O
,	O
it	O
offers	O
a	O
smart	O
and	O
sober	O
plan	O
forward	O
.	O
technology	O
plays	O
a	O
big	O
role	O
in	O
that	O
.	O
chapter	O
4	O
of	O
the	O
report	O
,	O
which	O
delves	O
into	O
tools	O
that	O
are	O
available	O
for	O
early	O
intervention	O
and	O
treatment	O
--	O
has	O
a	O
good	O
(	O
but	O
too	O
brief	O
)	O
section	O
on	O
how	O
emerging	O
technologies	O
,	O
from	O
telemedicine	O
to	O
web-based	O
cognitive	O
behavioral	O
training	O
,	O
can	O
offer	O
inexpensive	O
and	O
timely	O
help	O
for	O
millions	O
.	O
to	O
the	O
extent	O
that	O
these	O
new	O
approaches	O
catch	O
on	O
,	O
you	O
can	O
thank	O
in	O
large	O
part	O
a	O
slew	O
of	O
new	O
entrepreneurs	O
and	O
the	O
venture	O
capitalists	O
backing	O
them	O
.	O
in	O
recent	O
months	O
,	O
several	O
innovative	O
startups	O
have	O
launched	O
with	O
the	O
aim	O
of	O
convincing	O
potential	O
customers	O
that	O
they	O
need	O
to	O
change	O
their	O
own	O
destructive	O
behaviors	O
(	O
in	O
theory	O
--	O
one	O
would	O
think	O
--	O
not	O
an	O
easy	O
sell	O
)	O
.	O
michael	PERS
laskoff	PERS
's	O
new	O
digital	O
health	O
offering	O
,	O
annum	O
health	O
--	O
which	O
provides	O
a	O
new	O
home-based	O
treatment	O
platform	O
for	O
heavy	O
drinkers	O
--	O
recently	O
raised	O
$	O
5	O
million	O
in	O
funding	O
.	O
former	O
wall	O
streeter	PERS
lauren	PERS
stahl	PERS
has	O
set	O
up	O
sparkite	O
,	O
an	O
``	O
aftercare	O
platform	O
''	O
built	O
specifically	O
for	O
mobile	O
devices	O
which	O
she	O
calls	O
``	O
addiction	O
support	O
in	O
the	O
pocket	O
.	O
''	O
pear	ORG
therapeutics	ORG
says	O
it	O
's	O
``	O
the	O
first	O
prescription	O
digital	O
therapy	O
designed	O
to	O
treat	O
opiate	O
dependence	O
.	O
''	O
and	O
venrock	O
-backed	O
lyra	O
health	O
,	O
cofounded	O
by	O
former	O
facebook	ORG
and	O
genentech	ORG
cfo	O
david	PERS
ebersman	PERS
,	O
works	O
with	O
employers	O
and	O
insurance	O
providers	O
to	O
coordinate	O
care	O
(	O
and	O
improve	O
outcomes	O
)	O
for	O
employees	O
with	O
regard	O
to	O
behavioral	O
health	O
issues	O
.	O
you	O
can	O
also	O
throw	O
into	O
the	O
mix	O
workit	O
health	O
,	O
mystrength	O
,	O
and	O
the	O
rock	O
health-backed	O
lantern	O
,	O
which	O
received	O
a	O
$	O
4	O
million	O
grant	O
from	O
the	O
national	ORG
institute	ORG
of	ORG
mental	ORG
health	ORG
.	O
private	O
insurers	O
are	O
becoming	O
much	O
more	O
aggressive	O
about	O
trying	O
to	O
stem	O
this	O
epidemic	O
as	O
well	O
--	O
see	O
,	O
for	O
example	O
,	O
sy	O
's	O
write-up	O
of	O
cigna	ORG
's	O
latest	O
effort	O
below	O
.	O
the	O
surgeon	O
general	O
calls	O
our	O
response	O
to	O
this	O
public	O
health	O
crisis	O
``	O
a	O
moral	O
test	O
for	O
america	LOC
.	O
''	O
he	O
is	O
right	O
.	O
read	O
on	O
for	O
more	O
.	O
and	O
please	O
be	O
sure	O
and	O
email	O
me	O
with	O
any	O
news	O
,	O
feedback	O
,	O
or	O
a	O
general	O
hello	O
.	O
i	O
would	O
love	O
to	O
hear	O
from	O
you	O
!	O
clifton	PERS
leaf	PERS
@	O
cliftonleaf	O
clifton.leaf	O
@	O
fortune.com	O
digital	O
health	O
intel	ORG
and	O
the	O
broad	ORG
institute	ORG
strike	O
a	O
5-year	O
genomic	O
data	O
collaboration	O
.	O
tech	O
giant	O
intel	ORG
and	O
the	O
broad	ORG
institute	ORG
of	ORG
mit	ORG
and	ORG
harvard	ORG
are	O
teaming	O
up	O
for	O
a	O
5-year	O
,	O
$	O
25	O
million	O
partnership	O
that	O
aims	O
to	O
make	O
it	O
easier	O
to	O
sift	O
through	O
the	O
mountains	O
of	O
genomic	O
data	O
which	O
are	O
piling	O
up	O
in	O
labs	O
and	O
academic	O
institutes	O
throughout	O
the	O
world	O
.	O
the	O
hope	O
is	O
that	O
the	O
new	O
intel-broad	ORG
center	ORG
for	ORG
genomic	ORG
data	ORG
engineering	ORG
will	O
be	O
able	O
to	O
create	O
a	O
data	O
``	O
superhighway	O
''	O
that	O
will	O
make	O
it	O
far	O
easier	O
for	O
scientists	O
to	O
access	O
information	O
in	O
disparate	O
cloud	O
networks	O
,	O
including	O
in	O
both	O
the	O
private	O
and	O
public	O
spheres	O
.	O
``	O
the	O
size	O
of	O
genomic	O
datasets	O
doubles	O
about	O
every	O
eight	O
months	O
and	O
,	O
as	O
it	O
does	O
,	O
the	O
challenge	O
of	O
acquiring	O
,	O
processing	O
,	O
storing	O
,	O
and	O
analyzing	O
this	O
information	O
increases	O
as	O
well	O
,	O
''	O
said	O
eric	PERS
banks	PERS
,	O
director	O
of	O
the	O
data	ORG
sciences	ORG
and	ORG
data	ORG
engineering	ORG
group	O
at	O
the	O
broad	ORG
institute	ORG
,	O
in	O
a	O
statement	O
.	O
``	O
working	O
with	O
intel	ORG
,	O
we	O
plan	O
to	O
build	O
out	O
solutions	O
that	O
can	O
work	O
across	O
different	O
infrastructures	O
to	O
facilitate	O
efficient	O
processing	O
of	O
these	O
growing	O
data	O
sets	O
,	O
and	O
then	O
make	O
these	O
tools	O
openly	O
available	O
for	O
researchers	O
worldwide	O
.	O
''	O
e-cigarettes	O
may	O
yellow	O
teeth	O
just	O
as	O
much	O
as	O
the	O
real	O
things	O
.	O
electronic	O
cigarettes	O
were	O
meant	O
to	O
be	O
one	O
of	O
the	O
earlier	O
examples	O
of	O
how	O
the	O
digital	O
health	O
revolution	O
could	O
extend	O
into	O
the	O
consumer	O
public	O
health	O
sphere	O
.	O
the	O
products	O
were	O
largely	O
hawked	O
as	O
healthier	O
alternatives	O
to	O
traditional	O
cigarettes	O
and	O
even	O
as	O
a	O
step	O
in	O
smoking	O
cessation	O
,	O
since	O
they	O
do	O
n't	O
have	O
some	O
of	O
the	O
more	O
obvious	O
carcinogens	O
in	O
cigarettes	O
.	O
but	O
new	O
research	O
has	O
brought	O
e-cigs	O
'	O
effect	O
on	O
health	O
into	O
question	O
--	O
including	O
suggestions	O
that	O
they	O
may	O
actually	O
be	O
encouraging	O
teens	O
who	O
may	O
otherwise	O
have	O
never	O
used	O
nicotine	O
products	O
at	O
all	O
to	O
smoke	O
.	O
and	O
a	O
new	O
study	O
on	O
3d	O
human	O
jaw	O
models	O
suggests	O
that	O
the	O
inflammation	O
and	O
irritation	O
caused	O
by	O
electronic	O
cigarette	O
vapor	O
may	O
be	O
just	O
as	O
deleterious	O
for	O
tooth	O
and	O
gum	O
tissue	O
health	O
.	O
(	O
fortune	O
)	O
trump	PERS
's	O
plans	O
to	O
scrap	O
obamacare	O
are	O
messing	O
with	O
his	O
in-law	O
's	O
$	O
2.7	O
billion	O
high-tech	O
insurance	O
startup	O
.	O
as	O
president	O
barack	PERS
obama	PERS
painfully	O
found	O
out	O
over	O
the	O
course	O
of	O
his	O
two	O
terms	O
,	O
major	O
policy	O
overhauls	O
inherently	O
demand	O
tradeoffs	O
.	O
and	O
president-elect	O
donald	PERS
trump	PERS
's	O
pledge	O
to	O
repeal	O
(	O
or	O
significantly	O
dismantle	O
)	O
obamacare	O
is	O
no	O
different	O
.	O
in	O
fact	O
,	O
it	O
's	O
already	O
having	O
an	O
effect	O
on	O
one	O
of	O
his	O
relatives	O
'	O
business	O
:	O
oscar	PERS
health	PERS
,	O
the	O
app-oriented	O
individual	O
insurance	O
company	O
that	O
was	O
co-founded	O
by	O
joshua	PERS
kushner	PERS
,	O
brother	O
of	O
