special	O
reports	O
library	O
aerospace	O
aerospace	O
corporate	ORG
aviation	ORG
portal	O
high	O
flying	O
:	O
the	O
ft	O
guide	O
to	O
corporate	ORG
aviation	ORG
defence	O
defence	O
september	O
2011	O
(	O
pdf	O
)	O
satellite	ORG
communications	ORG
business	O
management	O
50	O
top	O
business	O
ideas	O
50	O
leading	O
business	O
pioneers	O
50	O
leading	O
business	O
pioneers	O
march	O
2015	O
(	O
pdf	O
)	O
boldness	O
in	O
business	O
the	O
business	O
of	O
consulting	O
the	O
business	O
of	O
marketing	O
business	O
turnrounds	O
co-operatives	O
&	O
employee-owned	O
businesses	O
corporate	O
longevity	O
creativity	O
and	O
business	O
cyber	O
security	O
digital	O
&	O
social	O
media	O
marketing	O
disruption	O
and	O
technology	O
engineering	O
the	O
future	O
family	ORG
office	ORG
ft	O
general	O
counsel	O
ft	O
general	O
counsel	O
2016	O
(	O
pdf	O
)	O
the	O
future	O
of	O
business	O
data	O
the	O
future	O
of	O
the	O
company	O
inventions	O
and	O
patents	O
investing	O
in	O
young	O
people	O
innovative	O
lawyers	O
:	O
asia-pacific	LOC
innovative	O
lawyers	O
:	O
europe	LOC
innovative	O
lawyers	O
:	O
north	O
america	LOC
mid-market	O
companies	O
the	O
new	O
world	O
of	O
work	O
plc	O
awards	O
private	O
business	O
the	O
queen	O
’	O
s	O
awards	O
for	O
enterprise	O
responsible	O
business	O
risk	O
management	O
risk	O
management	O
:	O
people	O
november	O
2016	O
(	O
pdf	O
)	O
risk	O
management	O
:	O
technology	O
october	O
2016	O
(	O
pdf	O
)	O
risk	O
management	O
:	O
property	O
may	O
2016	O
(	O
pdf	O
)	O
risk	O
management	O
:	O
people	O
april	O
2013	O
(	O
pdf	O
)	O
risk	O
management	O
:	O
insurance	O
2011	O
(	O
pdf	O
)	O
risk	O
management	O
:	O
finance	O
2011	O
(	O
pdf	O
)	O
sustainable	O
business	O
:	O
green	O
economy	O
sustainable	O
business	O
:	O
green	O
technology	O
sustainable	O
business	O
:	O
development	ORG
technology	O
leaders	O
tomorrow	O
’	O
s	O
global	O
business	O
understanding	O
entrepreneurs	O
understanding	O
risk	O
urban	O
ingenuity	O
women	O
in	O
business	O
women	O
in	O
business	O
:	O
emerging	O
markets	O
the	O
connected	O
business	O
the	O
connected	O
business	O
hub	O
mobile	O
technology	O
mobile	O
technology	O
february	O
2016	O
(	O
pdf	O
)	O
understanding	O
cloud	O
computing	O
the	O
connected	O
workplace	O
culture	O
&	O
sport	O
the	O
business	O
of	O
african	ORG
art	ORG
and	O
design	ORG
chess	O
emerging	O
voices	O
the	O
business	O
of	O
football	O
the	O
business	O
of	O
formula	O
one	O
the	O
business	O
of	O
tennis	O
ft	O
formula	O
one	O
golf	O
london	LOC
2012	O
olympic	O
games	O
&	O
legacy	O
polo	O
the	O
business	O
of	O
rugby	ORG
union	ORG
sport	O
&	O
development	ORG
education	O
education	O
in	O
the	O
arab	O
world	O
european	O
business	O
schools	O
executive	O
mba	O
executive	O
education	O
financial	O
training	O
the	O
future	O
of	O
the	O
university	O
guide	O
to	O
schools	O
innovations	O
in	O
education	O
innovative	O
law	O
schools	O
masters	O
in	O
management	O
mba	O
online	O
learning	O
top	O
schools	O
top	O
1000	O
schools	O
2011	O
(	O
pdf	O
)	O
working	O
with	O
schools	O
2010	O
(	O
pdf	O
)	O
independent	O
schools	O
2010	O
(	O
pdf	O
)	O
energy	O
canadian	ORG
energy	ORG
commodities	O
energy	O
european	ORG
energy	ORG
gas	O
industry	O
innovation	ORG
in	O
energy	O
mexico	ORG
energy	ORG
modern	ORG
energy	ORG
north	ORG
american	ORG
energy	ORG
oil	O
industry	O
oil	O
&	O
gas	O
2012	O
(	O
pdf	O
)	O
oil	O
&	O
gas	O
2011	O
(	O
pdf	O
)	O
working	O
in	O
global	ORG
energy	ORG
environment	O
business	O
and	O
food	O
sustainability	O
2010	O
(	O
pdf	O
)	O
business	O
and	O
the	O
environment	O
2011	O
(	O
pdf	O
)	O
the	O
business	O
of	O
global	O
food	O
security	O
climate	O
change	O
insight	O
-	O
durban	O
2011	O
(	O
pdf	O
)	O
environment	O
&	O
intellectual	O
property	O
2010	O
(	O
pdf	O
)	O
the	O
future	O
of	O
cities	O
the	O
future	O
of	O
the	O
food	O
industry	O
green	O
innovation	ORG
&	ORG
design	ORG
2010	O
(	O
pdf	O
)	O
managing	O
climate	O
change	O
recovering	O
from	O
natural	O
disaster	O
sustainable	O
development	ORG
urban	O
ingenuity	O
urban	O
resilience	O
water	O
&	O
waste	O
management	O
2010	O
(	O
pdf	O
)	O
financial	ORG
services	ORG
banking	O
and	O
society	O
2010	O
(	O
pdf	O
)	O
debt	ORG
capital	ORG
markets	ORG
deals	O
&	O
dealmakers	O
2012	O
derivatives	O
nov	O
2011	O
(	O
pdf	O
)	O
derivatives	O
may	O
2011	O
(	O
pdf	O
)	O
equity	ORG
capital	ORG
markets	ORG
2010	O
(	O
pdf	O
)	O
exchanges	O
,	O
trading	O
&	O
clearing	O
financial	ORG
markets	ORG
foreign	O
exchange	O
ft	O
400	O
top	O
financial	O
advisers	O
ft	O
100	O
women	O
financial	O
advisers	O
the	O
future	O
of	O
development	ORG
banks	ORG
2012	O
(	O
pdf	O
)	O
investment	ORG
toolkit	ORG
islamic	ORG
finance	ORG
dec	O
2011	O
(	O
pdf	O
)	O
islamic	ORG
finance	ORG
may	O
2011	O
(	O
pdf	O
)	O
the	O
future	O
of	O
islamic	ORG
finance	ORG
dec	O
2010	O
(	O
pdf	O
)	O
islamic	ORG
finance	ORG
may	O
2010	O
(	O
pdf	O
)	O
private	O
banking	O
ft	O
300	O
top	O
registered	O
investment	O
advisers	O
top	O
401	O
retirement	O
investment	O
advisers	O
the	O
future	O
of	O
banking	O
the	O
future	O
of	O
retirement	O
the	O
future	O
of	O
the	O
renminbi	O
structured	O
products	O
2010	O
(	O
pdf	O
)	O
sustainable	O
banking	ORG
&	ORG
finance	ORG
2012	O
(	O
pdf	O
)	O
sustainable	O
banking	ORG
&	ORG
finance	ORG
2011	O
(	O
pdf	O
)	O
sustainable	O
banking	O
2010	O
(	O
pdf	O
)	O
trading	O
insight	O
transaction	ORG
services	ORG
2011	O
(	O
pdf	O
)	O
world	O
’	O
s	O
top	O
analysts	O
fund	O
management	O
asset	O
manager	O
intentions	O
asset	O
servicing	O
debt	ORG
capital	ORG
markets	ORG
global	O
alternative	O
survey	O
hedge	O
fund	O
strategies	O
hedge	O
fund	O
survey	O
index	O
investing	O
investing	O
for	O
retirement	O
investing	O
in	O
commodities	O
investing	O
in	O
fixed	O
income	O
investing	O
in	O
foreign	O
exchange	O
managed	O
futures	O
otc	O
derivatives	O
prime	O
broking	O
responsible	O
investing	O
retail	O
funds	O
industry	O
risk	O
management	O
structured	O
products	O
us	ORG
mutual	ORG
funds	ORG
industry	O
women	O
in	O
asset	O
management	O
healthcare	O
combating	O
aids	O
2012	O
(	O
pdf	O
)	O
combating	O
aids	O
2011	O
(	O
pdf	O
)	O
combating	O
aids	O
2010	O
(	O
pdf	O
)	O
combating	O
cancer	O
combating	O
diabetes	O
combating	O
hepatitis	O
c	O
combating	O
neglected	O
diseases	O
combating	O
malaria	O
combating	O
rare	O
diseases	O
combating	O
rare	O
diseases	O
september	O
2015	O
(	O
pdf	O
)	O
combating	O
tuberculosis	O
digital	ORG
innovation	ORG
eyecare	O
eyecare	O
2016	O
(	O
pdf	O
)	O
health	O
at	O
work	O
health	O
at	O
work	O
2016	O
(	O
pdf	O
)	O
health	O
:	O
devices	O
and	O
diagnostics	O
health	O
:	O
emerging	O
markets	O
health	O
:	O
global	ORG
policy	ORG
health	O
and	O
the	O
workplace	O
innovation	ORG
in	O
healthcare	O
innovation	ORG
in	O
healthcare	O
2016	O
(	O
pdf	O
)	O
life	O
sciences	O
industry	O
2011	O
(	O
pdf	O
)	O
life	O
sciences	O
industry	O
2010	O
(	O
pdf	O
)	O
maternal	O
and	O
child	O
health	O
maternal	O
and	O
child	O
health	O
2016	O
(	O
pdf	O
)	O
sexual	O
and	O
reproductive	O
health	O
sleep	O
sustainable	O
healthcare	O
transatlantic	ORG
healthcare	ORG
vaccines	O
luxury	ORG
&	O
brands	O
business	O
of	O
luxury	ORG
the	O
business	O
of	O
african	ORG
luxury	ORG
the	O
business	O
of	O
rum	O
the	O
business	O
of	O
tequila	O
the	O
business	O
of	O
whisky	O
buying	O
&	O
investing	O
in	O
wine	O
ft	O
wine	O
ft	O
wine	O
:	O
bordeaux	O
(	O
pdf	O
)	O
ft	O
wine	O
july	O
2015	O
(	O
pdf	O
)	O
global	ORG
brands	ORG
latin	ORG
american	ORG
brands	O
watches	O
&	O
jewellery	O
ft	ORG
wealth	ORG
yachts	O
&	O
marinas	O
property	O
building	O
the	O
future	O
central	O
&	O
eastern	O
europe	LOC
:	O
property	O
ft	O
property	O
global	O
property	O
insight	O
property	O
:	O
asia	LOC
and	O
north	O
america	LOC
property	O
:	O
europe	LOC
and	O
the	O
middle	LOC
east	LOC
recruitment	O
architects	O
of	O
meritocracy	O
architects	O
of	O
meritocracy	O
2016	O
(	O
pdf	O
)	O
best	O
places	O
to	O
work	O
best	O
places	O
to	O
work	O
2015	O
(	O
pdf	O
)	O
employment	O
:	O
global	O
best	O
practice	O
ethnicity	O
&	O
inclusion	O
in	O
the	O
workplace	O
executive	O
diversity	O
the	O
work	O
revolution	O
the	O
work	O
revolution	O
2016	O
(	O
pdf	O
)	O
women	O
in	O
the	O
workplace	O
working	O
in	O
accountancy	O
working	O
in	O
international	O
banking	O
transport	O
fleet	O
management	O
the	O
future	O
of	O
the	O
car	O
the	O
future	O
of	O
transport	O
innovation	ORG
in	O
transport	O
rail	O
and	O
metro	O
rail	O
&	O
transport	O
2011	O
(	O
pdf	O
)	O
rail	O
industry	O
2010	O
(	O
pdf	O
)	O
travel	O
destination	ORG
:	O
monaco	LOC
2012	O
destination	ORG
:	O
paris	LOC
2012	O
destination	ORG
:	O
south	LOC
africa	LOC
2011	O
global	O
traveller	O
nov	O
2011	O
fund	O
management	O
asset	O
manager	O
intentions	O
asset	O
servicing	O
debt	ORG
capital	ORG
markets	ORG
global	O
alternative	O
survey	O
hedge	O
fund	O
strategies	O
hedge	O
fund	O
survey	O
index	O
investing	O
investing	O
for	O
retirement	O
investing	O
in	O
commodities	O
investing	O
in	O
fixed	O
income	O
investing	O
in	O
foreign	O
exchange	O
managed	O
futures	O
otc	O
derivatives	O
prime	O
broking	O
responsible	O
investing	O
retail	O
funds	O
industry	O
risk	O
management	O
structured	O
products	O
us	ORG
mutual	ORG
funds	ORG
industry	O
women	O
in	O
asset	O
management	O
africa	LOC
the	O
business	O
of	O
african	ORG
art	ORG
&	ORG
design	ORG
the	O
business	O
of	O
african	ORG
luxury	ORG
the	O
new	O
africa	LOC
africa	LOC
:	O
banking	ORG
&	ORG
finance	ORG
africa	LOC
:	O
oil	O
&	O
gas	O
2010	O
(	O
pdf	O
)	O
africa-china	ORG
trade	ORG
2010	O
(	O
pdf	O
)	O
africa	LOC
&	O
the	O
green	O
economy	O
african	ORG
entrepreneurs	ORG
african	ORG
farming	ORG
gabon	LOC
investing	O
in	O
ivory	LOC
coast	LOC
investing	O
in	O
kenya	LOC
kenya	LOC
at	O
50	O
doing	O
business	O
in	O
kenya	LOC
2010	O
(	O
pdf	O
)	O
investing	O
in	O
liberia	LOC
investing	O
in	O
liberia	LOC
april	O
2016	O
(	O
pdf	O
)	O
doing	O
business	O
in	O
liberia	LOC
lesotho	LOC
investing	O
in	O
mauritania	LOC
investing	O
in	O
mauritius	LOC
mauritius	LOC
:	O
world	ORG
financial	ORG
centre	ORG
mauritius	LOC
:	O
world	ORG
financial	ORG
centre	ORG
2016	O
(	O
pdf	O
)	O
mauritius	LOC
doing	O
business	O
in	O
mauritius	LOC
morocco	LOC
:	O
industry	O
and	O
services	O
morocco	LOC
:	O
industry	O
and	O
services	O
march	O
2016	O
(	O
pdf	O
)	O
investing	O
in	O
nigeria	LOC
nigeria	LOC
:	O
energy	O
nigeria	LOC
:	O
oil	O
&	O
gas	O
nigeria	LOC
at	O
50	O
(	O
pdf	O
)	O
investing	O
in	O
rwanda	LOC
doing	O
business	O
in	O
rwanda	LOC
south	LOC
africa	LOC
and	O
africa	LOC
south	LOC
africa	LOC
2010	O
(	O
pdf	O
)	O
southern	LOC
africa	LOC
mining	O
south	LOC
africa	LOC
infrastructure	O
2010	O
(	O
pdf	O
)	O
south	ORG
africa	ORG
finance	ORG
&	ORG
investment	ORG
2010	O
(	O
pdf	O
)	O
south	ORG
african	ORG
power	ORG
&	ORG
energy	ORG
2010	O
(	O
pdf	O
)	O
investing	O
in	O
tanzania	LOC
investing	O
in	O
tanzania	LOC
2016	O
(	O
pdf	O
)	O
doing	O
business	O
in	O
tanzania	LOC
americas	LOC
the	O
new	LOC
argentina	LOC
the	O
new	LOC
argentina	LOC
september	O
2016	O
(	O
pdf	O
)	O
investing	O
in	O
bogotá	O
brazil	LOC
brazil	LOC
:	O
competitive	O
profile	O
modern	ORG
brazil	ORG
brazil	LOC
:	O
innovation	ORG
,	O
research	O
&	O
development	ORG
brazil	LOC
:	O
infrastructure	O
investing	O
in	O
brazil	LOC
brazil	ORG
capital	ORG
markets	ORG
doing	O
business	O
in	O
brazil	LOC
’	O
s	O
northeast	O
brazil	LOC
&	O
the	O
us	LOC
canadian	ORG
energy	ORG
doing	O
business	O
in	O
chicago	LOC
doing	O
business	O
in	O
chicago	LOC
2016	O
(	O
pdf	O
)	O
investing	O
in	O
chile	LOC
energy	O
in	O
the	O
americas	LOC
the	O
new	O
colombia	LOC
investing	O
in	O
colombia	LOC
investing	O
in	O
cuba	LOC
investing	O
in	O
haiti	LOC
latin	LOC
america	LOC
:	O
social	O
enterprise	O
&	O
philanthropy	O
latin	ORG
american	ORG
capital	ORG
markets	ORG
doing	O
business	O
in	O
mendoza	O
modern	ORG
mexico	ORG
mexico	LOC
infrastructure	O
mexico	LOC
the	O
future	O
of	O
nafta	O
investing	O
in	O
the	O
pacific	O
alliance	O
countries	O
investing	O
in	O
peru	LOC
2011	O
(	O
pdf	O
)	O
the	O
new	O
trade	O
routes	O
:	O
brazil	LOC
the	O
new	O
trade	O
routes	O
:	O
brazil	LOC
-	O
china	LOC
(	O
pdf	O
)	O
the	O
new	O
trade	O
routes	O
:	O
brazil	LOC
-	O
uk	LOC
the	O
new	O
trade	O
routes	O
:	O
latin	LOC
america	LOC
(	O
pdf	O
)	O
the	O
new	O
trade	O
routes	O
:	O
mexico	LOC
the	O
new	O
trade	O
routes	O
:	O
pacific	O
alliance	O
the	O
us	LOC
president	O
’	O
s	O
new	O
challenge	O
(	O
2013	O
)	O
asia-pacific	LOC
investing	O
in	O
chengdu	O
doing	O
business	O
in	O
china	LOC
china	LOC
doing	O
business	O
in	O
hong	LOC
kong	LOC
indian	O
banking	ORG
&	ORG
finance	ORG
india	LOC
&	O
globalisation	O
japan	LOC
and	O
the	O
world	O
japan	LOC
japan	LOC
2013	O
(	O
pdf	O
)	O
japan	LOC
:	O
banking	ORG
&	ORG
finance	ORG
japan	LOC
:	O
technology	O
&	O
innovation	ORG
investing	O
in	O
japan	LOC
the	O
new	O
trade	O
routes	O
:	O
pacific	O
the	O
new	O
trade	O
routes	O
:	O
philippines	LOC
the	O
new	O
trade	O
routes	O
:	O
silk	O
road	O
corridor	O
investing	O
in	O
south	LOC
korea	LOC
europe	LOC
doing	O
business	O
in	O
austria	LOC
doing	O
business	O
in	O
austria	LOC
2016	O
(	O
pdf	O
)	O
azerbaijan	LOC
modern	ORG
barcelona	ORG
doing	O
business	O
in	O
the	O
basque	O
country	O
investing	O
in	O
bulgaria	LOC
investing	O
in	O
bulgaria	LOC
2016	O
(	O
pdf	O
)	O
bulgaria	LOC
investing	O
in	O
central	O
&	O
eastern	O
europe	LOC
central	O
&	O
eastern	O
europe	LOC
:	O
energy	O
and	O
infrastructure	O
central	O
&	O
eastern	O
europe	LOC
:	O
technology	O
&	O
innovation	ORG
central	O
&	O
eastern	O
europe	LOC
:	O
automotive	O
&	O
manufacturing	O
central	O
&	O
eastern	O
europe	LOC
:	O
banking	ORG
&	ORG
finance	ORG
central	O
&	O
eastern	O
europe	LOC
:	O
emerging	O
industries	O
central	O
&	O
eastern	O
europe	LOC
:	O
property	O
the	O
connected	O
europe	LOC
investing	O
in	O
the	O
czech	LOC
republic	LOC
finland	LOC
business	O
locations	O
in	O
france	LOC
frankfurt	LOC
as	O
a	O
financial	ORG
centre	ORG
investing	O
in	O
germany	LOC
doing	O
business	O
in	O
greece	LOC
european	O
financial	O
centres	O
the	O
future	O
of	O
the	O
european	LOC
union	LOC
istanbul	LOC
:	O
business	O
&	O
finance	O
doing	O
business	O
in	O
lyon	LOC
macedonia	LOC
doing	O
business	O
in	O
nice	O
cote	O
d	O
’	O
azur	O
doing	O
business	O
in	O
north	O
rhine-westphalia	O
investing	O
in	O
poland	LOC
poland	LOC
poland	LOC
:	O
30	O
years	O
after	O
solidarity	O
investing	O
in	O
portugal	LOC
investing	O
in	O
portugal	LOC
2015	O
(	O
pdf	O
)	O
doing	O
business	O
in	O
portugal	LOC
portugal	LOC
2010	O
investing	O
in	O
russia	LOC
new	O
trade	O
routes	O
:	O
russia	LOC
serbia	LOC
spain	LOC
:	O
business	O
&	O
innovation	ORG
spain	LOC
:	O
business	O
&	O
innovation	ORG
2016	O
(	O
pdf	O
)	O
investing	O
in	O
spain	LOC
spain	LOC
the	O
future	O
of	O
spanish	O
businesses	O
investing	O
in	O
turkey	LOC
the	O
new	O
trade	O
routes	O
:	O
turkey	LOC
turkey	LOC
and	O
the	O
world	O
turkey	LOC
ukraine	LOC
vienna	LOC
as	O
a	O
business	O
location	O
vienna	LOC
as	O
a	O
financial	ORG
centre	ORG
doing	O
business	O
in	O
wallonia	O
warsaw	LOC
as	O
a	O
financial	ORG
centre	ORG
middle	LOC
east	LOC
women	O
in	O
the	O
arab	ORG
awakening	ORG
arab	O
world	O
:	O
banking	O
and	O
finance	O
arab	ORG
banking	ORG
and	O
finance	O
october	O
2014	O
(	O
pdf	O
)	O
new	O
trade	O
routes	O
:	O
the	O
arab	O
world	O
doing	O
business	O
in	O
the	O
arab	O
world	O
investing	O
in	O
the	O
arab	O
world	O
destination	ORG
dubai	ORG
destination	ORG
uae	ORG
egypt	LOC
israel	LOC
:	O
innovation	ORG
and	O
technology	O
kurdistan	O
:	O
oil	O
&	O
gas	O
kuwait	LOC
doing	O
business	O
in	O
morocco	LOC
doing	O
business	O
in	O
morocco	LOC
2015	O
(	O
pdf	O
)	O
new	O
trade	O
routes	O
:	O
arab	O
world	O
new	O
trade	O
routes	O
:	O
middle	LOC
east	LOC
-	O
africa	LOC
qatar	LOC
year	O
in	O
the	O
arab	O
world	O
uk	LOC
&	O
ireland	LOC
blueprint	O
for	O
british	O
business	O
britain	LOC
after	O
brexit	O
guernsey	O
as	O
a	O
financial	ORG
centre	ORG
gibraltar	O
as	O
a	O
financial	ORG
centre	ORG
2010	O
investing	O
in	O
britain	LOC
doing	O
business	O
in	O
birmingham	LOC
ireland	ORG
financial	ORG
services	ORG
doing	O
business	O
in	O
the	O
isle	O
of	O
man	O
doing	O
business	O
in	O
jersey	O
doing	O
business	O
in	O
newport	O
2010	O
doing	O
business	O
in	O
norfolk	O
2010	O
destination	ORG
:	O
north	O
of	O
england	LOC
doing	O
business	O
in	O
the	O
north	O
of	O
england	LOC
london	LOC
and	O
the	O
world	O
london	LOC
’	O
s	O
summer	O
legacy	O
business	O
guide	O
to	O
manchester	LOC
north-west	O
england	LOC
:	O
creative	ORG
&	ORG
digital	ORG
industries	ORG
2010	O
business	O
guide	O
to	O
sunderland	O
the	O
uk	LOC
’	O
s	O
entrepreneurs	O
the	O
world	O
the	O
ft	O
’	O
s	O
year	O
in	O
finance	O
g7	O
:	O
japan	LOC
g8	O
summit	O
g20	O
:	O
turkey	LOC
and	O
the	O
world	O
g20	O
:	O
mexico	LOC
and	O
the	O
world	O
g20	O
:	O
south	LOC
korea	LOC
guide	O
to	O
davos	LOC
innovation	ORG
and	O
the	O
economy	O
the	O
millennial	O
generation	O
the	O
mint	O
economies	O
urban	O
demographics	O
the	O
world	O
world	O
economy	O
world	O
retailing	O
reaction	O
to	O
eu	LOC
court	O
ruling	O
on	O
headscarves	O
the	O
european	LOC
union	LOC
's	O
highest	O
court	O
ruled	O
on	O
tuesday	O
that	O
firms	O
may	O
ban	O
staff	O
from	O
wearing	O
islamic	O
headscarves	O
and	O
other	O
visible	O
religious	O
symbols	O
under	O
certain	O
conditions	O
.	O
[	O
l5n1gr1ym	O
]	O
here	O
are	O
some	O
reactions	O
to	O
the	O
judgment	O
:	O
francois	PERS
fillon	PERS
,	O
french	O
conservative	O
presidential	O
candidate	O
''	O
the	O
judgment	O
...	O
defends	O
the	O
secular	O
nature	O
of	O
society	O
and	O
puts	O
a	O
stop	O
to	O
the	O
pushing	O
of	O
religious	O
interests	O
...	O
it	O
is	O
a	O
huge	O
relief	O
,	O
not	O
only	O
to	O
thousands	O
of	O
companies	O
but	O
also	O
their	O
employees	O
.	O
this	O
judgment	O
will	O
surely	O
contribute	O
to	O
social	O
cohesion	O
and	O
peace	O
throughout	O
europe	LOC
,	O
and	O
notably	O
france	LOC
.	O
''	O
chief	O
rabbi	O
pinchas	PERS
goldschmidt	PERS
,	O
president	O
of	O
the	O
conference	O
of	O
european	O
rabbis	O
:	O
''	O
with	O
the	O
rise	O
of	O
racially	O
motivated	O
incidents	O
and	O
today	O
’	O
s	O
decision	O
,	O
europe	LOC
is	O
sending	O
a	O
clear	O
message	O
-	O
its	O
faith	O
communities	O
are	O
no	O
longer	O
welcome	O
.	O
political	O
leaders	O
need	O
to	O
act	O
to	O
ensure	O
that	O
europe	LOC
does	O
not	O
isolate	O
religious	O
minorities	O
and	O
remains	O
a	O
diverse	O
and	O
open	O
continent	O
.	O
''	O
john	PERS
dalhuisen	PERS
,	O
amnesty	ORG
international	ORG
:	O
''	O
today	O
's	O
disappointing	O
rulings	O
...	O
give	O
greater	O
leeway	O
to	O
employers	O
to	O
discriminate	O
against	O
women	O
--	O
and	O
men	O
--	O
on	O
the	O
grounds	O
of	O
religious	O
belief	O
.	O
at	O
a	O
time	O
when	O
identity	O
and	O
appearance	O
have	O
become	O
a	O
political	O
battleground	O
,	O
people	O
need	O
more	O
protection	O
against	O
prejudice	O
,	O
not	O
less	O
.	O
''	O
g4s	O
,	O
company	O
whose	O
ban	O
in	O
belgium	LOC
was	O
upheld	O
by	O
the	O
ecj	ORG
:	O
''	O
in	O
many	O
countries	O
such	O
as	O
the	O
uk	LOC
where	O
there	O
is	O
no	O
strong	O
tradition	O
of	O
religious	O
and	O
political	O
neutrality	O
,	O
g4s	O
permits	O
the	O
wearing	O
of	O
religious	O
dress	O
such	O
as	O
islamic	O
headscarves	O
.	O
''	O
amel	PERS
yacef	PERS
,	O
chair	O
of	O
the	O
european	ORG
network	ORG
against	O
racism	O
:	O
''	O
it	O
effectively	O
bars	O
all	O
muslim	O
women	O
wearing	O
the	O
headscarf	O
from	O
the	O
workplace	O
.	O
this	O
is	O
nothing	O
short	O
of	O
a	O
muslim	O
ban	O
applied	O
only	O
to	O
women	O
in	O
private	O
employment	O
.	O
``	O
muslim	O
women	O
already	O
experience	O
significant	O
obstacles	O
in	O
finding	O
and	O
keeping	O
a	O
job	O
and	O
this	O
decision	O
will	O
only	O
make	O
matters	O
worse	O
,	O
giving	O
employers	O
a	O
license	O
to	O
discriminate	O
.	O
''	O
jonathan	PERS
chamberlain	PERS
,	O
at	O
british	O
law	O
firm	O
gowling	ORG
wlg	ORG
:	O
''	O
the	O
decision	O
brings	O
eu	LOC
law	O
into	O
line	O
with	O
what	O
has	O
been	O
the	O
uk	LOC
's	O
approach	O
for	O
some	O
years	O
.	O
for	O
example	O
,	O
it	O
's	O
fine	O
for	O
employers	O
to	O
have	O
a	O
dress	O
code	O
but	O
it	O
needs	O
to	O
be	O
applied	O
with	O
some	O
sensitivity	O
and	O
flexibility	O
to	O
take	O
account	O
of	O
religious	O
beliefs	O
.	O
what	O
is	O
almost	O
certainly	O
never	O
ok	O
is	O
for	O
an	O
employer	O
to	O
tell	O
an	O
employee	O
to	O
stop	O
wearing	O
a	O
religious	O
symbol	O
because	O
a	O
particular	O
customer	O
has	O
asked	O
for	O
it	O
.	O
''	O
carla	PERS
amina	PERS
baghajati	PERS
,	O
austrian	O
islamic	O
body	O
iggo	O
:	O
''	O
participation	O
in	O
the	O
workplace	O
is	O
a	O
key	O
to	O
social	O
cohesion	O
,	O
for	O
women	O
’	O
s	O
right	O
to	O
work	O
and	O
their	O
inclusion	O
in	O
society	O
.	O
if	O
this	O
ruling	O
is	O
taken	O
by	O
employers	O
as	O
an	O
invitation	O
to	O
take	O
restrictive	O
action	O
,	O
that	O
would	O
be	O
a	O
serious	O
consequence	O
for	O
muslim	O
women	O
who	O
want	O
to	O
wear	O
a	O
headscarf	O
because	O
they	O
would	O
be	O
shut	O
out	O
.	O
''	O
maryam	PERS
hmadoun	PERS
,	O
open	ORG
society	ORG
justice	O
initiative	O
:	O
''	O
this	O
disappointing	O
ruling	O
weakens	O
the	O
guarantee	O
of	O
equality	O
that	O
is	O
at	O
the	O
heart	O
of	O
the	O
eu	LOC
’	O
s	O
anti-discrimination	O
directive	O
.	O
in	O
many	O
member	O
states	O
,	O
national	O
laws	O
will	O
still	O
recognize	O
that	O
banning	O
religious	O
headscarves	O
at	O
work	O
is	O
discrimination	O
.	O
but	O
in	O
places	O
where	O
national	O
law	O
is	O
weak	O
,	O
this	O
ruling	O
will	O
exclude	O
many	O
muslim	O
women	O
from	O
the	O
workplace	O
.	O
european	LOC
union	LOC
lawmakers	O
must	O
now	O
act	O
quickly	O
to	O
make	O
it	O
clear	O
that	O
the	O
scope	O
of	O
this	O
directive	O
includes	O
direct	O
discrimination	O
on	O
the	O
basis	O
of	O
religious	O
dress	O
.	O
''	O
forum	ORG
of	ORG
european	ORG
muslim	ORG
youth	ORG
and	ORG
student	ORG
organisations	ORG
:	O
''	O
muslim	O
women	O
already	O
face	O
significant	O
obstacles	O
in	O
getting	O
an	O
education	O
or	O
finding	O
and	O
keeping	O
a	O
job	O
and	O
this	O
decision	O
will	O
only	O
make	O
matters	O
worse	O
,	O
giving	O
employers	O
a	O
license	O
to	O
discriminate	O
.	O
in	O
belgium	LOC
,	O
for	O
instance	O
,	O
44	O
percent	O
of	O
employers	O
agree	O
that	O
wearing	O
a	O
headscarf	O
can	O
negatively	O
influence	O
the	O
selection	O
of	O
candidates	O
.	O
in	O
this	O
case	O
,	O
this	O
judgment	O
forces	O
muslim	O
women	O
who	O
wear	O
a	O
headscarf	O
,	O
sikhs	O
wearing	O
a	O
turban	O
and	O
jews	O
wearing	O
a	O
kippa	O
to	O
choose	O
between	O
their	O
religious	O
expression	O
,	O
which	O
is	O
a	O
fundamental	O
right	O
,	O
and	O
their	O
right	O
to	O
access	O
the	O
labor	O
market	O
.	O
''	O
(	O
reporting	O
by	O
waverly	PERS
colville	PERS
;	O
editing	O
by	O
alastair	PERS
macdonald	PERS
and	O
gareth	PERS
jones	PERS
)	O
the	O
world	O
’	O
s	O
most	O
powerful	O
women	O
:	O
march	O
15	O
the	O
european	ORG
court	ORG
of	ORG
justice	ORG
ruled	O
yesterday	O
that	O
it	O
's	O
legal	O
for	O
private	O
employers	O
in	O
the	O
eu	LOC
to	O
ban	O
women	O
's	O
headscarves	O
from	O
the	O
workplace	O
.	O
the	O
decision	O
stemmed	O
from	O
two	O
cases	O
in	O
france	LOC
and	O
belgium	LOC
where	O
women	O
were	O
dismissed	O
from	O
their	O
jobs	O
for	O
wearing	O
headscarves	O
to	O
work	O
;	O
one	O
woman	O
was	O
fired	O
for	O
violating	O
her	O
company	O
's	O
informal	O
neutral	O
dress	O
policy	O
,	O
the	O
other	O
was	O
asked	O
to	O
leave	O
after	O
a	O
customer	O
complained	O
about	O
her	O
head	O
covering	O
.	O
the	O
ecj	ORG
ruling	O
did	O
not	O
issue	O
an	O
outright	O
ban	O
against	O
headscarves	O
but	O
said	O
employers	O
could	O
prohibit	O
them	O
as	O
part	O
of	O
a	O
broader	O
effort	O
maintain	O
an	O
ideologically	O
neutral	O
workplace	O
that	O
disallows	O
symbols	O
of	O
all	O
religions	O
.	O
the	O
verdict	O
conflicts	O
with	O
a	O
2015	O
u.s.	ORG
supreme	ORG
court	ORG
decision	O
regarding	O
workplace	O
discrimination	O
.	O
the	O
u.s.	LOC
court	O
ruled	O
8-1	O
in	O
favor	O
of	O
samantha	PERS
elauf	PERS
,	O
a	O
muslim	O
woman	O
who	O
filed	O
suit	O
against	O
clothing	O
retailer	O
abercrombie	ORG
&	ORG
fitch	ORG
after	O
she	O
was	O
denied	O
a	O
job	O
for	O
wearing	O
a	O
headscarf	O
,	O
on	O
the	O
grounds	O
that	O
an	O
employer	O
ca	O
n't	O
consider	O
an	O
applicant	O
’	O
s	O
religious	O
practice	O
--	O
confirmed	O
or	O
otherwise	O
--	O
in	O
employment	O
decisions	O
.	O
europe	LOC
's	O
far-right	O
politicians	O
were	O
quick	O
to	O
cheer	O
yesterday	O
's	O
ecj	ORG
decision	O
,	O
which	O
could	O
fuel	O
the	O
anti-islamic	O
rhetoric	O
of	O
populist	O
presidential	O
candidates	O
like	O
france	LOC
's	O
marine	O
le	PERS
pen	PERS
and	O
the	LOC
netherlands	LOC
'	O
geert	PERS
wilders	PERS
.	O
le	PERS
pen	PERS
,	O
who	O
refused	O
to	O
don	O
a	O
headscarf	O
while	O
visiting	O
lebanon	LOC
last	O
month	O
,	O
has	O
called	O
for	O
an	O
outright	O
ban	O
on	O
all	O
religious	O
symbols	O
in	O
public	O
in	O
france	LOC
.	O
john	PERS
dalhuisen	PERS
of	O
amnesty	ORG
international	ORG
,	O
meanwhile	O
,	O
said	O
yesterday	O
's	O
ruling	O
will	O
``	O
give	O
greater	O
leeway	O
to	O
employers	O
to	O
discriminate	O
.	O
''	O
``	O
at	O
a	O
time	O
when	O
identity	O
and	O
appearance	O
has	O
become	O
a	O
political	O
battleground	O
,	O
''	O
dalhuisen	PERS
said	O
,	O
``	O
people	O
need	O
more	O
protection	O
against	O
prejudice	O
,	O
not	O
less	O
.	O
''	O
the	O
ecj	ORG
's	O
call	O
for	O
a	O
uniform	O
approach	O
to	O
religious	O
symbolism	O
in	O
the	O
workplace	O
seems	O
to	O
be	O
an	O
attempt	O
to	O
tiptoe	O
toward	O
less	O
contentious	O
ground	O
,	O
but	O
early	O
responses	O
to	O
the	O
ruling	O
indicate	O
that	O
finding	O
that	O
territory	O
--	O
where	O
all	O
parties	O
must	O
agree	O
on	O
what	O
'neutral	O
'	O
means	O
--	O
is	O
just	O
as	O
politically	O
charged	O
.	O
@	O
clairezillman	O
europe/middle	O
east/africa	O
[	O
bs-title	O
]	O
punished	O
in	O
parliament	ORG
[	O
/bs-title	O
]	O
[	O
bs-content	O
]	O
the	O
european	ORG
parliament	ORG
has	O
punished	O
the	O
far-right	O
polish	ORG
mep	ORG
who	O
said	O
women	O
must	O
earn	O
less	O
than	O
men	O
because	O
they	O
are	O
weaker	O
,	O
smaller	O
and	O
less	O
intelligent	O
.	O
president	O
antonio	PERS
tajani	PERS
leveled	O
an	O
unprecedented	O
penalty	O
against	O
janusz	PERS
korwin-mikkehe	PERS
for	O
his	O
sexist	O
tirade	O
,	O
stripping	O
him	O
of	O
his	O
daily	O
allowance	O
for	O
30	O
days	O
,	O
suspending	O
him	O
from	O
parliamentary	O
work	O
for	O
10	O
days	O
,	O
and	O
banning	O
him	O
from	O
representing	O
the	O
parliament	ORG
for	O
a	O
year	O
.	O
``	O
by	O
offending	O
all	O
women	O
,	O
the	O
mep	O
displayed	O
contempt	O
for	O
our	O
most	O
fundamental	O
values	O
,	O
''	O
tajani	PERS
said	O
yesterday	O
.	O
[	O
/bs-content	O
]	O
[	O
bs-link	O
link=	O
''	O
https	O
:	O
//www.theguardian.com/world/2017/mar/14/polish-mep-janusz-korwin-mikke-punished-saying-women-less-intelligent-men	O
''	O
source=	O
''	O
guardian	ORG
''	O
]	O
[	O
bs-seperator	O
]	O
[	O
bs-title	O
]	O
family	O
ties	O
[	O
/bs-title	O
]	O
[	O
bs-content	O
]	O
charlotte	PERS
hogg	PERS
,	O
bank	ORG
of	ORG
england	ORG
deputy	O
governor	O
for	O
markets	O
and	O
banking	O
,	O
resigned	O
yesterday	O
after	O
parliament	ORG
's	O
treasury	ORG
committee	O
determined	O
her	O
failure	O
to	O
disclose	O
a	O
potential	O
conflict	O
of	O
interest	O
was	O
``	O
a	O
serious	O
error	O
of	O
judgment	O
.	O
''	O
hogg	PERS
's	O
brother	O
held	O
a	O
senior	O
position	O
at	O
barclays	ORG
during	O
her	O
four-year	O
tenure	O
at	O
the	O
bank	ORG
of	ORG
england	ORG
.	O
her	O
departure	O
comes	O
at	O
a	O
delicate	O
time	O
for	O
the	O
central	ORG
bank	ORG
as	O
brexit	O
negotiations	O
approach	O
,	O
and	O
it	O
's	O
fueling	O
the	O
bank	O
's	O
on-going	O
gender	O
diversity	O
debate	O
.	O
[	O
/bs-content	O
]	O
[	O
bs-link	O
link=	O
''	O
https	O
:	O
//www.wsj.com/articles/boe-deputy-governor-charlotte-hogg-resigns-after-critical-report-1489485813	O
''	O
source=	O
''	O
wall	ORG
street	ORG
journal	ORG
''	O
]	O
[	O
bs-seperator	O
]	O
[	O
bs-title	O
]	O
unfortunate	O
optics	O
[	O
/bs-title	O
]	O
[	O
bs-content	O
]	O
saudi	O
arabia	O
launched	O
a	O
girls	O
'	O
council	O
aiming	O
to	O
improve	O
women	O
's	O
representation	O
in	O
the	O
workforce	O
,	O
but	O
it	O
forgot	O
to	O
include	O
one	O
critical	O
element	O
in	O
the	O
debut	O
:	O
girls	O
themselves	O
.	O
photos	O
of	O
the	O
weekend	O
launch	O
of	O
the	O
qassim	O
girls	O
'	O
council	O
show	O
13	O
men	O
on	O
stage	O
championing	O
the	O
initiative	O
.	O
the	O
women	O
,	O
including	O
princess	O
abir	PERS
bint	PERS
salman	PERS
,	O
chair	O
of	O
the	O
program	O
,	O
were	O
connected	O
via	O
video	O
link	O
from	O
another	O
room	O
.	O
state	O
policy	O
requires	O
gender	O
segregation	O
between	O
unrelated	O
men	O
and	O
women	O
.	O
[	O
/bs-content	O
]	O
[	O
bs-link	O
link=	O
''	O
http	O
:	O
//www.bbc.co.uk/news/world-middle-east-39264349	O
''	O
source=	O
''	O
bbc	ORG
''	O
]	O
the	O
americas	LOC
[	O
bs-title	O
]	O
megyn	O
's	O
mess	O
[	O
/bs-title	O
]	O
[	O
bs-content	O
]	O
after	O
signing	O
off	O
from	O
fox	O
new	O
in	O
january	O
,	O
megyn	PERS
kelly	PERS
appears	O
to	O
be	O
in	O
limbo	O
as	O
she	O
awaits	O
the	O
fall	O
debut	O
of	O
her	O
new	O
show	O
on	O
nbc	ORG
.	O
fox	ORG
news	ORG
says	O
it	O
's	O
already	O
released	O
kelly	O
,	O
but	O
her	O
reps	O
say	O
the	O
terms	O
of	O
her	O
termination	O
are	O
still	O
being	O
negotiated	O
.	O
kelly	O
still	O
does	O
n't	O
have	O
an	O
official	O
start	O
date	O
at	O
nbc	ORG
,	O
nor	O
has	O
the	O
network	O
hired	O
an	O
executive	O
producer	O
for	O
her	O
new	O
show	O
.	O
[	O
/bs-content	O
]	O
[	O
bs-link	O
link=	O
''	O
https	O
:	O
//www.wsj.com/articles/megyn-kellys-messy-exit-from-fox-news-1489526768	O
''	O
source=	O
''	O
wall	ORG
street	ORG
journal	ORG
''	O
]	O
[	O
bs-seperator	O
]	O
[	O
bs-title	O
]	O
no	O
longer	O
essential	O
?	O
[	O
/bs-title	O
]	O
[	O
bs-content	O
]	O
congressional	O
republicans	O
'	O
replacement	O
health	O
care	O
plan	O
will	O
cause	O
14	O
million	O
people	O
to	O
lose	O
healthcare	O
next	O
year	O
,	O
defund	O
planned	ORG
parenthood	ORG
,	O
and	O
,	O
in	O
doing	O
so	O
,	O
lead	O
to	O
thousands	O
of	O
births	O
,	O
according	O
to	O
a	O
new	O
report	O
from	O
the	O
congressional	ORG
budget	ORG
office	ORG
.	O
beyond	O
those	O
top-line	O
numbers	O
,	O
republicans	O
'	O
effort	O
to	O
revamp	O
obamacare	O
could	O
also	O
mean	O
rolling	O
back	O
the	O
law	O
's	O
game-changing	O
approach	O
to	O
women	O
's	O
health	O
care	O
,	O
such	O
as	O
requiring	O
every	O
insurance	O
plan	O
to	O
cover	O
essential	O
benefits	O
like	O
contraception	O
and	O
maternity	O
care	O
.	O
[	O
/bs-content	O
]	O
[	O
bs-link	O
link=	O
''	O
http	O
:	O
//fortune.com/2017/03/14/trumpcare-planned-parenthood-maternity-coverage/	O
''	O
source=	O
''	O
fortune	ORG
''	O
]	O
[	O
bs-seperator	O
]	O
[	O
bs-title	O
]	O
good	O
question	O
[	O
/bs-title	O
]	O
[	O
bs-content	O
]	O
'why	O
is	O
silicon	LOC
valley	LOC
so	O
awful	O
to	O
women	O
?	O
'	O
liza	PERS
mundy	PERS
probes	O
the	O
answer	O
in	O
the	O
latest	O
issue	O
of	O
the	O
atlantic	O
,	O
speaking	O
to	O
dozens	O
of	O
women	O
in	O
the	O
tech	O
industry	O
who	O
love	O
their	O
jobs	O
,	O
but	O
who	O
all	O
have	O
endured	O
incidents	O
that	O
``	O
chipped	O
away	O
at	O
their	O
sense	O
of	O
belonging	O
and	O
expertise	O
.	O
''	O
a	O
recent	O
survey	O
of	O
nearly	O
200	O
senior	O
women	O
in	O
tech	O
found	O
that	O
almost	O
all	O
of	O
them	O
had	O
experienced	O
sexist	O
interactions	O
.	O
[	O
/bs-content	O
]	O
[	O
bs-link	O
link=	O
''	O
https	O
:	O
//www.theatlantic.com/magazine/archive/2017/04/why-is-silicon-valley-so-awful-to-women/517788/	O
''	O
source=	O
''	O
the	O
atlantic	O
''	O
]	O
asia-pacific	LOC
[	O
bs-title	O
]	O
pressing	O
park	PERS
[	O
/bs-title	O
]	O
[	O
bs-content	O
]	O
ousted	O
south	O
korean	O
president	O
park	PERS
geun-hye	PERS
,	O
the	O
country	O
's	O
first	O
democratically-elected	O
president	O
to	O
be	O
removed	O
from	O
office	O
,	O
will	O
be	O
summoned	O
for	O
questioning	O
regarding	O
the	O
expansive	O
corruption	O
probe	O
that	O
led	O
to	O
her	O
impeachment	O
.	O
her	O
longstanding	O
friendship	O
with	O
her	O
religious	O
mentor	O
's	O
daughter	O
,	O
choi	PERS
soon-sil	PERS
,	O
who	O
is	O
currently	O
on	O
trial	O
for	O
coercion	O
and	O
attempted	O
fraud	O
,	O
is	O
a	O
large	O
factor	O
in	O
the	O
investigations	O
.	O
park	PERS
faces	O
allegations	O
that	O
she	O
used	O
her	O
presidential	O
powers	O
to	O
collect	O
funds	O
for	O
choi	O
's	O
foundations	O
.	O
[	O
/bs-content	O
]	O
[	O
bs-link	O
link=	O
''	O
http	O
:	O
//www.aljazeera.com/news/2017/03/prosecutors-summon-ousted-park-geun-hye-170314065031836.html	O
''	O
source=	O
''	O
al	ORG
jazeera	ORG
''	O
]	O
[	O
bs-seperator	O
]	O
[	O
bs-title	O
]	O
boycotting	O
china	LOC
's	O
bankers	O
[	O
/bs-title	O
]	O
[	O
bs-content	O
]	O
baijing	PERS
yu	PERS
may	O
have	O
been	O
raised	O
by	O
two	O
generations	O
of	O
chinese	O
bankers	O
,	O
but	O
that	O
does	O
n't	O
mean	O
she	O
has	O
faith	O
in	O
the	O
domestic	O
market	O
.	O
her	O
$	O
202	O
million	O
comgest	O
growth	O
greater	O
china	LOC
fund	O
returns	O
an	O
annualized	O
22	O
%	O
,	O
but	O
takes	O
the	O
bold	O
approach	O
of	O
excluding	O
chinese	O
lenders	O
.	O
close	O
ties	O
between	O
china	LOC
's	O
banks	O
and	O
government	O
make	O
yu	O
wary	O
of	O
investing	O
in	O
the	O
sector	O
,	O
where	O
,	O
she	O
says	O
,	O
lenders	O
have	O
``	O
black	O
box	O
''	O
balance	O
sheets	O
and	O
operate	O
as	O
political	O
tools	O
.	O
[	O
/bs-content	O
]	O
[	O
bs-link	O
link=	O
''	O
https	O
:	O
//www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2017-03-13/millennial-china-stock-guru-with-banker-parents-won-t-buy-banks	O
''	O
source=	O
''	O
bloomberg	O
''	O
]	O
[	O
bs-seperator	O
]	O
[	O
bs-content	O
]	O
news	O
summaries	O
by	O
linda	PERS
kinstler	PERS
@	O
lindakinstler	O
[	O
/bs-content	O
]	O
in	O
brief	O
[	O
bs-title	O
size=	O
''	O
small	O
''	O
]	O
we	O
know	O
female	O
ceos	O
get	O
paid	O
more	O
,	O
but	O
we	O
do	O
n't	O
know	O
why	O
[	O
/bs-title	O
]	O
[	O
bs-link	O
link=	O
''	O
https	O
:	O
//hbr.org/2017/03/we-know-female-ceos-get-paid-more-but-we-dont-know-why	O
?	O
''	O
source=	O
''	O
harvard	ORG
business	ORG
review	ORG
''	O
]	O
[	O
bs-title	O
size=	O
''	O
small	O
''	O
]	O
trumpcare	O
may	O
keep	O
obamacare	O
's	O
provisions	O
for	O
working	O
mothers	O
[	O
/bs-title	O
]	O
[	O
bs-link	O
link=	O
''	O
http	O
:	O
//fortune.com/2017/03/14/republican-healthcare-breastfeeding/	O
''	O
source=	O
''	O
fortune	ORG
''	O
]	O
[	O
bs-title	O
size=	O
''	O
small	O
''	O
]	O
women	O
in	O
cybersecurity	O
face	O
an	O
uphill	O
battle	O
.	O
mentorship	O
could	O
help	O
[	O
/bs-title	O
]	O
[	O
bs-link	O
link=	O
''	O
http	O
:	O
//fortune.com/2017/03/15/women-cybersecurity-discrimination-pwc-research/	O
''	O
source=	O
''	O
fortune	ORG
''	O
]	O
[	O
bs-title	O
size=	O
''	O
small	O
''	O
]	O
adidas	ORG
hires	O
social	O
media	O
stars	O
to	O
double	O
women	O
's	O
market	O
share	O
[	O
/bs-title	O
]	O
[	O
bs-link	O
link=	O
''	O
https	O
:	O
//www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2017-03-14/adidas-hires-social-media-stars-to-double-women-s-market-share	O
''	O
source=	O
''	O
bloomberg	O
''	O
]	O
[	O
bs-title	O
size=	O
''	O
small	O
''	O
]	O
scotland	O
's	O
muirfield	ORG
golf	O
club	O
votes	O
to	O
admit	O
women	O
for	O
the	O
first	O
time	O
in	O
its	O
273-year	O
history	O
[	O
/bs-title	O
]	O
[	O
bs-link	O
link=	O
''	O
http	O
:	O
//www.bbc.co.uk/news/uk-scotland-edinburgh-east-fife-39260578	O
?	O
ns_mchannel=social	O
&	O
ns_campaign=bbc_breaking	O
&	O
ns_source=twitter	O
&	O
ns_linkname=news_central	O
''	O
source=	O
''	O
bbc	ORG
''	O
]	O
[	O
bs-title	O
size=	O
''	O
small	O
''	O
]	O
the	O
50	O
most	O
powerful	O
latinas	O
of	O
2017	O
[	O
/bs-title	O
]	O
[	O
bs-link	O
link=	O
''	O
http	O
:	O
//fortune.com/2017/03/14/50-most-powerful-latinas/	O
''	O
source=	O
''	O
fortune	ORG
''	O
]	O
parting	O
words	O
[	O
bs-quote	O
link=	O
''	O
https	O
:	O
//jezebel.com/theres-a-lot-to-be-gained-from-loss-and-suffering-talk-1792828753	O
''	O
author=	O
''	O
--	O
writer	O
ariel	PERS
levy	PERS
,	O
on	O
writing	O
about	O
grief	O
and	O
love	O
for	O
her	O
new	O
book	O
,	O
'the	O
rules	O
do	O
not	O
apply	O
.	O
'	O
''	O
]	O
''	O
what	O
's	O
boring	O
is	O
beating	O
yourself	O
up	O
.	O
``	O
[	O
/bs-quote	O
]	O
eu	LOC
headscarf	O
ban	O
ruling	O
sparks	O
faith	ORG
group	ORG
backlash	O
brussels	LOC
(	O
r	O
eu	LOC
ters	O
)	O
-	O
companies	O
may	O
bar	O
staff	O
from	O
wearing	O
islamic	O
headscarves	O
and	O
other	O
visible	O
religious	O
symbols	O
under	O
certain	O
conditions	O
,	O
the	O
eu	LOC
ropean	O
union	O
’	O
s	O
top	O
court	O
ruled	O
on	O
tuesday	O
,	O
setting	O
off	O
a	O
storm	O
of	O
complaint	O
from	O
rights	O
group	O
s	O
and	O
religious	O
leaders	O
.	O
in	O
its	O
first	O
ruling	O
on	O
a	O
hot	O
political	O
issue	O
across	O
eu	LOC
rope	O
,	O
the	O
court	ORG
of	ORG
justice	ORG
(	O
ecj	ORG
)	O
found	O
a	O
belgian	O
firm	O
which	O
had	O
a	O
rule	O
barring	O
employees	O
who	O
dealt	O
with	O
customers	O
from	O
wearing	O
visible	O
religious	O
and	O
political	O
symbols	O
may	O
not	O
have	O
discriminated	O
against	O
a	O
receptionist	O
dismissed	O
for	O
wearing	O
a	O
headscarf	O
.	O
the	O
judgment	O
on	O
that	O
and	O
a	O
french	O
case	O
came	O
on	O
the	O
eve	O
of	O
a	O
dutch	O
election	O
in	O
which	O
muslim	O
immigration	O
is	O
a	O
key	O
issue	O
and	O
weeks	O
before	O
france	LOC
votes	O
for	O
a	O
president	O
in	O
a	O
similarly	O
charged	O
campaign	O
.	O
french	O
conservative	O
candidate	O
francois	PERS
fillon	PERS
hailed	O
the	O
ruling	O
as	O
“	O
an	O
immense	O
relief	O
”	O
that	O
would	O
contribute	O
to	O
“	O
social	O
peace	O
”	O
.	O
but	O
a	O
campaign	O
group	O
backing	O
the	O
women	O
said	O
the	O
ruling	O
could	O
shut	O
many	O
muslim	O
women	O
out	O
of	O
the	O
workforce	O
.	O
and	O
eu	LOC
ropean	O
rabbis	O
said	O
the	O
court	O
had	O
added	O
to	O
rising	O
incidences	O
of	O
hate	O
crime	O
to	O
send	O
a	O
message	O
that	O
“	O
faith	O
communities	O
are	O
no	O
longer	O
welcome	O
”	O
.	O
the	O
judges	O
in	O
luxembourg	LOC
did	O
find	O
that	O
the	O
dismissals	O
of	O
the	O
two	O
women	O
may	O
,	O
depending	O
on	O
the	O
view	O
of	O
national	O
courts	O
,	O
have	O
breached	O
eu	LOC
laws	O
against	O
religious	O
discrimination	O
.	O
they	O
found	O
in	O
particular	O
that	O
the	O
case	O
of	O
the	O
french	O
software	O
engineer	O
,	O
fired	O
after	O
a	O
customer	O
complaint	O
,	O
may	O
well	O
have	O
been	O
discriminatory	O
.	O
reactions	O
,	O
however	O
,	O
focused	O
on	O
the	O
conclusion	O
that	O
services	O
firm	O
g4s	O
in	O
belgium	LOC
was	O
entitled	O
to	O
dismiss	O
receptionist	O
samira	PERS
achbita	PERS
in	O
2006	O
if	O
,	O
in	O
pursuit	O
of	O
legitimate	O
business	O
interests	O
,	O
it	O
fairly	O
applied	O
a	O
broad	O
dress	O
code	O
for	O
all	O
customer-facing	O
staff	O
to	O
project	O
an	O
image	O
of	O
political	O
and	O
religious	O
n	O
eu	LOC
trality	O
.	O
“	O
backdoor	O
to	O
prejudice	O
”	O
the	ORG
open	ORG
society	ORG
justice	ORG
initiative	ORG
,	O
a	O
group	O
backed	O
by	O
the	O
philanthropist	O
george	PERS
soros	PERS
,	O
said	O
the	O
ruling	O
“	O
weakens	O
the	O
guarantee	O
of	O
equality	O
”	O
offered	O
by	O
eu	LOC
non-discrimination	O
laws	O
.	O
“	O
in	O
many	O
member	O
states	O
,	O
national	O
laws	O
will	O
still	O
recognize	O
that	O
ban	O
ning	O
religious	O
headscarves	O
at	O
work	O
is	O
discrimination	O
,	O
”	O
policy	O
office	O
maryam	PERS
hmadoun	PERS
said	O
.	O
“	O
but	O
in	O
places	O
where	O
national	O
law	O
is	O
weak	O
,	O
this	O
ruling	O
will	O
exclude	O
many	O
muslim	O
women	O
from	O
the	O
workplace.	O
”	O
amnesty	ORG
international	ORG
welcomed	O
the	O
ruling	O
on	O
the	O
french	O
case	O
that	O
“	O
employers	O
are	O
not	O
at	O
liberty	O
to	O
pander	O
to	O
the	O
prejudices	O
of	O
their	O
clients	O
”	O
.	O
but	O
,	O
it	O
said	O
,	O
ban	O
s	O
on	O
religious	O
symbols	O
to	O
show	O
n	O
eu	LOC
trality	O
opened	O
“	O
a	O
backdoor	O
to	O
precisely	O
such	O
prejudice	O
”	O
.	O
the	O
president	O
of	O
the	O
conference	O
of	O
eu	LOC
ropean	O
rabbis	O
,	O
chief	O
rabbi	O
pinchas	PERS
goldschmidt	PERS
,	O
complained	O
:	O
“	O
this	O
decision	O
sends	O
a	O
signal	O
to	O
all	O
religious	O
group	O
s	O
in	O
eu	LOC
rope	O
”	O
.	O
national	O
court	O
cases	O
across	O
eu	LOC
rope	O
have	O
included	O
questions	O
on	O
the	O
wearing	O
of	O
christian	O
crosses	O
,	O
sikh	O
tur	O
ban	O
s	O
and	O
jewish	O
skullcaps	O
.	O
in	O
the	O
belgian	O
case	O
,	O
the	O
ecj	ORG
said	O
:	O
“	O
an	O
internal	O
rule	O
of	O
an	O
undertaking	O
which	O
prohibits	O
the	O
visible	O
wearing	O
of	O
any	O
political	O
,	O
philosophical	O
or	O
religious	O
sign	O
does	O
not	O
constitute	O
direct	O
discrimination.	O
”	O
it	O
was	O
for	O
belgian	O
judges	O
to	O
determine	O
whether	O
she	O
may	O
have	O
been	O
a	O
victim	O
of	O
indirect	O
discrimination	O
if	O
the	O
rule	O
put	O
people	O
of	O
a	O
particular	O
faith	O
at	O
a	O
disadvantage	O
.	O
but	O
the	O
rule	O
could	O
still	O
be	O
justified	O
if	O
it	O
was	O
“	O
genuinely	O
pursued	O
in	O
a	O
consistent	O
and	O
systematic	O
manner	O
”	O
to	O
project	O
an	O
“	O
image	O
of	O
n	O
eu	LOC
trality	O
”	O
.	O
however	O
,	O
in	O
the	O
case	O
of	O
asma	PERS
bougnaoui	PERS
,	O
dismissed	O
by	O
french	O
software	O
company	O
micropole	ORG
,	O
it	O
said	O
it	O
was	O
up	O
to	O
french	O
courts	O
to	O
determine	O
whether	O
there	O
was	O
such	O
a	O
rule	O
.	O
if	O
her	O
dismissal	O
was	O
based	O
only	O
on	O
meeting	O
the	O
particular	O
customer	O
’	O
s	O
preference	O
,	O
it	O
saw	O
“	O
only	O
very	O
limited	O
circumstances	O
”	O
in	O
which	O
a	O
religious	O
symbol	O
could	O
be	O
objectively	O
taken	O
as	O
reason	O
for	O
her	O
not	O
to	O
work	O
.	O
(	O
additional	O
reporting	O
by	O
waverly	PERS
colville	PERS
in	O
brussels	LOC
and	O
sudip	O
kar-gupta	O
in	O
paris	LOC
;	O
editing	O
by	O
catherine	PERS
evans	PERS
)	O
update	O
2-eu	O
headscarf	O
ban	O
ruling	O
sparks	O
faith	O
group	O
backlash	O
by	O
|	O
brussels	LOC
companies	O
may	O
bar	O
staff	O
from	O
wearing	O
islamic	O
headscarves	O
and	O
other	O
visible	O
religious	O
symbols	O
under	O
certain	O
conditions	O
,	O
the	O
european	LOC
union	LOC
's	O
top	O
court	O
ruled	O
on	O
tuesday	O
,	O
setting	O
off	O
a	O
storm	O
of	O
complaint	O
from	O
rights	O
groups	O
and	O
religious	O
leaders	O
.	O
in	O
its	O
first	O
ruling	O
on	O
a	O
hot	O
political	O
issue	O
across	O
europe	LOC
,	O
the	O
court	ORG
of	ORG
justice	ORG
(	O
ecj	ORG
)	O
found	O
a	O
belgian	O
firm	O
which	O
had	O
a	O
rule	O
barring	O
employees	O
who	O
dealt	O
with	O
customers	O
from	O
wearing	O
visible	O
religious	O
and	O
political	O
symbols	O
may	O
not	O
have	O
discriminated	O
against	O
a	O
receptionist	O
dismissed	O
for	O
wearing	O
a	O
headscarf	O
.	O
the	O
judgment	O
on	O
that	O
and	O
a	O
french	O
case	O
came	O
on	O
the	O
eve	O
of	O
a	O
dutch	O
election	O
in	O
which	O
muslim	O
immigration	O
is	O
a	O
key	O
issue	O
and	O
weeks	O
before	O
france	LOC
votes	O
for	O
a	O
president	O
in	O
a	O
similarly	O
charged	O
campaign	O
.	O
french	O
conservative	O
candidate	O
francois	PERS
fillon	PERS
hailed	O
the	O
ruling	O
as	O
``	O
an	O
immense	O
relief	O
''	O
that	O
would	O
contribute	O
to	O
``	O
social	O
peace	O
''	O
.	O
but	O
a	O
campaign	O
group	O
backing	O
the	O
women	O
said	O
the	O
ruling	O
could	O
shut	O
many	O
muslim	O
women	O
out	O
of	O
the	O
workforce	O
.	O
and	O
european	O
rabbis	O
said	O
the	O
court	O
had	O
added	O
to	O
rising	O
incidences	O
of	O
hate	O
crime	O
to	O
send	O
a	O
message	O
that	O
``	O
faith	O
communities	O
are	O
no	O
longer	O
welcome	O
''	O
.	O
the	O
judges	O
in	O
luxembourg	LOC
did	O
find	O
that	O
the	O
dismissals	O
of	O
the	O
two	O
women	O
may	O
,	O
depending	O
on	O
the	O
view	O
of	O
national	O
courts	O
,	O
have	O
breached	O
eu	LOC
laws	O
against	O
religious	O
discrimination	O
.	O
they	O
found	O
in	O
particular	O
that	O
the	O
case	O
of	O
the	O
french	O
software	O
engineer	O
,	O
fired	O
after	O
a	O
customer	O
complaint	O
,	O
may	O
well	O
have	O
been	O
discriminatory	O
.	O
reactions	O
,	O
however	O
,	O
focused	O
on	O
the	O
conclusion	O
that	O
services	O
firm	O
g4s	O
in	O
belgium	LOC
was	O
entitled	O
to	O
dismiss	O
receptionist	O
samira	PERS
achbita	PERS
in	O
2006	O
if	O
,	O
in	O
pursuit	O
of	O
legitimate	O
business	O
interests	O
,	O
it	O
fairly	O
applied	O
a	O
broad	O
dress	O
code	O
for	O
all	O
customer-facing	O
staff	O
to	O
project	O
an	O
image	O
of	O
political	O
and	O
religious	O
neutrality	O
.	O
``	O
backdoor	O
to	O
prejudice	O
''	O
the	ORG
open	ORG
society	ORG
justice	ORG
initiative	ORG
,	O
a	O
group	O
backed	O
by	O
the	O
philanthropist	O
george	PERS
soros	PERS
,	O
said	O
the	O
ruling	O
``	O
weakens	O
the	O
guarantee	O
of	O
equality	O
''	O
offered	O
by	O
eu	LOC
non-discrimination	O
laws	O
.	O
``	O
in	O
many	O
member	O
states	O
,	O
national	O
laws	O
will	O
still	O
recognize	O
that	O
banning	O
religious	O
headscarves	O
at	O
work	O
is	O
discrimination	O
,	O
''	O
policy	O
office	O
maryam	PERS
hmadoun	PERS
said	O
.	O
``	O
but	O
in	O
places	O
where	O
national	O
law	O
is	O
weak	O
,	O
this	O
ruling	O
will	O
exclude	O
many	O
muslim	O
women	O
from	O
the	O
workplace	O
.	O
''	O
amnesty	ORG
international	ORG
welcomed	O
the	O
ruling	O
on	O
the	O
french	O
case	O
that	O
``	O
employers	O
are	O
not	O
at	O
liberty	O
to	O
pander	O
to	O
the	O
prejudices	O
of	O
their	O
clients	O
''	O
.	O
but	O
,	O
it	O
said	O
,	O
bans	O
on	O
religious	O
symbols	O
to	O
show	O
neutrality	O
opened	O
``	O
a	O
backdoor	O
to	O
precisely	O
such	O
prejudice	O
''	O
.	O
the	O
president	O
of	O
the	O
conference	O
of	O
european	O
rabbis	O
,	O
chief	O
rabbi	O
pinchas	PERS
goldschmidt	PERS
,	O
complained	O
:	O
``	O
this	O
decision	O
sends	O
a	O
signal	O
to	O
all	O
religious	O
groups	O
in	O
europe	LOC
''	O
.	O
national	O
court	O
cases	O
across	O
europe	LOC
have	O
included	O
questions	O
on	O
the	O
wearing	O
of	O
christian	O
crosses	O
,	O
sikh	O
turbans	O
and	O
jewish	O
skullcaps	O
.	O
in	O
the	O
belgian	O
case	O
,	O
the	O
ecj	ORG
said	O
:	O
``	O
an	O
internal	O
rule	O
of	O
an	O
undertaking	O
which	O
prohibits	O
the	O
visible	O
wearing	O
of	O
any	O
political	O
,	O
philosophical	O
or	O
religious	O
sign	O
does	O
not	O
constitute	O
direct	O
discrimination	O
.	O
''	O
it	O
was	O
for	O
belgian	O
judges	O
to	O
determine	O
whether	O
she	O
may	O
have	O
been	O
a	O
victim	O
of	O
indirect	O
discrimination	O
if	O
the	O
rule	O
put	O
people	O
of	O
a	O
particular	O
faith	O
at	O
a	O
disadvantage	O
.	O
but	O
the	O
rule	O
could	O
still	O
be	O
justified	O
if	O
it	O
was	O
``	O
genuinely	O
pursued	O
in	O
a	O
consistent	O
and	O
systematic	O
manner	O
''	O
to	O
project	O
an	O
``	O
image	O
of	O
neutrality	O
''	O
.	O
however	O
,	O
in	O
the	O
case	O
of	O
asma	PERS
bougnaoui	PERS
,	O
dismissed	O
by	O
french	O
software	O
company	O
micropole	ORG
,	O
it	O
said	O
it	O
was	O
up	O
to	O
french	O
courts	O
to	O
determine	O
whether	O
there	O
was	O
such	O
a	O
rule	O
.	O
if	O
her	O
dismissal	O
was	O
based	O
only	O
on	O
meeting	O
the	O
particular	O
customer	O
's	O
preference	O
,	O
it	O
saw	O
``	O
only	O
very	O
limited	O
circumstances	O
''	O
in	O
which	O
a	O
religious	O
symbol	O
could	O
be	O
objectively	O
taken	O
as	O
reason	O
for	O
her	O
not	O
to	O
work	O
.	O
(	O
additional	O
reporting	O
by	O
waverly	PERS
colville	PERS
in	O
brussels	LOC
and	O
sudip	O
kar-gupta	O
in	O
paris	LOC
;	O
editing	O
by	O
catherine	PERS
evans	PERS
)	O
a	O
recipe	O
for	O
healthy	O
holidays	O
:	O
14	O
key	O
ingredients	O
by	O
susan	PERS
blumenthal	PERS
,	O
m.d	O
.	O
and	O
katherine	PERS
perez	PERS
as	O
ralph	PERS
waldo	PERS
emerson	PERS
once	O
said	O
,	O
“	O
the	O
first	O
wealth	O
is	O
health.	O
”	O
while	O
reflecting	O
on	O
what	O
we	O
are	O
most	O
thankful	O
for	O
this	O
holiday	O
season	O
,	O
let	O
’	O
s	O
remember	O
the	O
importance	O
of	O
good	O
health	O
.	O
though	O
the	O
holidays	O
brim	O
with	O
joy	O
and	O
happiness	O
for	O
many	O
,	O
they	O
can	O
also	O
add	O
stress	O
with	O
traveling	O
,	O
visiting	O
relatives	O
and	O
maintaining	O
diet	O
and	O
exercise	O
goals	O
.	O
listed	O
below	O
are	O
some	O
key	O
ingredients	O
for	O
a	O
recipe	O
that	O
will	O
ensure	O
a	O
happy	O
and	O
healthy	O
holiday	O
season	O
:	O
1	O
)	O
eat	O
well	O
an	O
abundance	O
of	O
food	O
is	O
at	O
almost	O
every	O
event	O
this	O
time	O
of	O
year	O
.	O
but	O
don	O
’	O
t	O
let	O
the	O
holiday	O
season	O
undo	O
the	O
health	O
gains	O
you	O
’	O
ve	O
made	O
throughout	O
the	O
year	O
.	O
eat	O
a	O
balanced	O
diet	O
rich	O
in	O
fruits	O
,	O
vegetables	O
,	O
fiber	O
,	O
whole	O
grains	O
,	O
protein	O
and	O
vitamins	O
,	O
and	O
try	O
to	O
cut	O
down	O
on	O
calories	O
,	O
saturated	O
fats	O
and	O
salt	O
.	O
smart	O
eating	O
helps	O
maintain	O
a	O
healthy	O
weight	O
and	O
has	O
long-term	O
health	O
benefits	O
,	O
reducing	O
the	O
risk	O
of	O
chronic	O
illnesses	O
such	O
as	O
heart	O
disease	O
,	O
stroke	O
,	O
type	O
2	O
diabetes	O
,	O
certain	O
cancers	O
,	O
and	O
other	O
diseases	O
.	O
maintaining	O
healthy	O
eating	O
patterns	O
,	O
however	O
,	O
can	O
be	O
difficult	O
during	O
the	O
holiday	O
season	O
.	O
interactive	O
tools	O
such	O
as	O
my	O
plate	O
,	O
a	O
visual	O
guide	O
to	O
healthy	O
eating	O
,	O
can	O
help	O
you	O
build	O
a	O
nutritious	O
meal	O
by	O
defining	O
healthy	O
foods	O
and	O
their	O
serving	O
sizes	O
throughout	O
this	O
festive	O
season	O
.	O
to	O
keep	O
your	O
diet	O
on	O
track	O
,	O
maintain	O
a	O
routine	O
schedule	O
for	O
meals	O
during	O
the	O
holidays	O
,	O
pile	O
your	O
plate	O
with	O
vegetables	O
and	O
fruits	O
,	O
drink	O
plenty	O
of	O
water	O
,	O
and	O
eat	O
mindfully	O
,	O
taking	O
the	O
time	O
to	O
enjoy	O
your	O
food	O
.	O
start	O
the	O
morning	O
with	O
a	O
healthy	O
breakfast	O
,	O
which	O
will	O
provide	O
a	O
boost	O
of	O
energy	O
and	O
help	O
control	O
your	O
appetite	O
throughout	O
the	O
day	O
(	O
get	O
tips	O
from	O
the	O
american	ORG
heart	ORG
association	ORG
)	O
.	O
at	O
holiday	O
parties	O
,	O
whether	O
you	O
are	O
hosting	O
the	O
meal	O
or	O
bringing	O
food	O
to	O
share	O
,	O
make	O
recipes	O
healthier	O
by	O
reducing	O
fat	O
,	O
sugar	O
and	O
calories	O
.	O
some	O
simple	O
tricks	O
to	O
reduce	O
unhealthy	O
ingredients	O
in	O
your	O
recipes	O
include	O
using	O
fat	O
free	O
chicken	O
broth	O
,	O
decreasing	O
the	O
amount	O
of	O
oil	O
and	O
butter	O
,	O
and	O
replacing	O
cream	O
with	O
fat	O
free	O
yogurt	O
or	O
sour	O
cream	O
.	O
when	O
filling	O
your	O
plate	O
,	O
choose	O
lean	O
turkey	O
meat	O
,	O
whole	O
grains	O
,	O
fruits	O
,	O
vegetables	O
,	O
broth-based	O
soups	O
,	O
salads	O
,	O
and	O
other	O
foods	O
that	O
contain	O
water	O
and	O
fiber	O
.	O
a	O
good	O
variety	O
is	O
also	O
important—sampling	O
a	O
small	O
amount	O
of	O
foods	O
with	O
different	O
textures	O
and	O
colors	O
can	O
help	O
alleviate	O
cravings	O
.	O
don	O
’	O
t	O
punish	O
yourself	O
for	O
indulging	O
a	O
little—just	O
be	O
moderate	O
in	O
your	O
portions	O
of	O
less-healthy	O
foods	O
,	O
and	O
enjoy	O
your	O
favorite	O
dessert	O
this	O
holiday	O
season	O
,	O
but	O
do	O
so	O
in	O
small	O
amounts	O
.	O
2	O
)	O
cook	O
and	O
eat	O
safely	O
food	O
safety	O
is	O
very	O
important	O
when	O
preparing	O
your	O
holiday	O
meals	O
.	O
foodborne	O
illness	O
is	O
responsible	O
for	O
about	O
3,000	O
deaths	O
per	O
year	O
,	O
and	O
1	O
in	O
6	O
americans	O
become	O
sick	O
annually	O
from	O
contaminated	O
foods	O
or	O
beverages	O
.	O
to	O
reduce	O
the	O
risk	O
of	O
foodborne	O
illness	O
,	O
safely	O
thaw	O
,	O
prepare	O
,	O
and	O
cook	O
all	O
meat	O
,	O
poultry	O
,	O
and	O
seafood	O
.	O
keep	O
bacteria	O
at	O
bay	O
by	O
safely	O
thawing	O
frozen	O
meat	O
in	O
cold	O
water	O
in	O
either	O
the	O
refrigerator	O
or	O
in	O
a	O
microwave	O
oven—never	O
thaw	O
or	O
marinate	O
on	O
the	O
counter	O
.	O
thoroughly	O
clean	O
surfaces	O
,	O
utensils	O
and	O
cutting	O
boards	O
,	O
and	O
wash	O
your	O
hands	O
for	O
at	O
least	O
20	O
seconds	O
after	O
touching	O
raw	O
meat	O
.	O
unclean	O
surfaces	O
and	O
tools	O
can	O
transfer	O
illness-causing	O
bacteria	O
to	O
other	O
foods	O
.	O
minimize	O
the	O
risk	O
of	O
cross-contamination	O
by	O
separating	O
your	O
raw	O
meat	O
,	O
poultry	O
,	O
seafood	O
,	O
and	O
eggs	O
from	O
ready-to-eat	O
foods	O
in	O
your	O
shopping	O
cart	O
,	O
refrigerator	O
,	O
and	O
cutting	O
boards	O
.	O
checking	O
the	O
color	O
of	O
your	O
cooked	O
food	O
is	O
not	O
enough	O
to	O
ensure	O
that	O
it	O
is	O
free	O
from	O
bacterial	O
contamination	O
,	O
so	O
use	O
a	O
food	O
thermometer	O
to	O
ensure	O
the	O
correct	O
internal	O
temperature	O
of	O
the	O
meat	O
,	O
and	O
follow	O
safe	O
minimum	O
cooking	O
temperatures	O
.	O
promptly	O
store	O
perishable	O
foods	O
,	O
including	O
leftovers	O
,	O
in	O
containers	O
in	O
the	O
refrigerator	O
or	O
freezer	O
within	O
two	O
hours	O
,	O
as	O
bacteria	O
can	O
multiply	O
rapidly	O
at	O
room	O
temperature	O
.	O
remember	O
to	O
safely	O
handle	O
fruits	O
and	O
vegetables	O
as	O
well	O
;	O
wash	O
fruits	O
and	O
vegetables	O
before	O
eating	O
and	O
preparing	O
them	O
,	O
even	O
if	O
peeling	O
them	O
.	O
finally	O
,	O
with	O
the	O
holiday	O
season	O
coinciding	O
with	O
increased	O
travel	O
and	O
the	O
cold/flu	O
season	O
,	O
wash	O
your	O
hands	O
often	O
and	O
consider	O
using	O
alcohol	O
based	O
hand	O
sanitizers	O
to	O
prevent	O
the	O
spread	O
of	O
viruses	O
and	O
other	O
microbes	O
.	O
3	O
)	O
be	O
active	O
physical	O
activity	O
is	O
one	O
of	O
the	O
most	O
important	O
ingredients	O
of	O
a	O
healthier	O
future	O
.	O
don	O
’	O
t	O
let	O
the	O
cold	O
weather	O
get	O
you	O
down—bundle	O
up	O
and	O
get	O
moving	O
!	O
the	O
holidays	O
are	O
no	O
excuse	O
to	O
stop	O
your	O
exercise	O
routine	O
.	O
take	O
advantage	O
of	O
having	O
friends	O
and	O
family	O
around	O
by	O
asking	O
them	O
to	O
join	O
you	O
on	O
a	O
walk	O
or	O
gym	O
session	O
,	O
and	O
accept	O
their	O
invitations	O
when	O
they	O
request	O
your	O
company	O
.	O
if	O
staying	O
at	O
a	O
hotel	O
,	O
visit	O
the	O
indoor	O
swimming	O
pool	O
or	O
gym	O
,	O
and	O
if	O
you	O
find	O
yourself	O
at	O
a	O
relative	O
’	O
s	O
or	O
friend	O
’	O
s	O
home	O
,	O
take	O
a	O
walk	O
or	O
go	O
on	O
a	O
run	O
to	O
explore	O
the	O
new	O
neighborhood	O
and	O
local	O
sights	O
.	O
embrace	O
whatever	O
fitness	O
activities	O
are	O
available—play	O
tag	O
with	O
the	O
kids	O
,	O
volunteer	O
to	O
make	O
a	O
grocery	O
run	O
,	O
have	O
a	O
dance	O
party	O
,	O
or	O
do	O
a	O
simple	O
indoor	O
workout	O
routine	O
that	O
doesn	O
’	O
t	O
require	O
equipment	O
.	O
if	O
you	O
don	O
’	O
t	O
currently	O
have	O
an	O
exercise	O
regimen	O
,	O
the	O
holidays	O
are	O
a	O
wonderful	O
time	O
to	O
crowdsource	O
for	O
fitness	O
ideas	O
from	O
family	O
and	O
friends	O
,	O
and	O
you	O
can	O
even	O
add	O
fitness	O
equipment—such	O
as	O
a	O
jump	O
rope	O
that	O
counts	O
your	O
jumps	O
,	O
a	O
new	O
yoga	O
mat	O
,	O
or	O
an	O
electronic	O
exercise	O
monitor	O
to	O
wear	O
on	O
your	O
wrist—to	O
your	O
holiday	O
wish	O
list	O
.	O
when	O
crafting	O
an	O
exercise	O
plan	O
,	O
aim	O
for	O
at	O
least	O
30	O
minutes	O
of	O
moderate-intensity	O
aerobic	O
exercise	O
with	O
strength	O
training	O
at	O
least	O
five	O
days	O
a	O
week	O
,	O
or	O
1	O
hour	O
and	O
15	O
minutes	O
per	O
week	O
of	O
high-intensity	O
aerobic	O
exercise	O
combined	O
with	O
strength	O
training	O
.	O
the	O
new	O
year	O
is	O
a	O
great	O
time	O
to	O
make	O
small	O
,	O
everyday	O
lifestyle	O
changes	O
that	O
can	O
get	O
you	O
moving	O
;	O
take	O
the	O
stairs	O
instead	O
of	O
elevators	O
,	O
think	O
of	O
home	O
chores	O
,	O
such	O
as	O
vacuuming	O
,	O
raking	O
leaves	O
and	O
shoveling	O
snow	O
,	O
as	O
exercise	O
opportunities	O
rather	O
than	O
burdens	O
,	O
power	O
walk	O
with	O
coworkers	O
during	O
lunch	O
,	O
or	O
try	O
a	O
pedometer	O
and	O
aim	O
for	O
10,000	O
steps	O
a	O
day	O
.	O
visit	O
fitness.gov	O
to	O
learn	O
more	O
.	O
4	O
)	O
stay	O
hydrated	O
whether	O
you	O
are	O
traveling	O
or	O
hosting	O
a	O
holiday	O
event	O
,	O
cold	O
weather	O
,	O
changing	O
routines	O
,	O
and	O
busy	O
holiday	O
schedules	O
can	O
make	O
drinking	O
plenty	O
of	O
water	O
throughout	O
the	O
day	O
an	O
afterthought	O
.	O
be	O
aware	O
of	O
the	O
symptoms	O
of	O
dehydration	O
;	O
if	O
you	O
are	O
feeling	O
weak	O
,	O
dizzy	O
,	O
or	O
drowsy	O
,	O
or	O
if	O
you	O
have	O
headaches	O
or	O
migraines	O
,	O
you	O
may	O
not	O
be	O
getting	O
enough	O
water	O
.	O
staying	O
hydrated	O
can	O
help	O
with	O
jet-lag	O
if	O
you	O
are	O
traveling	O
and	O
can	O
help	O
prevent	O
excessive	O
eating	O
as	O
well	O
.	O
it	O
can	O
also	O
have	O
positive	O
effects	O
on	O
your	O
mood	O
.	O
aim	O
to	O
drink	O
eight	O
8-ounce	O
cups	O
of	O
water	O
per	O
day	O
,	O
have	O
an	O
extra	O
glass	O
before	O
your	O
holiday	O
meal	O
so	O
you	O
don	O
’	O
t	O
feel	O
famished	O
when	O
dinner	O
begins	O
,	O
and	O
replace	O
sugary	O
drinks	O
,	O
such	O
as	O
soda	O
,	O
with	O
water	O
,	O
which	O
will	O
also	O
help	O
to	O
trim	O
calories	O
from	O
your	O
diet	O
.	O
if	O
you	O
are	O
looking	O
for	O
a	O
useful	O
gift	O
for	O
friends	O
or	O
relatives	O
,	O
consider	O
a	O
reusable	O
water	O
bottle	O
as	O
a	O
present	O
.	O
not	O
only	O
are	O
they	O
a	O
fun	O
way	O
to	O
help	O
people	O
stay	O
hydrated	O
(	O
they	O
are	O
available	O
in	O
a	O
wide	O
array	O
of	O
colors	O
and	O
designs	O
)	O
,	O
but	O
they	O
also	O
have	O
the	O
added	O
benefit	O
of	O
being	O
environmentally	O
friendly	O
.	O
5	O
)	O
moderate	O
your	O
holiday	O
libations	O
the	O
holidays	O
are	O
a	O
time	O
for	O
celebration	O
but	O
shouldn	O
’	O
t	O
be	O
an	O
excuse	O
for	O
consuming	O
excess	O
alcohol	O
.	O
if	O
enjoying	O
a	O
drink	O
at	O
holiday	O
parties	O
this	O
season	O
,	O
remember	O
that	O
moderation	O
is	O
essential	O
.	O
the	O
holiday	O
season	O
can	O
be	O
one	O
of	O
the	O
most	O
dangerous	O
times	O
of	O
the	O
year	O
for	O
alcohol-related	O
injuries	O
and	O
alcohol	O
abuse	O
,	O
so	O
always	O
be	O
aware	O
of	O
your	O
alcohol	O
intake	O
,	O
don	O
’	O
t	O
drink	O
and	O
drive	O
,	O
and	O
also	O
be	O
sure	O
that	O
others	O
don	O
’	O
t	O
get	O
behind	O
the	O
wheel	O
after	O
drinking	O
alcohol	O
.	O
in	O
2015	O
,	O
alcohol-impaired	O
driving	O
killed	O
10,265	O
people	O
,	O
a	O
startling	O
3.2	O
%	O
increase	O
from	O
2014	O
.	O
moderate	O
your	O
alcohol	O
consumption	O
,	O
be	O
aware	O
of	O
standard	O
serving	O
sizes	O
,	O
stay	O
hydrated	O
,	O
and	O
remember	O
that	O
women	O
metabolize	O
alcohol	O
differently	O
from	O
men	O
and	O
should	O
consume	O
less	O
.	O
alcohol	O
also	O
adds	O
significant	O
calories	O
and	O
few	O
nutrients	O
to	O
your	O
diet	O
.	O
if	O
hosting	O
an	O
event	O
this	O
holiday	O
season	O
,	O
don	O
’	O
t	O
let	O
alcohol	O
be	O
the	O
focus	O
of	O
your	O
party	O
,	O
and	O
be	O
mindful	O
of	O
how	O
alcohol	O
may	O
affect	O
your	O
guests	O
.	O
serve	O
food	O
with	O
alcoholic	O
drinks	O
,	O
mix	O
alcohol	O
with	O
juice	O
or	O
spritzers	O
,	O
offer	O
a	O
selection	O
of	O
non-alcoholic	O
beverages	O
,	O
stop	O
serving	O
alcohol	O
well	O
before	O
the	O
party	O
ends	O
,	O
and	O
offer	O
to	O
allow	O
those	O
who	O
may	O
be	O
impaired	O
to	O
stay	O
the	O
night	O
and	O
off	O
the	O
roads	O
.	O
read	O
more	O
about	O
the	O
negative	O
health	O
effects	O
of	O
excessive	O
drinking	O
here	O
.	O
6	O
)	O
stop	O
smoking	O
cigarette	O
smoking	O
is	O
the	O
leading	O
preventable	O
cause	O
of	O
mortality	O
in	O
the	O
u.s	O
,	O
linked	O
to	O
1	O
in	O
5	O
deaths	O
in	O
america	LOC
annually	O
,	O
so	O
give	O
yourself	O
a	O
lifesaving	O
gift	O
by	O
never	O
smoking	O
or	O
by	O
stopping	O
tobacco	O
use	O
if	O
it	O
is	O
a	O
habit	O
.	O
smoking	O
increases	O
the	O
risk	O
for	O
coronary	O
heart	O
disease	O
,	O
cancer	O
,	O
stroke	O
and	O
many	O
other	O
diseases	O
.	O
furthermore	O
,	O
second-hand	O
smoke	O
significantly	O
impairs	O
the	O
health	O
of	O
others	O
.	O
if	O
you	O
smoke	O
,	O
utilize	O
the	O
support	O
of	O
your	O
family	O
and	O
friends	O
to	O
begin	O
weaning	O
off	O
cigarettes	O
this	O
holiday	O
season	O
.	O
quitting	O
smoking	O
reduces	O
your	O
risk	O
of	O
developing	O
cardiovascular	O
diseases	O
,	O
lung	O
and	O
other	O
cancers	O
,	O
and	O
stroke	O
.	O
learn	O
more	O
about	O
the	O
negative	O
effects	O
of	O
smoking	O
,	O
the	O
benefits	O
of	O
stopping	O
tobacco	O
use	O
,	O
and	O
the	O
variety	O
of	O
different	O
methods	O
to	O
help	O
you	O
quit	O
,	O
including	O
behavioral	O
interventions	O
,	O
nicotine	O
gum	O
and	O
patches	O
,	O
and	O
medications	O
,	O
at	O
smokefree.gov	O
and	O
at	O
betobaccofree.gov	O
.	O
kicking	O
the	O
habit	O
is	O
the	O
number	O
one	O
thing	O
you	O
can	O
do	O
to	O
safeguard	O
your	O
health	O
today	O
and	O
in	O
the	O
future	O
!	O
7	O
)	O
enjoy	O
family	O
and	O
friends	O
though	O
being	O
surrounded	O
by	O
your	O
family	O
over	O
the	O
holidays	O
can	O
be	O
stressful—think	O
clark	PERS
griswold	PERS
in	O
christmas	O
vacation—	O
having	O
strong	O
social	O
support	O
actually	O
benefits	O
your	O
mental	O
health	O
,	O
health	O
behaviors	O
,	O
and	O
physical	O
health	O
.	O
in	O
fact	O
,	O
scientists	O
in	O
the	O
field	O
of	O
psychoneuroimmunology	O
,	O
the	O
study	O
of	O
how	O
social	O
and	O
psychological	O
factors	O
impact	O
the	O
immune	O
system	O
,	O
have	O
found	O
that	O
having	O
strong	O
social	O
connections	O
strengthens	O
the	O
immune	O
system	O
and	O
may	O
significantly	O
increase	O
longevity	O
.	O
conversely	O
,	O
social	O
isolation	O
and	O
non-supportive	O
social	O
interactions	O
can	O
result	O
in	O
poor	O
immune	O
system	O
functioning	O
.	O
studies	O
show	O
that	O
,	O
holding	O
other	O
factors	O
that	O
may	O
influence	O
mortality	O
constant	O
,	O
the	O
risk	O
of	O
death	O
among	O
individuals	O
with	O
fewer	O
social	O
ties	O
is	O
more	O
than	O
twice	O
the	O
risk	O
of	O
death	O
among	O
those	O
with	O
the	O
most	O
social	O
connections	O
.	O
additionally	O
,	O
behavioral	O
factors	O
,	O
such	O
as	O
concern	O
for	O
other	O
people	O
create	O
incentives	O
to	O
stay	O
healthy	O
.	O
social	O
networks	O
facilitate	O
health	O
information	O
sharing	O
and	O
establish	O
health	O
behavior	O
norms	O
,	O
so	O
if	O
you	O
’	O
ve	O
been	O
eager	O
to	O
try	O
out	O
a	O
new	O
exercise	O
routine	O
,	O
exercise	O
class	O
,	O
or	O
diet	O
,	O
ask	O
others	O
to	O
join	O
you—you	O
’	O
ll	O
have	O
more	O
fun	O
with	O
friends	O
and	O
family	O
around	O
to	O
offer	O
support	O
and	O
share	O
the	O
experience	O
,	O
and	O
you	O
will	O
build	O
new	O
memories	O
with	O
those	O
close	O
to	O
you	O
.	O
by	O
spending	O
quality	O
time	O
with	O
your	O
friends	O
and	O
family	O
and	O
engaging	O
them	O
in	O
fun	O
,	O
healthy	O
activities	O
,	O
such	O
as	O
a	O
walk	O
,	O
hike	O
,	O
or	O
game	O
,	O
you	O
’	O
ll	O
give	O
yourself	O
and	O
others	O
an	O
important	O
ingredient	O
of	O
the	O
gift	O
of	O
good	O
health	O
.	O
8	O
)	O
stress	O
busters	O
and	O
mindfulness	O
stress	O
can	O
negatively	O
impact	O
your	O
mental	O
and	O
physical	O
health	O
,	O
so	O
if	O
you	O
feel	O
overwhelmed	O
during	O
the	O
holidays	O
,	O
try	O
to	O
reflect	O
on	O
what	O
might	O
be	O
bothering	O
you	O
,	O
and	O
take	O
time	O
to	O
remedy	O
the	O
problem	O
.	O
perhaps	O
having	O
some	O
alone	O
time	O
,	O
watching	O
a	O
favorite	O
movie	O
,	O
reading	O
a	O
book	O
,	O
listening	O
to	O
music	O
or	O
taking	O
a	O
peaceful	O
walk	O
will	O
help	O
you	O
relax	O
and	O
enjoy	O
this	O
busy	O
season	O
.	O
set	O
aside	O
time	O
for	O
a	O
yoga	O
routine	O
,	O
or	O
head	O
to	O
the	O
gym	O
,	O
as	O
physical	O
activity	O
can	O
be	O
an	O
effective	O
way	O
to	O
reduce	O
stress	O
.	O
also	O
consider	O
practicing	O
mindfulness	O
,	O
“	O
a	O
state	O
of	O
active	O
,	O
open	O
attention	O
on	O
the	O
present	O
,	O
”	O
as	O
a	O
method	O
of	O
stress-reduction	O
.	O
there	O
’	O
s	O
been	O
a	O
lot	O
of	O
news	O
about	O
the	O
benefits	O
of	O
mindfulness	O
for	O
a	O
reason—it	O
has	O
been	O
shown	O
to	O
reduce	O
anxiety	O
and	O
stress	O
,	O
help	O
with	O
weight	O
loss	O
,	O
and	O
improve	O
sleep	O
.	O
during	O
the	O
holidays	O
,	O
mindfulness	O
can	O
be	O
a	O
wonderful	O
tool	O
to	O
help	O
you	O
stay	O
on	O
track	O
with	O
your	O
diet	O
,	O
exercise	O
and	O
sleep	O
goals	O
.	O
as	O
you	O
begin	O
the	O
new	O
year	O
,	O
practicing	O
mindfulness	O
can	O
help	O
you	O
reduce	O
stress	O
and	O
reflect	O
most	O
on	O
what	O
provides	O
you	O
with	O
fulfillment	O
and	O
contentment	O
.	O
try	O
it	O
out—you	O
may	O
be	O
surprised	O
by	O
how	O
many	O
of	O
life	O
’	O
s	O
ups	O
and	O
downs	O
are	O
in	O
your	O
control	O
.	O
learn	O
more	O
about	O
mindfulness	O
and	O
how	O
to	O
practice	O
it	O
here	O
.	O
9	O
)	O
be	O
realistic	O
many	O
people	O
spend	O
a	O
lot	O
of	O
their	O
time	O
trying	O
to	O
make	O
the	O
holidays	O
perfect	O
in	O
every	O
way	O
,	O
but	O
this	O
year	O
,	O
take	O
a	O
step	O
back	O
and	O
relax	O
.	O
set	O
realistic	O
goals	O
for	O
yourself	O
,	O
and	O
don	O
’	O
t	O
expect	O
that	O
you	O
will	O
find	O
the	O
perfect	O
gift	O
for	O
everyone	O
or	O
make	O
an	O
award	O
winning	O
holiday	O
dinner	O
.	O
focus	O
on	O
weight	O
maintenance	O
rather	O
than	O
weight	O
loss	O
,	O
and	O
don	O
’	O
t	O
punish	O
yourself	O
if	O
you	O
indulge	O
every	O
now	O
and	O
again	O
.	O
when	O
brainstorming	O
your	O
new	O
year	O
’	O
s	O
resolutions	O
,	O
think	O
of	O
one	O
or	O
two	O
realistic	O
,	O
achievable	O
goals	O
that	O
are	O
adaptable	O
to	O
your	O
lifestyle	O
and	O
daily	O
schedule	O
,	O
and	O
you	O
’	O
ll	O
be	O
much	O
more	O
likely	O
to	O
be	O
successful—research	O
finds	O
that	O
only	O
8	O
%	O
of	O
americans	O
achieve	O
their	O
resolutions	O
.	O
consistently	O
track	O
the	O
progress	O
of	O
your	O
resolutions	O
,	O
and	O
if	O
you	O
have	O
a	O
slight	O
setback	O
,	O
don	O
’	O
t	O
give	O
up	O
.	O
perseverance	O
pays	O
off	O
!	O
10	O
)	O
get	O
enough	O
sleep	O
between	O
traveling	O
,	O
shopping	O
,	O
attending	O
holiday	O
events	O
and	O
seeing	O
family	O
and	O
friends	O
,	O
getting	O
enough	O
sleep	O
during	O
the	O
holiday	O
season	O
can	O
be	O
difficult	O
.	O
yet	O
getting	O
a	O
good	O
night	O
’	O
s	O
rest	O
will	O
leave	O
you	O
refreshed	O
for	O
the	O
next	O
day	O
’	O
s	O
festive	O
events	O
,	O
help	O
reduce	O
stress	O
,	O
and	O
improve	O
your	O
overall	O
health	O
.	O
most	O
adults	O
require	O
7	O
to	O
8	O
hours	O
of	O
sleep	O
each	O
night	O
.	O
whether	O
you	O
are	O
away	O
from	O
home	O
during	O
the	O
holidays	O
or	O
hosting	O
guests	O
,	O
prioritize	O
maintaining	O
a	O
regular	O
bedtime	O
routine	O
,	O
and	O
avoid	O
caffeine	O
,	O
alcohol	O
,	O
heavy	O
meals	O
,	O
exercise	O
and	O
looking	O
at	O
your	O
computer	O
,	O
phone	O
or	O
tablet	O
right	O
before	O
bedtime	O
.	O
research	O
finds	O
that	O
artificial	O
light	O
exposure	O
between	O
dusk	O
and	O
the	O
time	O
you	O
go	O
to	O
bed	O
makes	O
it	O
more	O
difficult	O
to	O
fall	O
asleep	O
,	O
so	O
try	O
a	O
book	O
instead	O
of	O
your	O
cellphone	O
.	O
create	O
a	O
dark	O
,	O
quiet	O
,	O
and	O
comfortable	O
environment	O
to	O
help	O
you	O
fall	O
asleep	O
.	O
if	O
you	O
have	O
trouble	O
sleeping	O
,	O
listen	O
to	O
a	O
book	O
on	O
tape	O
or	O
a	O
podcast	O
that	O
can	O
help	O
you	O
fall	O
asleep	O
.	O
getting	O
adequate	O
sleep	O
will	O
give	O
you	O
a	O
boost	O
to	O
feel	O
your	O
best	O
and	O
fully	O
enjoy	O
the	O
holidays	O
.	O
11	O
)	O
fend	O
off	O
flu	O
and	O
other	O
infectious	O
diseases	O
being	O
sick	O
can	O
quickly	O
disrupt	O
your	O
holiday	O
cheer	O
.	O
with	O
increased	O
domestic	O
and	O
international	O
travel	O
during	O
the	O
holiday	O
season	O
,	O
infectious	O
diseases	O
,	O
like	O
the	O
flu	O
,	O
can	O
spread	O
,	O
so	O
keep	O
safe	O
by	O
practicing	O
good	O
hygiene	O
,	O
washing	O
your	O
hands	O
,	O
covering	O
coughs	O
,	O
avoiding	O
close	O
contact	O
with	O
people	O
who	O
are	O
ill	O
,	O
carrying	O
hand	O
sanitizer	O
or	O
sanitizing	O
wipes	O
,	O
and	O
getting	O
vaccinated	O
for	O
seasonal	O
flu	O
now	O
.	O
immunization	O
is	O
the	O
most	O
effective	O
way	O
to	O
prevent	O
contracting	O
the	O
flu	O
,	O
but	O
be	O
sure	O
to	O
opt	O
for	O
the	O
injectable	O
flu	O
vaccine	O
this	O
year	O
,	O
as	O
experts	O
are	O
recommending	O
against	O
the	O
nasal	O
spray	O
vaccine	O
.	O
each	O
year	O
,	O
complications	O
from	O
influenza	O
virus	O
infection	O
,	O
including	O
pneumonia	O
,	O
bronchitis	O
,	O
sinus	O
and	O
ear	O
infections	O
,	O
result	O
in	O
more	O
than	O
200,000	O
hospitalizations	O
and	O
between	O
3,300	O
and	O
49,000	O
deaths	O
annually	O
in	O
the	O
united	LOC
states	LOC
.	O
learn	O
more	O
about	O
the	O
flu	O
vaccine	O
,	O
and	O
check	O
out	O
www.flu.gov	O
to	O
find	O
ways	O
to	O
protect	O
you	O
and	O
your	O
family	O
from	O
this	O
illness	O
during	O
the	O
holidays	O
.	O
if	O
you	O
are	O
travelling	O
internationally	O
,	O
speak	O
with	O
your	O
doctor	O
about	O
any	O
necessary	O
immunizations	O
or	O
health	O
safety	O
precautions	O
that	O
might	O
be	O
relevant	O
for	O
your	O
destination	O
.	O
check	O
out	O
the	O
cdc	O
’	O
s	O
travel	O
page	O
for	O
information	O
about	O
how	O
to	O
protect	O
yourself	O
from	O
infectious	O
diseases	O
during	O
your	O
holiday	O
travels	O
.	O
12	O
)	O
travel	O
safely	O
travel	O
safely	O
this	O
holiday	O
season	O
by	O
following	O
this	O
roadmap	O
:	O
1	O
)	O
if	O
you	O
are	O
driving	O
,	O
wear	O
a	O
seatbelt	O
,	O
stay	O
calm	O
while	O
in	O
holiday	O
traffic	O
,	O
and	O
get	O
adequate	O
sleep	O
before	O
getting	O
behind	O
the	O
wheel	O
;	O
2	O
)	O
never	O
drink	O
or	O
use	O
other	O
substances	O
and	O
then	O
drive	O
;	O
and	O
3	O
)	O
avoid	O
fatigue	O
on	O
long	O
road	O
trips	O
by	O
bringing	O
a	O
companion	O
with	O
you	O
who	O
can	O
take	O
over	O
if	O
you	O
feel	O
tired	O
and	O
by	O
scheduling	O
regular	O
stops	O
every	O
two	O
hours	O
to	O
stretch	O
your	O
legs	O
and	O
have	O
a	O
snack	O
.	O
research	O
shows	O
that	O
being	O
awake	O
for	O
at	O
least	O
18	O
hours	O
is	O
equivalent	O
to	O
having	O
a	O
blood	O
alcohol	O
content	O
level	O
of	O
0.05	O
%	O
.	O
recent	O
studies	O
estimate	O
that	O
driver	O
fatigue	O
is	O
linked	O
to	O
100,000	O
automobile	O
crashes	O
annually	O
.	O
if	O
you	O
are	O
flying	O
,	O
getting	O
enough	O
rest	O
and	O
drinking	O
plenty	O
of	O
water	O
is	O
important	O
,	O
especially	O
if	O
you	O
are	O
crossing	O
time	O
zones	O
.	O
13	O
)	O
get	O
insured	O
having	O
health	O
insurance	O
is	O
critical	O
to	O
receiving	O
the	O
medical	O
care	O
you	O
need	O
.	O
in	O
2015	O
,	O
one	O
in	O
five	O
americans	O
without	O
insurance	O
was	O
unable	O
to	O
receive	O
necessary	O
health	O
care	O
,	O
including	O
preventive	O
services	O
,	O
because	O
of	O
high	O
medical	O
costs	O
.	O
53	O
%	O
of	O
uninsured	O
adults	O
report	O
having	O
problems	O
paying	O
medical	O
bills	O
significantly	O
straining	O
their	O
financial	O
stability	O
,	O
as	O
compared	O
to	O
20	O
%	O
of	O
adults	O
with	O
insurance	O
.	O
thanks	O
to	O
the	O
passage	O
of	O
the	O
patient	O
protection	O
and	O
affordable	O
care	O
act	O
of	O
2010	O
(	O
aca	O
)	O
,	O
the	O
rate	O
of	O
uninsured	O
americans	O
is	O
at	O
an	O
all-time	O
low	O
of	O
8.6	O
%	O
.	O
the	O
aca	O
’	O
s	O
“	O
patient	O
’	O
s	O
bill	O
of	O
rights	O
”	O
prohibits	O
insurance	O
companies	O
from	O
instituting	O
lifetime	O
and	O
annual	O
limits	O
on	O
coverage	O
,	O
dropping	O
patients	O
who	O
file	O
reimbursement	O
claims	O
,	O
and	O
spending	O
more	O
than	O
20	O
percent	O
of	O
premium	O
payments	O
on	O
administrative	O
costs	O
.	O
important	O
victories	O
of	O
the	O
legislation	O
include	O
provisions	O
that	O
prohibit	O
insurance	O
companies	O
from	O
denying	O
insurance	O
coverage	O
to	O
people	O
because	O
of	O
pre-existing	O
conditions	O
or	O
gender	O
,	O
allowing	O
young	O
adults	O
to	O
stay	O
on	O
their	O
parents	O
’	O
health	O
insurance	O
until	O
age	O
twenty-six	O
,	O
providing	O
free	O
preventive	O
care	O
services	O
including	O
mammograms	O
and	O
colonoscopies	O
,	O
and	O
ensuring	O
parity	O
in	O
coverage	O
of	O
mental	O
and	O
physical	O
illnesses	O
.	O
additionally	O
,	O
the	O
aca	O
expanded	O
eligibility	O
for	O
the	O
medicaid	ORG
program	O
in	O
states	O
to	O
provide	O
coverage	O
for	O
more	O
individuals	O
with	O
incomes	O
at	O
or	O
below	O
138	O
percent	O
of	O
the	O
poverty	O
level	O
(	O
approximately	O
$	O
16,243	O
annually	O
for	O
an	O
individual	O
and	O
$	O
33,465	O
for	O
a	O
family	O
of	O
four	O
in	O
2016	O
)	O
.	O
since	O
the	O
passage	O
of	O
the	O
aca	O
in	O
2010	O
,	O
an	O
estimated	O
20	O
million	O
americans	O
,	O
including	O
more	O
than	O
6	O
million	O
young	O
adults	O
,	O
have	O
gained	O
health	O
insurance	O
coverage	O
.	O
however	O
,	O
despite	O
this	O
progress	O
,	O
approximately	O
29	O
million	O
people	O
—1	O
in	O
11	O
americans—remain	O
without	O
health	O
insurance	O
.	O
the	O
health	ORG
insurance	ORG
marketplace	ORG
is	O
currently	O
in	O
a	O
period	O
of	O
open	O
enrollment	O
that	O
lasts	O
until	O
january	O
31	O
,	O
2017	O
,	O
so	O
if	O
you	O
are	O
uninsured	O
,	O
give	O
yourself	O
a	O
lifesaving	O
gift	O
by	O
shopping	O
for	O
the	O
best	O
plan	O
for	O
you	O
on	O
www.healthcare.gov	O
.	O
14	O
)	O
remember	O
those	O
in	O
need	O
remember	O
to	O
think	O
of	O
those	O
who	O
are	O
in	O
need	O
this	O
holiday	O
season	O
.	O
one	O
in	O
seven	O
americans	O
experiences	O
food	O
insecurity	O
,	O
and	O
in	O
2015	O
,	O
15.8	O
million	O
(	O
12.7	O
percent	O
)	O
u.s.	LOC
households	O
were	O
food	O
insecure	O
.	O
during	O
the	O
holidays	O
,	O
feel	O
gratitude	O
for	O
what	O
you	O
have	O
and	O
be	O
charitable	O
to	O
those	O
who	O
are	O
less	O
fortunate	O
.	O
help	O
serve	O
in	O
a	O
food	O
pantry	O
in	O
your	O
area	O
,	O
or	O
make	O
a	O
donation	O
to	O
a	O
local	O
charity	O
.	O
visit	O
the	O
snap	O
to	O
health	O
website	O
to	O
learn	O
more	O
about	O
how	O
you	O
can	O
contribute	O
to	O
preventing	O
hunger	O
in	O
your	O
community	O
and	O
in	O
our	O
country	O
.	O
visit	O
the	O
charity	O
navigator	O
website	O
to	O
learn	O
how	O
you	O
can	O
give	O
to	O
charities	O
that	O
have	O
a	O
big	O
impact	O
on	O
the	O
lives	O
of	O
the	O
people	O
they	O
serve	O
.	O
make	O
giving	O
to	O
others	O
a	O
year-round	O
priority	O
.	O
safeguarding	O
your	O
health	O
is	O
the	O
most	O
enduring	O
gift	O
you	O
can	O
give	O
yourself	O
this	O
holiday	O
season	O
.	O
health	O
impacts	O
all	O
facets	O
of	O
life	O
.	O
in	O
fact	O
,	O
studies	O
have	O
found	O
that	O
good	O
health	O
is	O
associated	O
with	O
increased	O
happiness	O
,	O
higher	O
levels	O
of	O
workplace	O
productivity	O
,	O
and	O
longer	O
life	O
expectancy	O
.	O
integrating	O
the	O
fourteen	O
ingredients	O
discussed	O
above	O
into	O
your	O
lifestyle	O
will	O
help	O
ensure	O
you	O
have	O
a	O
healthy	O
and	O
happy	O
holiday	O
season	O
and	O
a	O
fulfilling	O
,	O
productive	O
new	O
year	O
.	O
treat	O
yourself	O
to	O
the	O
gift	O
of	O
good	O
health	O
,	O
and	O
its	O
effects	O
will	O
last	O
for	O
years	O
to	O
come	O
!	O
rear	O
admiral	O
susan	PERS
blumenthal	PERS
,	O
m.d.	O
,	O
m.p.a	O
.	O
(	O
ret	O
.	O
)	O
is	O
the	O
public	O
health	O
editor	O
of	O
the	O
huffington	ORG
post	ORG
.	O
she	O
is	O
also	O
a	O
clinical	O
professor	O
at	O
tufts	O
and	O
georgetown	ORG
schools	ORG
of	ORG
medicine	ORG
,	O
a	O
senior	O
fellow	O
in	O
health	O
policy	O
at	O
new	LOC
america	LOC
and	O
senior	O
policy	O
and	O
medical	O
advisor	O
at	O
amfar	ORG
,	O
the	O
foundation	O
for	O
aids	O
research	O
.	O
admiral	O
blumenthal	PERS
served	O
for	O
more	O
than	O
20	O
years	O
in	O
senior	O
health	O
leadership	O
positions	O
in	O
the	O
federal	O
government	O
in	O
the	O
administrations	O
of	O
four	O
u.s.	LOC
presidents	O
including	O
as	O
assistant	O
surgeon	O
general	O
of	O
the	O
united	LOC
states	LOC
,	O
the	O
first	O
deputy	ORG
assistant	O
secretary	O
of	O
women	O
’	O
s	O
health	O
,	O
and	O
as	O
senior	O
global	O
health	O
advisor	O
in	O
the	O
u.s.	ORG
department	ORG
of	ORG
health	ORG
and	ORG
human	ORG
services	ORG
.	O
she	O
also	O
served	O
as	O
a	O
white	ORG
house	ORG
advisor	O
on	O
health	O
.	O
prior	O
to	O
these	O
positions	O
,	O
dr.	O
blumenthal	PERS
was	O
chief	O
of	O
the	O
behavioral	ORG
medicine	ORG
and	ORG
basic	ORG
prevention	ORG
research	ORG
branch	ORG
and	O
chair	O
of	O
the	O
health	ORG
and	ORG
behavior	ORG
coordinating	ORG
committee	ORG
at	O
the	O
national	ORG
institutes	ORG
of	ORG
health	ORG
(	O
nih	O
)	O
.	O
she	O
has	O
chaired	O
many	O
national	O
and	O
global	O
commissions	O
and	O
conferences	O
and	O
is	O
the	O
author	O
of	O
many	O
scientific	O
publications	O
.	O
admiral	O
blumenthal	PERS
has	O
received	O
numerous	O
awards	O
including	O
honorary	O
doctorates	O
and	O
has	O
been	O
decorated	O
with	O
the	O
highest	O
medals	O
of	O
the	O
u.s.	LOC
public	ORG
health	ORG
service	ORG
for	O
her	O
pioneering	O
leadership	O
and	O
significant	O
contributions	O
to	O
advancing	O
health	O
in	O
the	O
united	LOC
states	LOC
and	O
worldwide	O
.	O
named	O
by	O
the	O
new	ORG
york	ORG
times	ORG
,	O
the	O
national	ORG
library	ORG
of	ORG
medicine	ORG
and	O
the	O
medical	ORG
herald	ORG
as	O
one	O
of	O
the	O
most	O
influential	O
women	O
in	O
medicine	O
,	O
dr.	O
blumenthal	PERS
was	O
named	O
the	O
2009	O
health	O
leader	O
of	O
the	O
year	O
by	O
the	O
commissioned	ORG
officers	ORG
association	ORG
and	O
as	O
a	O
rock	O
star	O
of	O
science	O
by	O
the	O
geoffrey	ORG
beene	ORG
foundation	ORG
.	O
she	O
is	O
the	O
recipient	O
of	O
the	O
rosalind	O
franklin	O
centennial	O
life	O
in	O
discovery	O
award	O
.	O
katherine	PERS
perez	PERS
graduated	O
with	O
honors	O
from	O
princeton	ORG
university	ORG
in	O
2016	O
with	O
a	O
degree	O
from	O
the	O
woodrow	ORG
wilson	ORG
school	ORG
of	ORG
public	ORG
and	ORG
international	ORG
affairs	ORG
and	O
minors	O
in	O
global	O
health	O
policy	O
and	O
african	O
studies	O
.	O
she	O
has	O
previously	O
interned	O
at	O
the	ORG
public	ORG
health	ORG
foundation	ORG
of	ORG
india	ORG
in	O
new	LOC
delhi	LOC
,	O
india	LOC
,	O
where	O
she	O
worked	O
on	O
vaccine	O
cold	O
chain	O
logistics	O
,	O
and	O
at	O
the	O
oxford	ORG
university	ORG
clinical	O
research	O
unit	O
in	O
ho	LOC
chi	LOC
minh	LOC
city	LOC
,	O
vietnam	LOC
,	O
where	O
she	O
studied	O
the	O
etiology	O
of	O
emerging	O
viral	O
infections	O
.	O
her	O
senior	O
thesis	O
at	O
princeton	ORG
examined	O
the	O
economic	O
and	O
societal	O
impacts	O
of	O
the	O
2014	O
ebola	O
outbreak	O
in	O
west	LOC
africa	LOC
and	O
integrated	O
economic	O
,	O
historical	O
and	O
anthropological	O
analysis	O
in	O
order	O
to	O
critically	O
assess	O
existent	O
health	O
policies	O
to	O
offer	O
recommendations	O
for	O
addressing	O
future	O
outbreaks	O
of	O
infectious	O
disease	O
on	O
both	O
a	O
national	O
and	O
a	O
global	O
scale	O
.	O
katherine	PERS
currently	O
serves	O
as	O
a	O
health	O
policy	O
intern	O
at	O
new	LOC
america	LOC
in	O
washington	LOC
,	O
d.c	O
.	O
mia	O
in	O
the	O
medical	O
revolution	ORG
:	O
a	O
sense	O
of	O
urgency	O
there	O
was	O
a	O
moment	O
yesterday	O
when	O
vice	O
president	O
joe	PERS
biden	PERS
’	O
s	O
words	O
got	O
caught	O
in	O
his	O
throat	O
.	O
he	O
was	O
addressing	O
an	O
intimate	O
crowd	O
at	O
the	O
startup	O
health	ORG
café	ORG
in	O
san	LOC
francisco	LOC
about	O
the	O
white	ORG
house	ORG
cancer	O
moonshot	O
—the	O
widely	O
praised	O
initiative	O
he	O
had	O
begun	O
leading	O
just	O
a	O
year	O
ago	O
and	O
that	O
,	O
only	O
days	O
from	O
now	O
,	O
was	O
slated	O
to	O
lose	O
its	O
potent	O
“	O
white	ORG
house	ORG
”	O
prefix—when	O
he	O
began	O
talking	O
about	O
his	O
eldest	O
son	O
.	O
beau	PERS
biden	PERS
had	O
been	O
the	O
state	O
of	O
delaware	LOC
’	O
s	O
attorney	O
general	O
and	O
a	O
decorated	O
veteran	O
who	O
had	O
served	O
in	O
iraq	LOC
.	O
in	O
2013	O
,	O
a	O
few	O
years	O
after	O
returning	O
from	O
the	O
war	O
,	O
the	O
forty-four	O
year	O
old	O
was	O
diagnosed	O
with	O
stage	O
4	O
glioblastoma	O
,	O
a	O
diagnosis	O
that	O
the	O
vice	O
president	O
said	O
his	O
entire	O
family	O
“	O
knew	O
was	O
the	O
equivalent	O
of	O
a	O
death	O
sentence.	O
”	O
so	O
joe	PERS
,	O
the	O
dad	O
,	O
set	O
out	O
to	O
learn	O
everything	O
he	O
could	O
about	O
the	O
disease	O
during	O
his	O
son	O
’	O
s	O
year-and-a-half	O
fight	O
to	O
survive	O
.	O
“	O
the	O
most	O
important	O
thing	O
i	O
learned	O
,	O
”	O
he	O
recounted	O
,	O
“	O
was	O
that	O
we	O
’	O
ve	O
reached—you	O
all	O
have	O
reached	O
in	O
science—an	O
inflection	O
point	O
in	O
cancer….i	O
found	O
myself	O
realizing	O
that	O
maybe	O
,	O
although	O
we	O
couldn	O
’	O
t	O
save	O
our	O
son	O
,	O
that	O
maybe	O
we	O
could…	O
''	O
that	O
’	O
s	O
when	O
the	O
words	O
disappeared	O
for	O
a	O
long	O
moment	O
and	O
a	O
father	O
’	O
s	O
grief	O
took	O
over	O
.	O
in	O
a	O
day	O
in	O
which	O
investors	O
and	O
entrepreneurs	O
young	O
and	O
old	O
shared	O
business	O
cards	O
and	O
elevator	O
pitches	O
,	O
in	O
which	O
the	O
notion	O
of	O
healthcare	O
as	O
deal-making	O
and	O
commerce	O
reigned	O
supreme	O
,	O
biden	PERS
’	O
s	O
seconds-long	O
flash	O
of	O
wordlessness	O
was	O
a	O
rare	O
moment	O
of	O
clarity	O
.	O
we	O
don	O
’	O
t	O
just	O
need	O
innovation	O
.	O
or	O
investment	O
.	O
or	O
a	O
clever	O
new	O
strategy	O
.	O
we	O
need	O
a	O
change	O
in	O
the	O
circadian	O
rhythm	O
of	O
medical	O
science	O
:	O
we	O
need	O
speed	O
.	O
“	O
my	O
absolute	O
conviction	O
is	O
that	O
we	O
have	O
to	O
inject	O
an	O
overwhelming	O
sense	O
of	O
urgency	O
into	O
this	O
fight	O
,	O
”	O
biden	PERS
told	O
the	O
shoulder-to-shoulder	O
gathering	O
on	O
monday	O
afternoon	O
.	O
these	O
,	O
in	O
my	O
view	O
,	O
ought	O
to	O
be	O
the	O
guiding	O
words	O
of	O
the	O
healthcare	O
revolution	ORG
.	O
more	O
news	O
below	O
.	O
[	O
ceo_attribution	O
author=	O
''	O
clifton	PERS
leaf	PERS
''	O
email=	O
''	O
clifton.leaf	O
@	O
fortune.com	O
''	O
twitter=	O
''	O
cliftonleaf	O
''	O
]	O
digital	O
health	O
this	O
company	O
is	O
launching	O
an	O
ai-powered	O
``	O
digital	O
doctor	O
.	O
''	O
digital	O
health	O
firm	O
healthtap	ORG
today	O
announced	O
that	O
it	O
's	O
launching	O
dr	O
.	O
a.i.	O
,	O
which	O
the	O
company	O
describes	O
as	O
``	O
a	O
personal	O
artificial	O
intelligence-powered	O
'physician	O
'	O
that	O
helps	O
route	O
users	O
to	O
doctor-recommended	O
insights	O
and	O
care	O
immediately	O
.	O
''	O
healthtap	ORG
founder	O
and	O
ceo	O
ron	PERS
gutman	PERS
gave	O
me	O
a	O
personal	O
demonstration	O
of	O
how	O
the	O
tech	O
works	O
before	O
the	O
holidays	O
.	O
it	O
's	O
basically	O
a	O
far	O
more	O
advanced	O
(	O
and	O
guided	O
)	O
version	O
of	O
webmd	O
;	O
but	O
rather	O
than	O
have	O
users	O
try	O
to	O
play	O
a	O
guessing	O
game	O
matching	O
their	O
symptoms	O
with	O
thousands	O
of	O
possible	O
medical	O
conditions	O
,	O
the	O
dr.	O
a.i	O
.	O
platform	O
asks	O
a	O
series	O
of	O
directed	O
questions	O
about	O
what	O
kinds	O
of	O
symptoms	O
the	O
patient	O
is	O
experiencing	O
(	O
for	O
example	O
,	O
light-headedness	O
,	O
pain	O
in	O
a	O
certain	O
region	O
of	O
the	O
body	O
,	O
trouble	O
sleeping	O
,	O
etc	O
.	O
)	O
.	O
it	O
then	O
uses	O
real-world	O
patient	O
question	O
data	O
compiled	O
from	O
more	O
than	O
100,000	O
physicians	O
over	O
six	O
years	O
in	O
order	O
to	O
compile	O
a	O
list	O
of	O
possible	O
conditions	O
that	O
may	O
be	O
afflicting	O
the	O
patient	O
,	O
and	O
then	O
ranks	O
them	O
in	O
order	O
of	O
seriousness	O
from	O
low	O
risk	O
to	O
advising	O
an	O
emergency	O
room	O
visit	O
.	O
and	O
the	O
software	O
,	O
which	O
is	O
connected	O
to	O
healthtap	ORG
's	O
broader	O
digital	O
connection	O
services	O
to	O
physicians	O
and	O
medical	O
experts	O
,	O
can	O
even	O
connect	O
users	O
to	O
doctors	O
and	O
specialists	O
right	O
from	O
the	O
app	O
.	O
st.	ORG
jude	ORG
updates	O
heart	O
device	O
after	O
cyber	O
security	O
concerns	O
.	O
last	O
year	O
,	O
st.	ORG
jude	ORG
medical	ORG
and	O
acquirer	O
abbott	ORG
laboratories	ORG
was	O
hit	O
with	O
a	O
federal	O
government	O
probe	O
into	O
claims	O
that	O
st.	ORG
jude	ORG
's	O
popular	O
heart	O
devices	O
had	O
security	O
vulnerabilities	O
that	O
made	O
them	O
vulnerable	O
to	O
life-threatening	O
hacking	O
.	O
on	O
monday	O
,	O
abbott	ORG
announced	O
that	O
it	O
's	O
taken	O
steps	O
to	O
update	O
the	O
devices	O
'	O
cyber	O
security	O
features	O
.	O
the	O
updates	O
will	O
be	O
automatically	O
applied	O
to	O
the	O
products	O
;	O
but	O
the	O
department	ORG
of	ORG
homeland	ORG
security	ORG
's	O
industrial	O
control	O
systems	O
cyber	O
emergency	O
response	O
team	O
(	O
ics-cert	O
)	O
says	O
that	O
there	O
are	O
still	O
some	O
lingering	O
concerns	O
.	O
``	O
st.	ORG
jude	ORG
medical	ORG
is	O
continuing	O
to	O
work	O
with	O
ics-cert	O
and	O
the	O
fda	ORG
to	O
address	O
additional	O
security	O
issues	O
that	O
have	O
been	O
identified	O
,	O
''	O
said	O
the	O
agency	O
in	O
a	O
statement	O
.	O
(	O
fortune	ORG
)	O
ge	ORG
's	O
hiring	O
practices	O
in	O
saudi	O
it	O
services	O
unit	O
wins	O
it	O
an	O
ace	ORG
.	O
general	ORG
electric	ORG
has	O
been	O
awarded	O
the	O
state	ORG
department	ORG
's	O
prestigious	O
global	O
2016	O
award	O
for	O
corporate	O
excellence	O
(	O
ace	ORG
)	O
for	O
its	O
efforts	O
to	O
recruit	O
a	O
diverse	O
workforce	O
,	O
especially	O
in	O
its	O
it	O
services	O
sectors	O
,	O
in	O
countries	O
like	O
saudi	LOC
arabia	LOC
.	O
for	O
instance	O
,	O
ge	ORG
has	O
an	O
all-women	O
business	O
process	O
&	O
it	O
services	O
center	O
in	O
riyadh	LOC
that	O
employs	O
more	O
than	O
1,000	O
women	O
and	O
has	O
a	O
goal	O
of	O
eventually	O
getting	O
to	O
3,000	O
female	O
hires	O
.	O
ge	ORG
ceo	O
jeff	PERS
immelt	PERS
,	O
who	O
's	O
made	O
workforce	O
diversification	O
a	O
priority	O
for	O
the	O
company	O
,	O
argues	O
that	O
the	O
hiring	O
tactic	O
is	O
ultimately	O
a	O
win	O
for	O
everybody	O
.	O
``	O
the	O
all-women	O
business	O
process	O
center	O
is	O
an	O
innovative	O
solution	O
that	O
enabled	O
us	O
not	O
only	O
to	O
provide	O
career	O
opportunities	O
for	O
the	O
well-educated	O
and	O
talented	O
saudi	O
females	O
but	O
also	O
to	O
build	O
in-country	O
capabilities	O
that	O
’	O
ll	O
have	O
lasting	O
impact	O
,	O
in	O
what	O
is	O
an	O
important	O
market	O
going	O
through	O
transformative	O
changes	O
,	O
''	O
he	O
said	O
in	O
a	O
statement	O
.	O
as	O
cliff	O
's	O
written	O
before	O
,	O
digital	O
health	O
firms	O
in	O
general	O
could	O
use	O
a	O
whole	O
lot	O
more	O
female	O
talent	O
.	O
(	O
healthcare	O
it	O
news	O
)	O
indications	O
teva	ORG
ceo	O
explains	O
why	O
the	O
company	O
's	O
sales	O
guidance	O
was	O
off	O
by	O
$	O
1	O
billion	O
.	O
drug	O
giant	O
teva	ORG
had	O
to	O
make	O
a	O
pretty	O
serious	O
revision	O
to	O
its	O
2017	O
guidance	O
last	O
week	O
,	O
cutting	O
more	O
than	O
$	O
1	O
billion	O
off	O
of	O
its	O
sales	O
forecast	O
for	O
the	O
year	O
.	O
at	O
the	O
ongoing	O
j.p.	ORG
morgan	ORG
healthcare	ORG
conference	O
in	O
san	LOC
francisco	LOC
,	O
ceo	O
erez	PERS
vigodman	PERS
offered	O
an	O
explanation	O
:	O
the	O
snafu	O
can	O
be	O
traced	O
to	O
a	O
hot	O
hand	O
fallacy	O
of	O
sorts	O
where	O
teva	ORG
projected	O
new	O
product	O
sales	O
to	O
keep	O
up	O
the	O
robust	O
pace	O
of	O
the	O
past	O
five	O
years	O
.	O
but	O
that	O
did	O
n't	O
happen	O
in	O
2016	O
,	O
leading	O
to	O
inflated	O
expectations	O
in	O
the	O
initial	O
july	O
sales	O
forecast	O
.	O
in	O
fact	O
,	O
new	O
launches	O
added	O
just	O
$	O
140	O
million	O
to	O
teva	ORG
's	O
coffers	O
last	O
year	O
.	O
``	O
[	O
teva	ORG
will	O
]	O
do	O
everything	O
in	O
our	O
power	O
to	O
make	O
sure	O
that	O
something	O
like	O
that	O
does	O
not	O
happen	O
again	O
,	O
''	O
said	O
vigodman	PERS
at	O
jpm	O
.	O
still	O
,	O
the	O
sheer	O
scope	O
of	O
the	O
guidance	O
revision	O
has	O
some	O
analysts	O
questioning	O
whether	O
teva	ORG
's	O
personnel	O
is	O
suited	O
to	O
the	O
task	O
of	O
properly	O
accounting	O
for	O
and	O
projecting	O
the	O
drug	O
maker	O
's	O
business	O
.	O
(	O
fiercepharma	O
)	O
more	O
details	O
emerge	O
about	O
moderna	O
's	O
pipeline	O
strategy	O
.	O
moderna	O
therapeutics	O
has	O
no	O
shortage	O
of	O
cash	O
.	O
in	O
fact	O
,	O
at	O
$	O
5	O
billion	O
,	O
it	O
's	O
the	O
most	O
highly	O
valued	O
private	O
biotech	O
in	O
the	O
country	O
.	O
but	O
the	O
secretive	O
firm	O
,	O
which	O
is	O
building	O
out	O
a	O
highly	O
experimental	O
messenger	O
rna	O
(	O
mrna	O
)	O
drug	O
platform	O
,	O
has	O
plenty	O
of	O
skeptics	O
,	O
including	O
stat	O
's	O
damian	PERS
garde	PERS
.	O
garde	PERS
and	O
others	O
have	O
pointed	O
to	O
key	O
personnel	O
departures	O
and	O
a	O
lack	O
of	O
evidence	O
about	O
exactly	O
how	O
effective	O
moderna	O
's	O
pipeline	O
prospects	O
might	O
be	O
.	O
at	O
the	O
j.p.	ORG
morgan	ORG
healthcare	ORG
conference	O
,	O
the	O
firm	O
pulled	O
back	O
the	O
curtains	O
on	O
its	O
strategy	O
a	O
bit	O
,	O
revealing	O
that	O
it	O
's	O
concentrating	O
on	O
five	O
clinical	O
vaccines	O
programs	O
as	O
a	O
way	O
of	O
introducing	O
its	O
platform	O
to	O
the	O
market	O
.	O
but	O
that	O
decision	O
is	O
also	O
raising	O
some	O
eyebrows	O
since	O
vaccines	O
are	O
inherently	O
a	O
low-margin	O
business	O
.	O
moderna	O
,	O
for	O
its	O
part	O
,	O
argues	O
that	O
it	O
's	O
playing	O
the	O
long	O
game	O
by	O
demonstrating	O
that	O
mrna	O
is	O
a	O
feasible	O
drug	O
delivery	O
method	O
that	O
can	O
be	O
used	O
to	O
make	O
a	O
wide	O
variety	O
of	O
treatments	O
.	O
(	O
endpoints	O
)	O
kite	ORG
plots	O
big	O
moves	O
into	O
asian	O
markets	O
as	O
pioneering	O
car-t	O
drug	O
nears	O
an	O
fda	ORG
filing	O
.	O
kite	ORG
pharma	ORG
,	O
which	O
is	O
locked	O
in	O
a	O
race	O
with	O
pharma	O
giant	O
novartis	ORG
to	O
be	O
the	O
first	O
company	O
with	O
an	O
approved	O
car-t	O
therapy	O
on	O
the	O
market	O
,	O
is	O
partnering	O
with	O
japan	LOC
's	O
daiichi	ORG
sankyo	O
in	O
a	O
$	O
250	O
million	O
deal	O
that	O
will	O
net	O
kite	ORG
$	O
50	O
million	O
in	O
upfront	O
cash	O
.	O
car-t	O
is	O
a	O
hot	O
new	O
space	O
in	O
cancer	O
treatment	O
which	O
involves	O
modifying	O
a	O
patient	O
's	O
immune	O
t-cells	O
to	O
target	O
cancers	O
before	O
infusing	O
the	O
re-engineered	O
cells	O
back	O
into	O
the	O
body	O
.	O
it	O
's	O
shown	O
particular	O
promise	O
in	O
blood	O
cancers	O
like	O
non-hodgkin	O
lymphoma	O
,	O
which	O
kite	ORG
is	O
targeting	O
for	O
its	O
first	O
car-t	O
approval	O
.	O
the	O
daiichi	ORG
partnership	O
will	O
give	O
kite	ORG
access	O
to	O
the	O
japanese	O
market	O
as	O
well	O
as	O
the	O
firm	O
's	O
manufacturing	O
assets	O
(	O
car-t	O
drugs	O
are	O
particularly	O
hard	O
to	O
scale	O
thanks	O
to	O
their	O
highly	O
personalized	O
nature	O
)	O
.	O
(	O
reuters	ORG
)	O
the	O
big	O
picture	O
the	O
global	O
cost	O
of	O
smoking	O
is	O
$	O
1	O
trillion	O
per	O
year	O
.	O
here	O
's	O
a	O
whopper	O
of	O
a	O
stat	O
:	O
a	O
new	O
study	O
by	O
the	O
national	ORG
cancer	ORG
institute	ORG
(	O
nci	ORG
)	O
finds	O
that	O
the	O
cost	O
of	O
smoking	O
to	O
the	O
global	O
economy	O
is	O
more	O
than	O
$	O
1	O
trillion	O
per	O
year	O
,	O
easily	O
dwarfing	O
the	O
approximately	O
$	O
269	O
billion	O
in	O
tobacco	O
taxes	O
collected	O
between	O
2013	O
and	O
2014	O
.	O
and	O
continued	O
smoking	O
growth	O
in	O
poorer	O
nations	O
will	O
contribute	O
to	O
millions	O
of	O
more	O
tobacco-related	O
deaths	O
by	O
2030	O
.	O
``	O
the	O
number	O
of	O
tobacco-related	O
deaths	O
is	O
projected	O
to	O
increase	O
from	O
about	O
6	O
million	O
deaths	O
annually	O
to	O
about	O
8	O
million	O
annually	O
by	O
2030	O
,	O
with	O
more	O
than	O
80	O
%	O
of	O
these	O
occurring	O
in	O
lmics	O
(	O
low-	O
and	O
middle-income	O
countries	O
)	O
,	O
''	O
wrote	O
the	O
study	O
authors	O
.	O
the	O
$	O
1	O
trillion-plus	O
figure	O
is	O
a	O
combination	O
of	O
preventable	O
smoking-related	O
health	O
care	O
costs	O
and	O
lost	O
productivity	O
.	O
(	O
fortune	ORG
)	O
unitedhealth	ORG
continues	O
its	O
health	O
services	O
buyout	O
spree	O
.	O
health	O
care	O
giant	O
unitedhealth	ORG
group	ORG
is	O
continuing	O
the	O
buying	O
spree	O
for	O
its	O
optum	ORG
health	O
services	O
unit	O
,	O
snapping	O
up	O
the	O
major	O
surgical	O
care	O
provider	O
surgical	ORG
care	ORG
affiliates	ORG
for	O
$	O
2.3	O
billion	O
.	O
it	O
's	O
the	O
latest	O
in	O
a	O
series	O
of	O
horizontal	O
buyouts	O
in	O
the	O
health	O
care	O
field	O
for	O
unitedhealth	ORG
group	ORG
,	O
which	O
already	O
contains	O
the	O
insurance	O
giant	O
unitedhealth	ORG
and	O
a	O
burgeoning	O
roster	O
of	O
actual	O
primary	O
care	O
and	O
ambulatory	O
service	O
providers	O
.	O
(	O
wall	ORG
street	ORG
journal	ORG
)	O
is	O
it	O
ok	O
for	O
a	O
bunch	O
of	O
men	O
to	O
lead	O
a	O
“	O
women	O
in	O
the	O
workforce	O
”	O
initiative	O
?	O
president	O
trump	PERS
has	O
just	O
appointed	O
two	O
men	O
to	O
head	O
up	O
his	O
women	O
in	O
the	O
workplace	O
initiative	O
.	O
the	O
reactions	O
are	O
predictable	O
:	O
how	O
can	O
men	O
appropriately	O
represent	O
women	O
?	O
but	O
that	O
is	O
the	O
typical	O
misframing	O
of	O
the	O
gender	O
issue	O
.	O
gender	O
equality	O
is	O
not	O
a	O
“	O
women	O
’	O
s	O
issue	O
”	O
—	O
it	O
’	O
s	O
a	O
huge	O
political	O
,	O
economic	O
,	O
and	O
social	O
opportunity	O
.	O
it	O
is	O
a	O
massive	O
business	O
issue	O
that	O
more	O
than	O
75	O
%	O
of	O
corporate	O
ceos	O
currently	O
put	O
on	O
their	O
agenda	O
of	O
top	O
10	O
issues	O
.	O
research	O
shows	O
that	O
gender	O
balance	O
happens	O
in	O
companies	O
only	O
if	O
it	O
is	O
personally	O
and	O
forcefully	O
led	O
by	O
the	O
ceo	O
.	O
the	O
reality	O
is	O
that	O
many	O
of	O
the	O
companies	O
starting	O
to	O
look	O
truly	O
balanced	O
are	O
or	O
were	O
led	O
by	O
men	O
.	O
successful	O
gender	O
balancing	O
requires	O
convincing	O
the	O
majority	O
of	O
your	O
employees	O
that	O
it	O
’	O
s	O
a	O
good	O
idea	O
.	O
smart	O
ceos	O
of	O
male-dominated	O
companies	O
know	O
that	O
the	O
real	O
push	O
on	O
gender	O
balance	O
(	O
especially	O
in	O
leadership	O
)	O
is	O
getting	O
leaders	O
,	O
most	O
of	O
whom	O
are	O
male	O
,	O
to	O
own	O
the	O
accountability	O
for	O
balancing	O
.	O
and	O
they	O
know	O
that	O
the	O
best	O
person	O
to	O
convince	O
them	O
of	O
this	O
isn	O
’	O
t	O
a	O
woman	O
.	O
it	O
’	O
s	O
one	O
of	O
their	O
own	O
.	O
so	O
getting	O
men	O
to	O
lead	O
the	O
charge	O
is	O
a	O
smart	O
choice	O
,	O
as	O
more	O
and	O
more	O
organizations	O
are	O
recognizing	O
.	O
but	O
how	O
can	O
you	O
tell	O
whether	O
a	O
ceo	O
is	O
a	O
good	O
leader	O
on	O
gender	O
?	O
it	O
’	O
s	O
pretty	O
easy	O
:	O
see	O
who	O
’	O
s	O
on	O
the	O
company	O
’	O
s	O
executive	O
team	O
.	O
how	O
many	O
women	O
are	O
there	O
?	O
are	O
they	O
in	O
strategic	O
roles	O
,	O
or	O
staff	O
functions	O
?	O
judging	O
this	O
way	O
,	O
are	O
trump	PERS
’	O
s	O
choices	O
,	O
the	O
ceos	O
of	O
walmart	ORG
and	O
ey	ORG
,	O
a	O
good	O
pick	O
?	O
take	O
a	O
quick	O
look	O
at	O
their	O
top	O
teams	O
:	O
ey	ORG
has	O
three	O
women	O
out	O
of	O
17	O
,	O
most	O
of	O
whom	O
are	O
in	O
staff	O
jobs	O
,	O
such	O
as	O
hr	O
.	O
walmart	ORG
has	O
five	O
men	O
who	O
sit	O
at	O
the	O
top	O
of	O
its	O
pyramid	O
and	O
probably	O
run	O
the	O
show	O
,	O
but	O
another	O
35	O
people	O
on	O
its	O
website	O
under	O
“	O
executive	O
management.	O
”	O
of	O
the	O
35	O
,	O
12	O
are	O
women	O
,	O
with	O
at	O
least	O
half	O
that	O
number	O
in	O
staff	O
jobs	O
again	O
(	O
legal	O
,	O
hr	O
,	O
communications	O
)	O
,	O
a	O
classic	O
strategy	O
for	O
first-stage	O
balancers	O
.	O
now	O
look	O
at	O
p	O
&	O
g	O
or	O
mcdonald	O
’	O
s	O
.	O
see	O
the	O
difference	O
?	O
walmart	ORG
and	O
ey	ORG
certainly	O
have	O
worked	O
hard	O
to	O
get	O
to	O
where	O
they	O
are	O
.	O
but	O
they	O
aren	O
’	O
t	O
best	O
in	O
class	O
.	O
many	O
companies	O
and	O
ceos	O
are	O
voicing	O
support	O
for	O
gender	O
issues	O
.	O
but	O
while	O
most	O
companies	O
compete	O
to	O
say	O
how	O
much	O
they	O
care	O
,	O
fewer	O
actually	O
deliver	O
more	O
than	O
tokenism	O
at	O
the	O
top	O
.	O
companies	O
have	O
gotten	O
much	O
more	O
skilled	O
at	O
what	O
we	O
call	O
pinkwashing	O
.	O
they	O
sound	O
good	O
on	O
gender	O
issues	O
,	O
their	O
websites	O
trumpet	O
their	O
dedication	O
,	O
and	O
they	O
sponsor	O
great	O
women	O
’	O
s	O
conferences	O
,	O
but	O
the	O
core	O
jobs	O
on	O
their	O
leadership	O
teams	O
remain	O
male-dominated	O
.	O
they	O
may	O
manage	O
to	O
get	O
a	O
few	O
women	O
up	O
into	O
the	O
latest	O
pink	O
ghetto	O
:	O
the	O
staff	O
jobs	O
of	O
the	O
executive	O
team	O
.	O
on	O
gender	O
issues	O
,	O
there	O
are	O
three	O
kinds	O
of	O
companies	O
today	O
:	O
the	O
progressive	O
.	O
companies	O
that	O
are	O
truly	O
balanced	O
,	O
with	O
a	O
mix	O
of	O
genders	O
in	O
nonstereotypical	O
roles	O
on	O
their	O
leadership	O
teams	O
(	O
especially	O
across	O
both	O
line	O
and	O
staff	O
responsibilities	O
)	O
.	O
the	O
pretending	O
.	O
those	O
that	O
say	O
all	O
the	O
right	O
things	O
,	O
run	O
a	O
lot	O
of	O
women-branded	O
initiatives	O
,	O
but	O
still	O
have	O
women	O
only	O
in	O
noncore	O
p	O
&	O
l	O
roles	O
on	O
their	O
executive	O
team	O
.	O
better	O
than	O
nothing	O
,	O
some	O
of	O
you	O
may	O
be	O
thinking	O
.	O
perhaps	O
,	O
but	O
it	O
doesn	O
’	O
t	O
promise	O
much	O
for	O
the	O
future	O
.	O
the	O
plodding	O
.	O
those	O
that	O
ignore	O
the	O
issue	O
completely	O
and	O
stick	O
unapologetically	O
to	O
their	O
all-male	O
status	O
quo	O
.	O
the	O
first	O
category	O
here	O
is	O
still	O
rare	O
,	O
unfortunately	O
.	O
even	O
mckinsey	ORG
&	ORG
co.	ORG
,	O
which	O
each	O
year	O
publishes	O
convincing	O
“	O
women	O
matter	O
”	O
reports	O
on	O
the	O
importance	O
of	O
strategic	O
,	O
ceo-led	O
gender	O
initiatives	O
that	O
deliver	O
consistent	O
outperformance	O
—	O
reports	O
that	O
are	O
widely	O
cited	O
in	O
discussions	O
about	O
women	O
in	O
business	O
—	O
can	O
muster	O
only	O
11	O
%	O
women	O
in	O
its	O
senior	O
leadership	O
.	O
trump	PERS
’	O
s	O
own	O
cabinet	O
sits	O
somewhere	O
between	O
the	O
last	O
two	O
categories	O
.	O
they	O
’	O
ve	O
made	O
a	O
nod	O
to	O
a	O
handful	O
of	O
women	O
(	O
four	O
out	O
of	O
17	O
,	O
the	O
least	O
balanced	O
team	O
for	O
decades	O
)	O
,	O
but	O
you	O
know	O
that	O
they	O
aren	O
’	O
t	O
seen	O
as	O
core	O
functions	O
to	O
this	O
administration	O
.	O
one	O
of	O
the	O
characteristics	O
of	O
unconvinced	O
leaders	O
is	O
that	O
they	O
tend	O
not	O
to	O
pick	O
very	O
strong	O
women	O
—	O
almost	O
as	O
though	O
they	O
don	O
’	O
t	O
believe	O
such	O
women	O
can	O
be	O
found	O
.	O
so	O
betsy	PERS
devos	PERS
,	O
a	O
major	O
republican	O
donor	O
,	O
has	O
proved	O
to	O
be	O
the	O
most	O
imperiled	O
cabinet	O
pick	O
as	O
the	O
most	O
glaringly	O
unqualified	O
.	O
pinkwashing	O
is	O
increasingly	O
easy	O
to	O
identify	O
.	O
for	O
example	O
,	O
no	O
sooner	O
had	O
audi	ORG
aired	O
its	O
gender-equality-extolling	O
super	O
bowl	O
ad	O
than	O
viewers	O
were	O
quick	O
to	O
point	O
out	O
that	O
its	O
board	O
is	O
100	O
%	O
male	O
and	O
its	O
executive	O
team	O
contains	O
only	O
two	O
women	O
(	O
in	O
the	O
pink	O
ghetto	O
functions	O
of	O
hr	O
and	O
communications	O
)	O
.	O
the	O
organizations	O
that	O
really	O
care	O
enough	O
to	O
attain	O
gender	O
balance	O
have	O
been	O
working	O
at	O
the	O
issue	O
for	O
decades	O
,	O
and	O
it	O
shows	O
,	O
very	O
publicly	O
,	O
in	O
their	O
boards	O
and	O
executive	O
teams	O
.	O
the	O
others	O
are	O
looking	O
more	O
transparently	O
traditional	O
.	O
this	O
transparency	O
has	O
been	O
hard	O
to	O
measure	O
up	O
until	O
now	O
;	O
very	O
few	O
companies	O
had	O
managed	O
any	O
form	O
of	O
balance	O
up	O
to	O
the	O
top	O
of	O
their	O
corporate	O
pyramids	O
.	O
gender	O
statistics	O
are	O
a	O
tightly	O
guarded	O
secret	O
,	O
because	O
they	O
can	O
paint	O
an	O
embarrassing	O
picture	O
.	O
in	O
the	O
competitive	O
war	O
for	O
talent	O
,	O
companies	O
that	O
can	O
prove	O
their	O
balancing	O
success	O
will	O
become	O
vastly	O
more	O
powerful	O
magnets	O
of	O
top	O
female	O
talent	O
.	O
and	O
since	O
women	O
now	O
represent	O
55	O
%	O
of	O
american	O
university	O
graduates	O
,	O
this	O
is	O
likely	O
to	O
be	O
a	O
huge	O
lever	O
for	O
continued	O
competitive	O
advantage	O
.	O
this	O
,	O
of	O
course	O
,	O
has	O
long	O
been	O
predicted	O
,	O
but	O
the	O
next	O
decade	O
may	O
show	O
the	O
wheat	O
running	O
away	O
from	O
the	O
chaff	O
.	O
careful	O
observers	O
will	O
be	O
able	O
to	O
distinguish	O
which	O
efforts	O
are	O
for	O
show	O
and	O
which	O
actually	O
show	O
conviction	O
.	O
beware	O
pinkwashing	O
,	O
but	O
recognize	O
and	O
celebrate	O
the	O
men	O
who	O
push	O
for	O
the	O
real	O
thing	O
.	O
their	O
numbers	O
are	O
growing	O
.	O
get	O
started	O
:	O
women-owned	O
businesses	O
struggle	O
with	O
financing	O
|	O
women	O
and	O
financing	O
women	O
who	O
own	O
businesses	O
struggle	O
more	O
with	O
getting	O
financing	O
than	O
small	O
company	O
owners	O
in	O
general	O
,	O
according	O
to	O
a	O
survey	O
by	O
researchers	O
at	O
pepperdine	ORG
university	ORG
’	O
s	O
graziadio	ORG
school	ORG
of	ORG
business	ORG
and	ORG
management	ORG
and	O
dun	ORG
&	ORG
bradstreet	ORG
corp.	ORG
thirty-seven	O
percent	O
of	O
the	O
364	O
women-owned	O
businesses	O
surveyed	O
in	O
october	O
said	O
they	O
had	O
sought	O
financing	O
during	O
the	O
previous	O
three	O
months	O
,	O
compared	O
to	O
29	O
percent	O
of	O
all	O
the	O
nearly	O
1,600	O
small	O
businesses	O
surveyed	O
.	O
just	O
over	O
a	O
quarter	O
of	O
the	O
women-owned	O
businesses	O
got	O
bank	O
loans	O
,	O
compared	O
to	O
37	O
percent	O
of	O
all	O
small	O
companies	O
.	O
the	O
survey	O
indicates	O
39	O
percent	O
of	O
women	O
owners	O
turned	O
to	O
savings	O
and	O
other	O
personal	O
assets	O
to	O
finance	O
their	O
companies	O
—	O
for	O
many	O
,	O
a	O
move	O
likely	O
linked	O
to	O
the	O
difficulty	O
they	O
had	O
in	O
borrowing	O
.	O
fewer	O
small	O
businesses	O
in	O
general	O
—	O
33	O
percent	O
—	O
turned	O
to	O
personal	O
assets	O
for	O
financing	O
.	O
many	O
women	O
owners	O
turned	O
to	O
alternative	O
lending	O
sources	O
to	O
obtain	O
financing	O
.	O
sixty	O
percent	O
used	O
personal	O
credit	O
cards	O
,	O
