what	O
the	O
future	O
of	O
mobility	O
means	O
for	O
the	O
future	O
of	O
transportation	O
mobile	O
,	O
real	O
time	O
data	O
services	O
will	O
drive	O
-	O
literally	O
and	O
figuratively	O
-	O
consumer	O
behavior	O
.	O
which	O
may	O
diffuse	O
the	O
nature	O
of	O
the	O
the	O
financial	O
opportunity	O
as	O
new	O
market	O
entrants	O
proliferate	O
while	O
sharpening	O
the	O
threat	O
for	O
incumbent	O
service	O
providers	O
.	O
but	O
the	O
biggest	O
change	O
may	O
be	O
the	O
convergence	O
of	O
disparate	O
disciplines	O
-	O
technology	O
,	O
automaking	O
,	O
public	O
transportation	O
,	O
data	O
analysis	O
,	O
among	O
others	O
-	O
into	O
one	O
.	O
jl	O
joris	O
d'inca	O
and	O
carolin	PERS
metz	PERS
comment	O
in	O
forbes	O
:	O
customer	O
relationships	O
and	O
data	O
are	O
at	O
risk	O
for	O
capture	O
by	O
new-entrant	O
mobility	O
providers	O
offering	O
increasingly	O
integrated	O
travel	O
planning	O
(	O
including	O
)	O
mobility	O
services	O
and	O
information	O
.	O
the	O
number	O
of	O
companies	O
operating	O
in	O
the	O
mobility	O
space	O
will	O
increase	O
and	O
become	O
more	O
diverse	O
,	O
likely	O
leading	O
to	O
more	O
co-opetition	O
.	O
and	O
as	O
the	O
transportation	O
landscape	O
becomes	O
more	O
diverse	O
and	O
competitive	O
,	O
the	O
revenue	O
pie	O
will	O
be	O
split	O
more	O
ways	O
.	O
it	O
's	O
a	O
beguiling	O
vision	O
:	O
you	O
wake	O
up	O
and	O
tell	O
your	O
house	O
management	O
system	O
that	O
you	O
need	O
to	O
be	O
in	O
munich	LOC
,	O
or	O
chicago	LOC
,	O
or	O
beijing	LOC
,	O
by	O
two	O
in	O
the	O
afternoon	O
.	O
the	O
house	O
tells	O
your	O
mobility	O
provider	O
,	O
which	O
computes	O
the	O
journey	O
and	O
sends	O
an	O
itinerary	O
to	O
your	O
smart	O
device	O
.	O
at	O
the	O
appointed	O
time	O
,	O
a	O
driverless	O
car	O
rolls	O
up	O
and	O
greets	O
you	O
by	O
name	O
,	O
and	O
you	O
say	O
hello	O
to	O
a	O
couple	O
of	O
people	O
already	O
seated	O
inside	O
.	O
the	O
car	O
drops	O
you	O
all	O
at	O
an	O
integrated	O
mobility	O
hub	O
,	O
where	O
you	O
board	O
a	O
750	O
miles	O
per	O
hour	O
hyperloop	O
that	O
whisks	O
you	O
to	O
your	O
target	O
city	O
in	O
mere	O
minutes	O
.	O
an	O
autonomous	O
bus	O
waits	O
at	O
the	O
station	O
to	O
take	O
you	O
to	O
your	O
final	O
destination	O
,	O
a	O
shared	O
office	O
space	O
in	O
the	O
city	O
center	O
.	O
to	O
determine	O
if	O
this	O
is	O
what	O
mobility	O
could	O
look	O
like	O
in	O
the	O
year	O
2040	O
,	O
oliver	ORG
wyman	ORG
recently	O
conducted	O
a	O
survey	O
of	O
several	O
hundred	O
executives	O
and	O
experts	O
in	O
the	O
transportation	O
industry	O
globally	O
.	O
driven	O
by	O
the	O
fourth	O
industrial	O
revolution	O
,	O
technological	O
convergence	O
,	O
new	O
entrants	O
in	O
the	O
mobility	O
space	O
,	O
and	O
changing	O
travel	O
behaviors	O
,	O
we	O
expect	O
the	O
pace	O
of	O
innovation	O
in	O
passenger	O
transportation	O
to	O
accelerate	O
over	O
the	O
next	O
quarter	O
century	O
.	O
disruption	O
to	O
existing	O
business	O
models	O
will	O
be	O
widespread	O
,	O
and	O
80	O
percent	O
of	O
passenger	O
transportation	O
incumbents	O
say	O
they	O
don	O
’	O
t	O
feel	O
well	O
prepared	O
for	O
what	O
’	O
s	O
coming	O
.	O
a	O
fast-approaching	O
tomorrow	O
our	O
survey	O
identified	O
four	O
key	O
trends	O
that	O
will	O
shape	O
passenger	O
transport	O
over	O
the	O
next	O
25	O
years	O
:	O
1	O
)	O
sustainable	O
,	O
efficient	O
assets	O
;	O
2	O
)	O
integrated	O
personal	O
mobility	O
;	O
3	O
)	O
urbanization	O
and	O
smarter	O
cities	O
;	O
and	O
4	O
)	O
increased	O
competition	O
and	O
innovation	O
.	O
sustainable	O
,	O
efficient	O
assets	O
:	O
the	O
next	O
25	O
years	O
will	O
see	O
greater	O
demand	O
for	O
sustainable	O
solutions	O
and	O
more	O
efficient	O
use	O
of	O
transportation	O
assets	O
.	O
eighty	O
percent	O
of	O
survey	O
participants	O
believe	O
that	O
there	O
will	O
be	O
fewer	O
private	O
cars	O
in	O
the	O
future	O
,	O
while	O
nearly	O
70	O
percent	O
see	O
a	O
significant	O
increase	O
in	O
car	O
sharing	O
.	O
these	O
trends	O
will	O
be	O
accelerated	O
by	O
the	O
development	O
of	O
fully	O
autonomous	O
vehicles	O
.	O
it	O
is	O
not	O
too	O
farfetched	O
to	O
imagine	O
autonomous	O
car	O
fleets	O
that	O
are	O
shared	O
across	O
a	O
neighborhood	O
or	O
city	O
on	O
a	O
fee-per-use	O
or	O
subscription	O
basis	O
.	O
integrated	O
personal	O
mobility	O
:	O
current	O
mobility	O
services	O
will	O
coalesce	O
into	O
full-scale	O
mobility	O
providers	O
,	O
who	O
will	O
focus	O
on	O
enabling	O
seamless	O
,	O
on-demand	O
journeys	O
by	O
integrating	O
all	O
modes	O
of	O
transport	O
.	O
for	O
the	O
traveler	O
,	O
transport	O
mode	O
selection	O
and	O
timetables	O
will	O
cease	O
to	O
be	O
an	O
issue	O
–	O
they	O
’	O
ll	O
only	O
need	O
to	O
know	O
what	O
time	O
to	O
be	O
ready	O
so	O
as	O
to	O
reach	O
a	O
destination	O
by	O
a	O
given	O
time	O
.	O
smart	O
devices	O
will	O
become	O
the	O
organizational	O
center	O
for	O
all	O
trip	O
planning	O
and	O
mobility	O
personalization	O
.	O
urbanization	O
and	O
smarter	O
cities	O
:	O
urban	O
and	O
conurbation	O
populations	O
will	O
continue	O
to	O
grow	O
,	O
increasing	O
passenger	O
volumes	O
.	O
the	O
“	O
smart	O
city	O
”	O
of	O
the	O
future	O
thus	O
will	O
have	O
to	O
invest	O
in	O
technology	O
and	O
transport	O
,	O
with	O
a	O
focus	O
on	O
passenger	O
flow	O
management	O
.	O
coordination	O
with	O
mobility	O
providers	O
,	O
real-time	O
data	O
monitoring	O
,	O
and	O
responsive	O
smart	O
grid	O
systems	O
will	O
ensure	O
the	O
best	O
use	O
of	O
public	O
transport	O
and	O
minimize	O
congestion	O
.	O
increased	O
competition	O
and	O
innovation	O
:	O
survey	O
respondents	O
expect	O
that	O
transport	O
deregulation	O
will	O
continue	O
to	O
spread	O
.	O
liberalization	O
of	O
railways	O
,	O
bus	O
services	O
,	O
taxis	O
,	O
and	O
ride-sharing	O
will	O
enable	O
new	O
companies	O
to	O
enter	O
the	O
market	O
,	O
giving	O
travelers	O
more	O
choice	O
and	O
driving	O
further	O
innovation	O
.	O
one	O
big	O
concern	O
:	O
that	O
liberalization	O
and	O
the	O
rise	O
of	O
low-cost	O
bus	O
and	O
rail	O
services	O
will	O
force	O
revenue	O
per	O
passenger	O
downward	O
,	O
adversely	O
impacting	O
incumbent	O
transport	O
providers	O
.	O
taken	O
all	O
together	O
,	O
what	O
do	O
these	O
trends	O
imply	O
for	O
the	O
future	O
of	O
mobility	O
?	O
private	O
cars	O
will	O
lose	O
their	O
leading	O
role	O
,	O
as	O
shared	O
mobility	O
–	O
using	O
autonomous	O
vehicles	O
–	O
increases	O
dramatically	O
.	O
public	O
transport	O
usage	O
will	O
increase	O
moderately	O
,	O
but	O
function	O
more	O
as	O
one	O
component	O
in	O
seamless	O
multimodal	O
passenger	O
flows	O
.	O
meanwhile	O
,	O
the	O
number	O
of	O
companies	O
operating	O
in	O
the	O
mobility	O
space	O
will	O
increase	O
and	O
become	O
more	O
diverse	O
,	O
likely	O
leading	O
to	O
more	O
“	O
co-opetition.	O
”	O
the	O
biggest	O
story	O
,	O
however	O
,	O
will	O
be	O
the	O
rise	O
of	O
mobility	O
services	O
and	O
information	O
.	O
out	O
of	O
many	O
different	O
providers	O
now	O
attempting	O
to	O
establish	O
themselves	O
in	O
this	O
space	O
,	O
we	O
expect	O
only	O
a	O
few	O
will	O
rise	O
to	O
the	O
top	O
,	O
gaining	O
enough	O
share	O
and	O
reach	O
to	O
provide	O
personal	O
mobility	O
coordination	O
that	O
stretches	O
from	O
one	O
end	O
of	O
the	O
journey	O
to	O
the	O
other	O
.	O
the	O
threat–and	O
potential–for	O
incumbents	O
incumbents	O
in	O
passenger	O
transportation	O
face	O
the	O
greatest	O
risks	O
from	O
this	O
vision	O
.	O
customer	O
relationships	O
and	O
data	O
are	O
at	O
risk	O
for	O
capture	O
by	O
new-entrant	O
mobility	O
providers	O
offering	O
increasingly	O
integrated	O
travel	O
planning	O
.	O
and	O
as	O
the	O
transportation	O
landscape	O
becomes	O
more	O
diverse	O
and	O
competitive	O
,	O
the	O
revenue	O
pie	O
will	O
be	O
split	O
more	O
ways	O
.	O
investment	O
capital	O
may	O
even	O
be	O
harder	O
to	O
come	O
by	O
for	O
traditional	O
transport	O
modes	O
if	O
investors	O
see	O
better	O
opportunities	O
elsewhere	O
.	O
our	O
analysis	O
found	O
,	O
for	O
example	O
,	O
that	O
over	O
the	O
longer	O
term	O
,	O
regional	O
passenger	O
railway	O
services	O
(	O
which	O
are	O
common	O
in	O
europe	LOC
)	O
may	O
be	O
especially	O
vulnerable	O
,	O
as	O
shorter	O
,	O
low-volume	O
routes	O
could	O
be	O
more	O
cost	O
effectively	O
served	O
by	O
autonomous	O
buses	O
.	O
in	O
germany	LOC
alone	O
,	O
20	O
percent	O
to	O
30	O
percent	O
of	O
fixed	O
assets	O
are	O
expected	O
to	O
be	O
at	O
risk	O
.	O
and	O
automotive	O
manufacturers	O
in	O
developed	O
countries	O
may	O
see	O
a	O
substantial	O
reduction	O
in	O
the	O
number	O
of	O
cars	O
they	O
sell	O
as	O
car	O
sharing	O
moves	O
mainstream	O
.	O
fully	O
autonomous	O
cars	O
–	O
expected	O
to	O
be	O
as	O
much	O
as	O
one-third	O
of	O
all	O
car	O
sales	O
by	O
2040	O
–	O
will	O
further	O
expand	O
this	O
trend	O
.	O
hyundai	ORG
motor	ORG
reveals	O
vision	O
for	O
‘	O
future	ORG
mobility	ORG
’	O
january	O
19	O
,	O
2017	O
–	O
hyundai	ORG
motor	ORG
believes	O
the	O
next	O
generation	O
of	O
convergent	O
technologies	O
will	O
link	O
cars	O
to	O
customer	O
’	O
s	O
lives	O
,	O
through	O
intelligent	O
autonomous	O
driving	O
,	O
smart	O
hyper-connectivity	O
solutions	O
,	O
and	O
innovations	O
to	O
promote	O
wellness	O
in	O
mobility	O
.	O
commenting	O
on	O
the	O
company	O
’	O
s	O
forthcoming	O
direction	O
,	O
mike	PERS
song	PERS
,	O
hyundai	ORG
’	O
s	O
head	O
of	O
operations	O
for	O
africa	LOC
and	O
the	O
middle	LOC
east	LOC
,	O
said	O
:	O
“	O
we	O
want	O
to	O
create	O
the	O
best	O
mobility	O
solutions	O
,	O
with	O
technology	O
that	O
cares	O
for	O
humans	O
and	O
society	O
.	O
increasingly	O
,	O
we	O
are	O
sharing	O
our	O
‘	O
vision	O
for	O
future	ORG
mobility	ORG
’	O
,	O
and	O
bringing	O
that	O
vision	O
alive	O
with	O
a	O
range	O
of	O
innovative	O
technologies	O
that	O
focus	O
on	O
intelligent	O
autonomous	O
driving	O
,	O
and	O
advanced	O
,	O
hyper-connectivity	O
solutions	O
that	O
link	O
cars	O
to	O
customer	O
’	O
s	O
lives.	O
”	O
autonomous	O
ioniq	ORG
concepts	O
reveal	O
advanced	O
self-driving	O
technologies	O
hyundai	ORG
motor	ORG
is	O
using	O
live	O
demonstrations	O
and	O
immersive	O
virtual	O
reality	O
displays	O
to	O
present	O
the	O
capabilities	O
of	O
its	O
latest	O
self-driving	O
technology	O
.	O
rather	O
than	O
developing	O
prototype	O
vehicles	O
,	O
hyundai	ORG
motor	ORG
is	O
currently	O
focusing	O
on	O
developing	O
self-driving	O
technologies	O
that	O
can	O
be	O
commercialized	O
in	O
mass	O
production	O
cars	O
.	O
the	O
self-driving	O
cars	O
will	O
be	O
readily	O
available	O
,	O
and	O
at	O
the	O
same	O
time	O
affordable	O
.	O
that	O
means	O
more	O
customers	O
can	O
enjoy	O
the	O
latest	O
advances	O
in	O
safe	O
mobility	O
.	O
moving	O
forward	O
with	O
the	O
use	O
of	O
lidar	O
technology	O
,	O
hyundai	ORG
motor	ORG
has	O
hidden	O
the	O
hardware	O
behind	O
the	O
autonomous	O
ioniq	ORG
’	O
s	O
front	O
bumper	O
rather	O
than	O
using	O
the	O
typical	O
roof-mounted	O
approach	O
,	O
retaining	O
the	O
new	O
car	O
’	O
s	O
sleek	O
design	O
.	O
hyundai	ORG
motor	ORG
’	O
s	O
latest	O
technology	O
allows	O
the	O
cars	O
to	O
navigate	O
the	O
most	O
challenging	O
situations	O
safely	O
,	O
including	O
high	O
levels	O
of	O
pedestrian	O
traffic	O
,	O
stop	O
lights	O
and	O
signs	O
,	O
road	O
construction	O
and	O
road	O
blocks	O
,	O
speed	O
bumps	O
,	O
dogs	O
,	O
small	O
children	O
and	O
even	O
intersections	O
without	O
traffic	O
signals	O
.	O
connected	O
car	O
platform	O
combines	O
intelligent	O
automotive	O
and	O
it	O
technologies	O
the	O
‘	O
hyper-connected	O
car	O
’	O
will	O
be	O
central	O
to	O
bringing	O
greater	O
convenience	O
,	O
comfort	O
,	O
and	O
enjoyment	O
to	O
tomorrow	O
’	O
s	O
lifestyles	O
.	O
with	O
an	O
objective	O
to	O
create	O
hyper-connected	O
intelligent	O
cars	O
that	O
boast	O
the	O
safest	O
and	O
most	O
advanced	O
self-driving	O
systems	O
on	O
the	O
market	O
,	O
hyundai	ORG
motor	ORG
is	O
collaborating	O
with	O
cisco	ORG
,	O
a	O
worldwide	O
leader	O
in	O
it	O
and	O
security	O
technology	O
.	O
the	O
joint	O
program	O
will	O
create	O
a	O
platform	O
optimized	O
for	O
connected	O
cars	O
,	O
which	O
will	O
help	O
enable	O
two-way	O
communication	O
both	O
internally	O
between	O
the	O
car	O
’	O
s	O
system	O
and	O
externally	O
with	O
road	O
infrastructure	O
,	O
other	O
vehicles	O
,	O
internet	O
of	O
things	O
(	O
lot	O
)	O
devices	O
,	O
and	O
the	O
cloud	O
.	O
hyundai	ORG
believes	O
that	O
the	O
connected	O
car	O
will	O
not	O
only	O
be	O
used	O
as	O
a	O
means	O
of	O
transportation	O
,	O
it	O
will	O
become	O
a	O
hub	O
that	O
connects	O
with	O
other	O
cars	O
,	O
your	O
house	O
,	O
your	O
office	O
and	O
even	O
the	O
wider	O
urban	O
environment	O
.	O
‘	O
mobility	O
vision	O
’	O
concept	O
converges	O
hyper-connectivity	O
and	O
smart	O
house	O
through	O
its	O
innovative	O
‘	O
mobility	O
vision	O
’	O
concept	O
,	O
hyundai	ORG
motor	ORG
is	O
demonstrating	O
the	O
potential	O
reach	O
of	O
its	O
advanced	O
technologies	O
.	O
the	O
smart	O
house	O
concept	O
seamlessly	O
integrates	O
the	O
car	O
into	O
the	O
daily	O
lives	O
of	O
users	O
,	O
blurring	O
the	O
line	O
between	O
mobility	O
and	O
customers	O
’	O
living	O
and	O
working	O
spaces	O
.	O
hyundai	ORG
motor	ORG
’	O
s	O
vision	O
sees	O
customers	O
living	O
,	O
without	O
interruption	O
,	O
while	O
on	O
the	O
move	O
as	O
the	O
comfort	O
,	O
convenience	O
and	O
connectivity	O
features	O
of	O
the	O
car	O
and	O
the	O
home	O
are	O
combined	O
into	O
‘	O
one	O
space	O
’	O
.	O
health	O
+	O
mobility	O
concept	O
for	O
wellness	O
in	O
mobility	O
hyundai	ORG
motor	ORG
proposes	O
a	O
‘	O
health	O
+	O
mobility	O
concept	O
’	O
,	O
its	O
future	O
vision	O
for	O
health-conscious	O
vehicles	O
that	O
connect	O
mobility	O
and	O
wellness	O
.	O
an	O
immersive	O
virtual	O
reality	O
room	O
demonstrates	O
how	O
in-car	O
conditions	O
can	O
be	O
created	O
to	O
better	O
manage	O
stress	O
and	O
associated	O
consequences	O
resulting	O
from	O
commuting	O
,	O
allowing	O
drivers	O
to	O
intentionally	O
shift	O
modes	O
for	O
increased	O
personal	O
productivity	O
or	O
relaxation	O
.	O
the	O
interactive	O
health-conscious	O
technology	O
monitors	O
a	O
suite	O
of	O
health	O
and	O
wellbeing	O
indicators	O
via	O
a	O
series	O
of	O
sensors	O
throughout	O
the	O
cockpit	O
.	O
wearable	O
robotics	O
offer	O
new	O
freedom	O
in	O
mobility	O
hyundai	ORG
motor	ORG
has	O
revealed	O
new	O
wearable	O
powered	O
robots	O
that	O
are	O
set	O
to	O
revolutionize	O
the	O
future	O
of	O
personal	O
mobility	O
.	O
the	O
latest	O
innovations	O
in	O
advanced	O
assistive	O
exoskeletons	O
for	O
medical	O
,	O
work	O
and	O
daily	O
life	O
reveal	O
the	O
company	O
’	O
s	O
ambition	O
to	O
provide	O
assisted-mobility	O
support	O
beyond	O
the	O
automobile	O
for	O
the	O
well-being	O
of	O
customers	O
.	O
the	O
range	O
of	O
wearable	O
exoskeletons	O
features	O
on-board	O
motion	O
control	O
systems	O
to	O
support	O
patients	O
with	O
lower	O
spinal	O
cord	O
injuries	O
,	O
or	O
provide	O
stroll	O
support	O
for	O
the	O
elderly	O
in	O
everyday	O
life	O
.	O
a	O
workplace-focused	O
exoskeleton	O
provides	O
upper-body	O
and	O
hip	O
support	O
to	O
prevent	O
back	O
injuries	O
for	O
workers	O
lifting	O
heavy	O
objects	O
.	O
clean	O
mobility	O
hyundai	ORG
cares	O
about	O
clean	O
mobility	O
,	O
helping	O
to	O
make	O
a	O
lasting	O
change	O
that	O
will	O
benefit	O
people	O
today	O
and	O
generations	O
to	O
come	O
.	O
it	O
is	O
fully	O
ready	O
to	O
deliver	O
every	O
type	O
of	O
eco	O
car	O
that	O
customers	O
want	O
around	O
the	O
globe	O
and	O
will	O
not	O
compromise	O
on	O
driving	O
dynamics	O
and	O
performance	O
–	O
a	O
balance	O
of	O
attributes	O
they	O
call	O
‘	O
green	O
performance.	O
’	O
hyundai	ORG
will	O
launch	O
14	O
or	O
more	O
eco-friendly	O
vehicles	O
models	O
by	O
2020	O
,	O
including	O
five	O
hybrid	O
models	O
,	O
four	O
plug-in	O
hybrids	O
,	O
and	O
four	O
electric	O
cars	O
and	O
one	O
fuel	O
cell	O
electric	O
vehicle	O
.	O
in	O
2018	O
,	O
they	O
will	O
launch	O
a	O
new-generation	O
hydrogen	O
fuel	O
cell	O
vehicle	O
.	O
it	O
will	O
be	O
a	O
completely	O
new	O
suv	O
model	O
,	O
based	O
on	O
a	O
new	O
platform	O
developed	O
especially	O
for	O
fuel	O
cell	O
technology	O
.	O
hyundai	ORG
plans	O
to	O
announce	O
more	O
details	O
of	O
this	O
fuel	O
cell	O
vehicle	O
within	O
the	O
next	O
few	O
months	O
.	O
hyundai	ORG
to	O
showcase	O
vision	O
for	O
future	ORG
mobility	ORG
at	O
2017	O
ces	O
hyundai	ORG
will	O
showcase	O
its	O
vision	O
for	O
future	ORG
mobility	ORG
at	O
the	O
consumer	O
electronics	O
show	O
(	O
ces	O
)	O
in	O
las	LOC
vegas	LOC
,	O
from	O
5	O
to	O
8	O
january	O
,	O
2017	O
.	O
on	O
display	O
at	O
the	O
hyundai	ORG
booth	O
will	O
be	O
a	O
pair	O
of	O
autonomous	O
ioniq	ORG
concepts	O
,	O
which	O
are	O
set	O
to	O
participate	O
in	O
the	O
company	O
’	O
s	O
self-driving	O
trials	O
in	O
urban	O
las	LOC
vegas	LOC
.	O
the	O
ioniq	ORG
models	O
will	O
operate	O
on	O
test	O
routes	O
in	O
the	O
boulevards	O
around	O
ces	O
,	O
while	O
inside	O
visitors	O
can	O
experience	O
a	O
driverless	O
journey	O
via	O
immersive	O
virtual	O
reality	O
simulators	O
.	O
a	O
new	O
micro	O
mobility	O
concept	O
,	O
integrated	O
with	O
the	O
ioniq	ORG
electric	ORG
,	O
will	O
showcase	O
the	O
future	O
of	O
first-	O
and	O
last-mile	O
mobility	O
.	O
the	O
korean	O
car	O
maker	O
is	O
also	O
set	O
to	O
present	O
its	O
‘	O
hyper-connected	O
”	O
car	O
platform	O
that	O
is	O
able	O
to	O
seamlessly	O
link	O
mobility	O
with	O
the	O
home	O
and	O
workplace	O
.	O
developed	O
with	O
leading	O
global	O
it	O
company	O
cisco	ORG
,	O
the	O
next-generation	O
car	O
connectivity	O
system	O
will	O
be	O
central	O
to	O
making	O
tomorrow	O
’	O
s	O
lifestyles	O
even	O
more	O
convenient	O
.	O
hyundai	ORG
’	O
s	O
caring	O
‘	O
mobility	O
vision	O
’	O
concept	O
shows	O
how	O
smart	O
house	O
and	O
connected	O
car	O
technologies	O
will	O
blur	O
the	O
lines	O
between	O
mobility	O
,	O
and	O
living	O
and	O
working	O
spaces	O
.	O
also	O
on	O
display	O
will	O
be	O
hyundai	ORG
’	O
s	O
vision	O
for	O
future	ORG
mobility	ORG
which	O
includes	O
wearable	O
robots	O
and	O
interactive	O
,	O
health-conscious	O
technology	O
.	O
the	O
healthcare	O
cockpit	O
connects	O
car	O
and	O
driver	O
to	O
boost	O
productivity	O
or	O
relaxation	O
when	O
travelling	O
.	O
meanwhile	O
the	O
company	O
’	O
s	O
range	O
of	O
advanced	O
wearable	O
exoskeletons	O
show	O
its	O
commitment	O
to	O
social	O
responsibility	O
,	O
offering	O
a	O
new	O
freedom	O
of	O
mobility	O
to	O
customers	O
who	O
require	O
physical	O
support	O
for	O
lifting	O
or	O
repetitive	O
work	O
,	O
plus	O
assisting	O
members	O
of	O
society	O
whose	O
mobility	O
is	O
restricted	O
.	O
hyundai	ORG
reveals	O
vision	O
for	O
human	O
future	ORG
mobility	ORG
hyper-connected	O
car	O
links	O
to	O
home	O
and	O
office	O
wearable	O
robotics	O
for	O
mobility	O
/	O
health	O
solutions	O
mini-scooter	O
speeds	O
end-of-commute	O
journey	O
hyundai	ORG
autonomous	O
car	O
:	O
the	O
south	O
korean	O
automaker	O
has	O
taken	O
the	O
concept	O
of	O
autonomous	O
(	O
self-driving	O
)	O
cars	O
to	O
new	O
levels	O
.	O
image	O
:	O
hyundai	ORG
/	O
newspress	O
las	LOC
vegas	LOC
,	O
nevada	LOC
–	O
hyundai	ORG
motor	ORG
is	O
showcasing	O
key	O
elements	O
of	O
its	O
strategy	O
for	O
future	ORG
mobility	ORG
at	O
the	O
2017	O
consumer	O
electronics	O
show	O
here	O
,	O
including	O
a	O
next-generation	O
of	O
convergent	O
tech	O
to	O
link	O
cars	O
to	O
customer	O
’	O
s	O
lives	O
.	O
they	O
include	O
intelligent	O
autonomous	O
driving	O
,	O
smart	O
car/home	O
hyper-connectivity	O
and	O
innovations	O
to	O
promote	O
wellness	O
in	O
personal	O
mobility	O
.	O
autonomous	O
ioniq	ORG
concepts	O
reveal	O
advanced	O
self-driving	O
technologies	O
the	O
automaker	O
is	O
using	O
live	O
demonstrations	O
and	O
virtual	O
reality	O
displays	O
to	O
present	O
the	O
capabilities	O
of	O
its	O
latest	O
self-driving	O
tech	O
.	O
two	O
cars	O
are	O
driving	O
test	O
routes	O
in	O
las	LOC
vegas	LOC
and	O
ces	O
visitors	O
can	O
experience	O
a	O
vr	O
driverless	O
journey	O
in	O
vehicle	O
simulators	O
.	O
advances	O
in	O
lidar	O
tech	O
have	O
allowed	O
hyundai	ORG
to	O
hide	O
the	O
hardware	O
behind	O
the	O
autonomous	O
ioniq	ORG
’	O
s	O
front	O
bumper	O
rather	O
than	O
using	O
cumbersome	O
roof-mounted	O
antennae	O
–	O
retaining	O
the	O
new	O
car	O
’	O
s	O
sleek	O
design	O
.	O
read	O
more	O
hyundai	ORG
features	O
on	O
carman	O
’	O
s	O
corner	O
hyundai	ORG
says	O
the	O
cars	O
can	O
safely	O
navigate	O
the	O
most	O
challenging	O
situations	O
,	O
including	O
high	O
levels	O
of	O
pedestrian	O
traffic	O
,	O
traffic	O
lights	O
and	O
signs	O
,	O
road	O
construction	O
and	O
road-blocks	O
,	O
speed	O
humps	O
,	O
dogs	O
,	O
small	O
children	O
–	O
even	O
intersections	O
without	O
traffic	O
lights	O
.	O
connected	O
car	O
platform	O
combines	O
intelligent	O
automotive	O
and	O
it	O
tech	O
another	O
interactive	O
experience	O
shows	O
how	O
the	O
‘	O
hyper-connected	O
car	O
’	O
will	O
be	O
central	O
to	O
buying	O
greater	O
convenience	O
,	O
comfort	O
and	O
enjoyment	O
for	O
“	O
tomorrow	O
’	O
s	O
lifestyles	O
”	O
.	O
the	O
objective	O
,	O
hyundai	ORG
says	O
,	O
is	O
the	O
creation	O
of	O
hyper-connected	O
intelligent	O
cars	O
that	O
will	O
use	O
the	O
safest	O
and	O
most	O
advanced	O
self-driving	O
systems	O
on	O
the	O
market	O
.	O
the	O
automaker	O
told	O
the	O
corner	O
is	O
a	O
media	O
release	O
:	O
“	O
we	O
are	O
collaborating	O
with	O
cisco	ORG
,	O
a	O
world	O
leader	O
in	O
it	O
and	O
security	O
technology	O
,	O
to	O
create	O
a	O
platform	O
which	O
will	O
enable	O
two-way	O
communication	O
between	O
the	O
car	O
,	O
road	O
infrastructure	O
,	O
other	O
vehicles	O
,	O
internet	O
of	O
things	O
(	O
lot	O
)	O
devices	O
,	O
and	O
the	O
cloud.	O
”	O
‘	O
mobility	O
vision	O
’	O
concept	O
converges	O
hyper-connectivity	O
and	O
smart	O
house	O
hyundai	ORG
’	O
s	O
‘	O
mobility	O
vision	O
’	O
concept	O
is	O
demonstrating	O
the	O
potential	O
for	O
its	O
smart	O
house	O
concept	O
at	O
ces…	O
it	O
integrates	O
a	O
car	O
into	O
users	O
’	O
daily	O
lives	O
“	O
blurring	O
the	O
line	O
between	O
mobility	O
and	O
people	O
’	O
s	O
living	O
and	O
working	O
spaces	O
”	O
.	O
smart	O
house	O
,	O
clever	O
car	O
:	O
keep	O
your	O
car	O
and	O
house	O
in	O
synch	O
with	O
hyundai	ORG
’	O
s	O
latest	O
systems	O
.	O
image	O
:	O
newspress	O
/	O
hyundai	ORG
motor	ORG
it	O
shows	O
how	O
a	O
car	O
might	O
integrate	O
with	O
the	O
home	O
when	O
parked	O
but	O
become	O
a	O
mobile	O
living	O
space	O
when	O
its	O
owner	O
needs	O
to	O
move	O
around	O
.	O
hyundai	ORG
sees	O
its	O
car-owners	O
living	O
,	O
without	O
interruption	O
,	O
on	O
the	O
move	O
with	O
the	O
comfort	O
,	O
convenience	O
and	O
connectivity	O
of	O
the	O
car	O
and	O
the	O
home	O
combined	O
.	O
health	O
+	O
mobility	O
concept	O
for	O
wellness	O
in	O
mobility	O
hyundai	ORG
motor	ORG
is	O
also	O
presenting	O
‘	O
health	O
+	O
mobility	O
concept	O
’	O
,	O
its	O
ideas	O
for	O
health-conscious	O
vehicles	O
that	O
connect	O
mobility	O
and	O
wellness	O
.	O
a	O
vr	O
room	O
demonstrates	O
how	O
in-car	O
conditions	O
can	O
be	O
created	O
to	O
manage	O
stress	O
and	O
associated	O
consequences	O
while	O
commuting	O
.	O
get	O
stressed	O
when	O
commuting	O
?	O
then	O
hyundai	ORG
’	O
s	O
smart	O
car	O
concept	O
will	O
help	O
to	O
take	O
the	O
strain	O
.	O
image	O
:	O
newspress	O
/	O
hyundai	ORG
motor	ORG
the	O
tech	O
monitors	O
several	O
health	O
and	O
well-being	O
indicators	O
through	O
cabin	O
sensors	O
.	O
wearable	O
robotics	O
offer	O
new	O
freedom	O
in	O
mobility	O
hyundai	ORG
motor	ORG
has	O
created	O
wearable	O
powered	O
robots	O
which	O
could	O
revolutionise	O
the	O
future	O
of	O
human	O
mobility	O
.	O
the	O
exoskeletons	O
reveal	O
the	O
company	O
’	O
s	O
desire	O
to	O
provide	O
customers	O
with	O
assisted	O
support	O
outside	O
the	O
car	O
.	O
just	O
like	O
the	O
the	O
sci-fi	O
movies	O
:	O
hyundai	ORG
,	O
looking	O
to	O
personal	O
mobility	O
,	O
has	O
developed	O
powered	O
exoskeletons	O
to	O
assist	O
the	O
aged	O
or	O
spinally	O
injured	O
walk	O
comfortably	O
or	O
even	O
workers	O
who	O
have	O
repeatedly	O
to	O
life	O
heavy	O
items	O
.	O
image	O
:	O
hyundai	ORG
motor	ORG
/	O
newspress	O
the	O
exoskeletons	O
at	O
ces	O
have	O
motion	O
controls	O
to	O
support	O
people	O
with	O
spinal-cord	O
injuries	O
or	O
everyday	O
walking	O
support	O
for	O
the	O
elderly	O
.	O
a	O
workplace	O
exoskeleton	O
provides	O
upper-body	O
and	O
hip	O
support	O
to	O
prevent	O
back	O
injuries	O
for	O
workers	O
lifting	O
heavy	O
objects	O
.	O
finally	O
,	O
the	O
ioniq	ORG
scooter	ORG
provides	O
final-kilometer	O
mobility	O
yes	O
,	O
it	O
’	O
s	O
a	O
real	O
scooter	O
:	O
the	O
ioniq	ORG
elextric	O
scoot	O
spends	O
its	O
time	O
in	O
the	O
door	O
of	O
an	O
hyundai	ORG
until	O
needed	O
to	O
speed	O
up	O
walking	O
.	O
image	O
:	O
hyundai	ORG
motor	ORG
/	O
newspress	O
hyundai	ORG
motor	ORG
has	O
unveiled	O
the	O
ioniq	ORG
scooter	ORG
,	O
an	O
innovative	O
portable-mobility	O
concept	O
that	O
enables	O
customers	O
to	O
continue	O
their	O
journey	O
to	O
the	O
final	O
destination	O
.	O
the	O
light	O
battery-powered	O
scoot	O
can	O
fold	O
and	O
be	O
recharged	O
in	O
the	O
front	O
door	O
of	O
the	O
ioniq	ORG
electric	ORG
.	O
car	O
to	O
go	O
with	O
it…	O
the	O
scooter	O
is	O
the	O
result	O
of	O
a	O
study	O
into	O
alternatives	O
for	O
‘	O
first-and-last	O
mile	O
mobility	O
’	O
by	O
hyundai	ORG
motor	ORG
’	O
s	O
long-term	O
research	O
and	O
development	O
programme	O
.	O
project	O
ioniq	ORG
,	O
works	O
to	O
redefine	O
future	ORG
mobility	ORG
through	O
innovation	O
.	O
also	O
on	O
display	O
at	O
the	O
hyundai	ORG
booth	O
is	O
the	O
latest	O
ioniq	ORG
hybrid	ORG
which	O
includes	O
enhancements	O
to	O
further	O
its	O
reputation	O
as	O
one	O
of	O
the	O
world	O
’	O
s	O
most	O
fuel-efficient	O
cars	O
.	O
hyundai	ORG
motor	ORG
advances	O
its	O
‘	O
future	ORG
mobility	ORG
’	O
vision	O
at	O
the	O
2017	O
seoul	ORG
motor	ORG
show	O
hyundai	ORG
has	O
revealed	O
its	O
latest	O
hyper-connected	O
car	O
and	O
autonomous	O
driving	O
technologies	O
at	O
the	O
2017	O
seoul	ORG
motor	ORG
show	O
which	O
runs	O
from	O
today	O
to	O
the	O
9th	O
of	O
april	O
2017	O
.	O
the	O
‘	O
home	O
to	O
car	O
’	O
and	O
‘	O
car	O
to	O
home	O
’	O
services	O
with	O
hyundai	ORG
's	O
self-developed	O
ccsp	O
platform	O
introduced	O
together	O
with	O
the	O
fe	O
fuel	O
cell	O
concept	O
car	O
’	O
s	O
asian	O
debut	O
(	O
above	O
)	O
demonstrates	O
hyundai	ORG
’	O
s	O
overall	O
tech	O
integration	O
as	O
well	O
as	O
eco-vehicle	O
commitment	O
.	O
aside	O
from	O
that	O
,	O
visitors	O
to	O
the	O
motor	O
show	O
can	O
see	O
two	O
specially-prepared	O
hyundai	ORG
ioniq	ORG
hybrids	O
-	O
an	O
autonomous	O
self	O
drive	O
(	O
and	O
experience	O
at	O
the	O
motor	O
show	O
)	O
variant	O
,	O
shown	O
above	O
,	O
and	O
one	O
that	O
set	O
an	O
fia-approved	O
record	O
of	O
157.825mph	O
last	O
year	O
at	O
the	O
world-renowned	O
bonneville	O
salt	O
flats	O
,	O
achieving	O
a	O
peak	O
exit	O
speed	O
of	O
160.7mph	O
in	O
the	O
process	O
.	O
let	O
me	O
also	O
add	O
that	O
the	O
ioniq	ORG
that	O
we	O
can	O
buy	O
here	O
in	O
malaysia	LOC
will	O
not	O
hit	O
160mph	O
or	O
over	O
255kmh	O
.	O
but	O
it	O
is	O
fun	O
to	O
drive	O
for	O
an	O
affordable	O
hybrid	O
car	O
(	O
a	O
review	O
will	O
be	O
out	O
by	O
yours	O
truly	O
sometime	O
soon	O
)	O
.	O
do	O
read	O
the	O
press	O
release	O
below	O
for	O
all	O
the	O
details	O
.	O
press	O
release	O
hyundai	ORG
motor	ORG
advances	O
‘	O
future	ORG
mobility	ORG
’	O
vision	O
at	O
the	O
2017	O
seoul	ORG
motor	ORG
show	O
march	O
31	O
,	O
2017	O
-	O
hyundai	ORG
motor	ORG
has	O
revealed	O
further	O
developments	O
for	O
its	O
future	ORG
mobility	ORG
strategy	O
by	O
demonstrating	O
a	O
suite	O
of	O
industry-leading	O
technologies	O
at	O
the	O
2017	O
seoul	ORG
motor	ORG
show	O
which	O
runs	O
from	O
march	O
31	O
to	O
april	O
9	O
,	O
2017	O
at	O
the	O
korea	LOC
international	O
exhibition	O
center	O
in	O
goyang	O
,	O
west	O
of	O
seoul	LOC
.	O
the	O
next	O
generation	O
of	O
convergent	O
technology	O
under	O
development	O
includes	O
a	O
newly-developed	O
connected	O
car	O
service	O
platform	O
(	O
ccsp	O
)	O
platform	O
and	O
smart	O
,	O
hyper-connectivity	O
innovations	O
that	O
focus	O
on	O
linking	O
cars	O
to	O
customers	O
’	O
lives	O
,	O
blurring	O
the	O
line	O
between	O
mobility	O
,	O
and	O
customers	O
’	O
living	O
and	O
working	O
spaces	O
.	O
connected	O
car	O
service	O
platform	O
connects	O
customers	O
and	O
cars	O
hyundai	ORG
displayed	O
its	O
latest	O
vision	O
for	O
connecting	O
cars	O
to	O
customers	O
’	O
lives	O
by	O
announcing	O
plans	O
for	O
its	O
self-developed	O
connected	O
car	O
service	O
platform	O
(	O
ccsp	O
)	O
platform	O
.	O
this	O
platform	O
will	O
allow	O
customers	O
to	O
connect	O
seamlessly	O
to	O
a	O
variety	O
of	O
other	O
iot	O
services	O
offered	O
by	O
telecommunications	O
providers	O
and	O
global	O
appliance	O
services	O
.	O
interconnected	O
services	O
will	O
blur	O
the	O
lines	O
between	O
mobility	O
,	O
living	O
and	O
working	O
spaces	O
,	O
with	O
‘	O
home	O
to	O
car	O
’	O
voice	O
controlled	O
operations	O
allowing	O
drivers	O
to	O
start	O
their	O
cars	O
and	O
open	O
or	O
close	O
doors	O
through	O
speech	O
.	O
meanwhile	O
,	O
‘	O
car	O
to	O
home	O
’	O
options	O
will	O
connect	O
customers	O
with	O
smart	O
home	O
services	O
,	O
including	O
home	O
lighting	O
,	O
climate	O
control	O
,	O
and	O
audio	O
systems	O
.	O
“	O
controlling	O
vehicles	O
via	O
voice	O
assistant	O
is	O
something	O
that	O
could	O
become	O
common-	O
place	O
in	O
the	O
not-too-	O
distant	O
future	O
,	O
”	O
said	O
seung-ho	PERS
hwang	PERS
,	O
executive	O
vice	O
president	O
and	O
head	O
of	O
auto	O
intelligence	O
division	O
at	O
hyundai	ORG
motor	ORG
company	ORG
.	O
“	O
we	O
are	O
working	O
with	O
various	O
companies	O
in	O
korea	LOC
and	O
around	O
the	O
world	O
to	O
ensure	O
that	O
all	O
of	O
our	O
platforms	O
are	O
compatible	O
and	O
that	O
hyundai	ORG
customers	O
will	O
be	O
able	O
to	O
interact	O
with	O
the	O
internet	O
of	O
things	O
in	O
ways	O
that	O
have	O
never	O
before	O
been	O
possible.	O
”	O
the	O
connectivity	O
services	O
demonstrated	O
at	O
the	O
show	O
will	O
be	O
available	O
commercially	O
in	O
the	O
next	O
few	O
years	O
,	O
with	O
‘	O
home	O
to	O
car	O
’	O
services	O
expected	O
in	O
2018	O
and	O
‘	O
car	O
to	O
home	O
’	O
operations	O
available	O
in	O
the	O
following	O
year	O
.	O
connected	O
car	O
roadmap	O
reveals	O
key	O
service	O
objectives	O
hyundai	ORG
presented	O
key	O
elements	O
of	O
its	O
connected	O
car	O
roadmap	O
at	O
the	O
2017	O
seoul	ORG
motor	ORG
show	O
.	O
building	O
on	O
its	O
philosophy	O
of	O
caring	O
for	O
customers	O
,	O
hyundai	ORG
revealed	O
the	O
four	O
main	O
objectives	O
that	O
will	O
ensure	O
smart	O
connected	O
technologies	O
provide	O
greater	O
convenience	O
and	O
efficiencies	O
for	O
drivers	O
.	O
	O
proactive	O
caring	O
–	O
regular	O
monitoring	O
of	O
a	O
car	O
’	O
s	O
diagnostic	O
information	O
,	O
paired	O
with	O
analysis	O
of	O
big	O
data	O
can	O
help	O
to	O
diagnose	O
potential	O
problems	O
before	O
they	O
become	O
an	O
issue	O
,	O
enabling	O
remote	O
proactive	O
maintenance	O
of	O
vehicles	O
.	O
	O
smart	O
convenience	O
–	O
hyundai	ORG
plans	O
to	O
offer	O
customers	O
regular	O
updates	O
to	O
vehicle	O
software	O
and	O
features	O
.	O
this	O
step	O
will	O
ensure	O
customers	O
always	O
benefit	O
from	O
the	O
latest	O
version	O
even	O
,	O
when	O
the	O
car	O
is	O
being	O
driven	O
,	O
ensuring	O
the	O
best	O
customer	O
experience	O
and	O
the	O
latest	O
vehicle	O
and	O
data	O
security	O
.	O
	O
cost	O
efficiency	O
–	O
hyundai	ORG
aims	O
to	O
bring	O
cost-saving	O
efficiencies	O
to	O
customers	O
by	O
analyzing	O
their	O
driving	O
patterns	O
and	O
fuel	O
economy	O
history	O
.	O
this	O
will	O
provide	O
highly	O
accurate	O
‘	O
distance	O
to	O
empty	O
’	O
advice	O
and	O
recommended	O
routes	O
that	O
deliver	O
best	O
fuel	O
economy	O
(	O
and	O
battery	O
life	O
when	O
applicable	O
)	O
.	O
	O
connected	O
efficiency	O
-	O
smart	O
application	O
management	O
will	O
ensure	O
connectivity-reliant	O
actions	O
happen	O
at	O
optimum	O
times	O
,	O
such	O
as	O
automatically	O
updating	O
software	O
while	O
the	O
car	O
is	O
charging	O
.	O
further	O
efficiencies	O
will	O
be	O
gained	O
through	O
monitoring	O
factors	O
that	O
may	O
impact	O
on	O
the	O
driver	O
each	O
day	O
,	O
providing	O
guidance	O
,	O
information	O
or	O
warnings	O
as	O
appropriate	O
.	O
for	O
example	O
,	O
a	O
weather	O
checking	O
service	O
can	O
deliver	O
information	O
to	O
the	O
driver	O
to	O
advise	O
on	O
the	O
optimal	O
time	O
to	O
wash	O
the	O
car	O
.	O
autonomous	O
ioniq	ORG
experience	O
in	O
virtual	O
reality	O
visitors	O
to	O
the	O
2017	O
seoul	ORG
motor	ORG
show	O
are	O
invited	O
to	O
experience	O
a	O
driverless	O
journey	O
via	O
immersive	O
virtual	O
reality	O
(	O
vr	O
)	O
simulators	O
at	O
the	O
hyundai	ORG
motor	ORG
stand	O
.	O
a	O
virtual	O
trip	O
in	O
an	O
autonomous	O
ioniq	ORG
demonstrates	O
how	O
the	O
advanced	O
piloting	O
capabilities	O
of	O
hyundai	ORG
’	O
s	O
latest	O
technology	O
enable	O
the	O
car	O
to	O
navigate	O
without	O
driver	O
input	O
,	O
through	O
the	O
most	O
challenging	O
situations	O
safely	O
.	O
with	O
a	O
sleek	O
design	O
resembling	O
the	O
rest	O
of	O
the	O
ioniq	ORG
line-up	O
,	O
the	O
autonomous	O
ioniq	ORG
is	O
one	O
of	O
the	O
few	O
self-driving	O
cars	O
being	O
developed	O
to	O
have	O
a	O
hidden	O
lidar	O
system	O
in	O
its	O
front	O
bumper	O
instead	O
of	O
on	O
the	O
roof	O
.	O
the	O
car	O
’	O
s	O
advanced	O
self-driving	O
systems	O
are	O
kept	O
as	O
simple	O
as	O
possible	O
by	O
integrating	O
existing	O
functions	O
from	O
the	O
production	O
model	O
,	O
including	O
the	O
smart	O
cruise	O
control	O
system	O
’	O
s	O
forward-facing	O
radar	O
and	O
lane	O
keeping	O
assist	O
cameras	O
.	O
the	O
smart	O
house	O
concept	O
brings	O
car	O
to	O
life	O
hyundai	ORG
presented	O
its	O
smart	O
house	O
concept	O
at	O
the	O
2017	O
seoul	ORG
motor	ORG
show	O
,	O
revealing	O
the	O
potential	O
reach	O
of	O
its	O
advanced	O
future	ORG
mobility	ORG
technologies	O
.	O
the	O
working	O
smart	O
house	O
exhibit	O
provides	O
a	O
vision	O
of	O
how	O
the	O
car	O
could	O
be	O
integrated	O
with	O
the	O
daily	O
lives	O
of	O
users	O
,	O
converging	O
mobility	O
and	O
customer	O
’	O
s	O
living	O
and	O
working	O
spaces	O
.	O
the	O
concept	O
suggests	O
how	O
cars	O
could	O
integrate	O
with	O
our	O
living	O
spaces	O
when	O
docked	O
,	O
before	O
becoming	O
a	O
mobile	O
living	O
space	O
when	O
customers	O
need	O
to	O
move	O
around	O
.	O
hyundai	ORG
’	O
s	O
vision	O
sees	O
customers	O
living	O
,	O
without	O
interruption	O
,	O
while	O
on	O
the	O
move	O
as	O
the	O
comfort	O
,	O
convenience	O
and	O
connectivity	O
features	O
of	O
the	O
car	O
and	O
the	O
home	O
are	O
combined	O
into	O
‘	O
one	O
space	O
’	O
.	O
asian	O
debut	O
for	O
futuristic	O
fe	O
fuel	O
cell	O
concept	O
,	O
the	O
next	O
generation	O
of	O
fuel	O
cell	O
vehicle	O
hyundai	ORG
has	O
revealed	O
its	O
trailblazing	O
future	O
eco	O
(	O
fe	O
)	O
fuel	O
cell	O
concept	O
to	O
asian	O
audiences	O
for	O
the	O
first	O
time	O
,	O
reaffirming	O
its	O
commitment	O
to	O
hydrogen-powered	O
vehicle	O
development	O
.	O
hyundai	ORG
has	O
established	O
itself	O
as	O
a	O
global	O
leader	O
for	O
hydrogen	O
transportation	O
by	O
being	O
the	O
world	O
’	O
s	O
first	O
manufacturer	O
to	O
mass-produce	O
a	O
fuel	O
cell	O
vehicle	O
.	O
the	O
fe	O
fuel	O
cell	O
concept	O
begins	O
a	O
new	O
chapter	O
for	O
hyundai	ORG
by	O
hinting	O
at	O
the	O
form	O
and	O
capabilities	O
of	O
a	O
forthcoming	O
production	O
fcev	O
due	O
for	O
launch	O
in	O
february	O
of	O
2018	O
.	O
the	O
new	O
model	O
will	O
feature	O
advanced	O
driver	O
assistance	O
technologies	O
,	O
alongside	O
an	O
extensive	O
hydrogen-powered	O
range	O
that	O
moves	O
hyundai	ORG
closer	O
toward	O
realizing	O
its	O
ultimate	O
ambition	O
of	O
creating	O
a	O
zero-emission	O
hydrogen	ORG
energy	ORG
society	ORG
.	O
the	O
concept	O
car	O
is	O
designed	O
to	O
run	O
for	O
more	O
than	O
800	O
kilometers	O
between	O
refueling	O
,	O
acknowledging	O
the	O
current	O
limited	O
hydrogen	O
infrastructure	O
and	O
features	O
a	O
host	O
of	O
clever	O
technologies	O
to	O
enhance	O
customer	O
comfort	O
,	O
convenience	O
and	O
safety	O
.	O
one	O
of	O
the	O
most	O
notable	O
characteristics	O
of	O
the	O
new	O
concept	O
is	O
its	O
internal	O
air	O
humidifier	O
,	O
which	O
recycles	O
water	O
emitted	O
by	O
the	O
car	O
’	O
s	O
clean	O
hydrogen	O
energy	O
circulation	O
to	O
create	O
a	O
more	O
comfortable	O
cabin	O
environment	O
.	O
hyundai	ORG
celebrates	O
ioniq	ORG
hybrid	O
world	O
record	O
hyundai	ORG
is	O
also	O
using	O
the	O
2017	O
seoul	ORG
motor	ORG
show	O
to	O
celebrate	O
setting	O
the	O
land-speed	O
record	O
for	O
a	O
production-based	O
hybrid	O
car	O
.	O
visitors	O
can	O
see	O
the	O
specially-prepared	O
hyundai	ORG
ioniq	ORG
hybrid	O
that	O
set	O
an	O
fia-approved	O
record	O
of	O
157.825mph	O
last	O
year	O
at	O
the	O
world-renowned	O
bonneville	O
salt	O
flats	O
,	O
achieving	O
a	O
peak	O
exit	O
speed	O
of	O
160.7mph	O
in	O
the	O
process	O
.	O
hyundai	ORG
's	O
ultimate	O
ambition	O
for	O
high	O
speed	O
driving	O
hyundai	ORG
is	O
showcasing	O
its	O
current	O
i20	O
coupe	O
wrc	O
challenger	O
that	O
is	O
competing	O
in	O
the	O
2017	O
fia	O
world	O
rally	O
championship	O
(	O
wrc	O
)	O
.	O
based	O
on	O
the	O
hyundai	ORG
i20	O
coupe	O
,	O
it	O
is	O
enhanced	O
in	O
line	O
with	O
the	O
wrc	O
’	O
s	O
2017	O
technical	O
regulations	O
that	O
allow	O
for	O
greater	O
power	O
and	O
greater	O
aerodynamic	O
downforce	O
.	O
hyundai	ORG
is	O
also	O
displaying	O
its	O
striking	O
high-performance	O
n	O
concept	O
,	O
the	O
rn30	O
,	O
that	O
was	O
first	O
introduced	O
during	O
last	O
year	O
’	O
s	O
paris	ORG
motor	ORG
show	O
.	O
the	O
motorsport-inspired	O
racing	O
concept	O
was	O
developed	O
in	O
close	O
collaboration	O
with	O
hyundai	ORG
motorsport	O
(	O
hmsg	O
)	O
,	O
hyundai	ORG
motor	ORG
europe	ORG
technical	O
center	O
(	O
hmetc	O
)	O
and	O
hyundai	ORG
motor	ORG
’	O
s	O
performance	O
development	O
and	O
high	O
performance	O
vehicle	O
division	O
.	O
at	O
the	O
seoul	ORG
motor	ORG
show	O
,	O
hyundai	ORG
also	O
unveiled	O
a	O
hybrid	O
variant	O
of	O
the	O
all-new	O
azera	O
–	O
badged	O
as	O
grandeur	O
in	O
korea	LOC
.	O
the	O
conventionally-powered	O
azera	O
was	O
launched	O
in	O
november	O
2016	O
.	O
hyundai	ORG
motor	ORG
’	O
s	O
press	O
conference	O
will	O
take	O
place	O
in	O
exhibition	O
hall	O
2	O
at	O
10:15	O
(	O
kst	O
)	O
on	O
thursday	O
march	O
30	O
,	O
2017	O
.	O
-ends-	O
hyundai	ORG
’	O
s	O
mobility	O
vision	O
is	O
driving	O
forward	O
with	O
the	O
ioniq	ORG
unlimited	ORG
platform	O
hyundai	ORG
made	O
one	O
of	O
the	O
more	O
significant	O
splashes	O
of	O
the	O
los	LOC
angeles	LOC
auto	O
show	O
last	O
month	O
when	O
the	O
korean	O
car	O
manufacturer	O
introduced	O
a	O
subscription-based	O
ownership	O
model	O
essentially	O
made	O
for	O
millennials	O
.	O
billed	O
as	O
ioniq	ORG
unlimited	ORG
,	O
the	O
innovative	O
,	O
stress-free	O
ownership	O
concept	O
is	O
designed	O
to	O
market	O
hyundai	ORG
’	O
s	O
ioniq	ORG
line	O
of	O
zero-emission	O
,	O
eco-focused	O
vehicles	O
by	O
offering	O
a	O
negotiation-free	O
,	O
single-payment	O
method	O
.	O
how	O
does	O
the	O
internet-based	O
buying	O
experience	O
work	O
,	O
exactly	O
?	O
ioniq	ORG
shoppers	O
will	O
be	O
able	O
to	O
select	O
one	O
fixed	O
payment	O
that	O
includes	O
unlimited	O
mileage	O
,	O
electric	O
charging	O
costs	O
,	O
scheduled	O
maintenance	O
,	O
wear	O
items	O
and	O
all	O
typical	O
purchase	O
fees	O
such	O
as	O
registration	O
and	O
down	O
payments	O
.	O
they	O
then	O
receive	O
a	O
quote	O
to	O
take	O
to	O
the	O
dealer	O
to	O
complete	O
the	O
transaction	O
.	O
the	O
pilot	O
program	O
will	O
launch	O
in	O
california	LOC
early	O
next	O
year	O
.	O
the	O
price	O
points	O
consumers	O
can	O
expect	O
to	O
pay	O
have	O
not	O
yet	O
been	O
announced	O
.	O
the	O
transaction-simple	O
project	O
will	O
be	O
paired	O
with	O
a	O
marketing	O
partnership	O
with	O
waivecar	O
to	O
give	O
consumers	O
a	O
chance	O
to	O
drive	O
ioniq	ORG
cars	O
on-demand	O
for	O
two	O
hours	O
at	O
no	O
charge	O
.	O
the	O
only	O
catch	O
is	O
that	O
the	O
cars	O
are	O
wrapped	O
in	O
ads	O
and	O
include	O
a	O
roof-mounted	O
digital	O
display	O
that	O
generates	O
ad	O
revenue	O
to	O
offset	O
costs	O
.	O
hyundai	ORG
expects	O
millennials	O
to	O
be	O
their	O
primary	O
buyers	O
in	O
2017	O
,	O
and	O
their	O
new	O
strategy	O
with	O
ioniq	ORG
unlimited	ORG
and	O
alternative-propulsion	O
vehicles	O
completely	O
aligns	O
the	O
company	O
with	O
their	O
expectations	O
.	O
according	O
to	O
an	O
april	O
report	O
from	O
bankrate	O
,	O
among	O
all	O
age	O
groups	O
that	O
were	O
surveyed	O
,	O
millennials	O
are	O
most	O
likely	O
to	O
purchase	O
a	O
vehicle	O
in	O
the	O
next	O
12	O
months	O
.	O
the	O
most	O
populous	O
generation	O
in	O
the	O
us	LOC
is	O
radically	O
changing	O
the	O
go-to	O
market	O
approach	O
for	O
car	O
companies	O
.	O
dean	PERS
evans	PERS
,	O
chief	O
marketing	O
officer	O
for	O
hyundai	ORG
motor	ORG
america	ORG
,	O
joined	O
[	O
a	O
]	O
listdaily	O
to	O
thoroughly	O
detail	O
the	O
new	O
direction	O
of	O
which	O
hyundai	ORG
is	O
driving	O
its	O
brand	O
.	O
at	O
the	O
la	O
auto	O
show	O
,	O
hyundai	ORG
’	O
s	O
message	O
about	O
no	O
longer	O
being	O
just	O
about	O
cars	O
was	O
rather	O
clear	O
.	O
how	O
are	O
you	O
democratizing	O
new	O
technology	O
while	O
staying	O
at	O
the	O
intersection	O
between	O
health	O
and	O
mobility	O
?	O
the	O
emergence	O
of	O
telematics	O
and	O
connected	O
cars	O
have	O
converged	O
the	O
automotive	O
and	O
technology	O
industries	O
.	O
today	O
,	O
it	O
’	O
s	O
to	O
the	O
point	O
that	O
automobiles	O
,	O
connectivity	O
and	O
technology	O
are	O
intrinsically	O
linked	O
and	O
interchangeable	O
moving	O
parts	O
at	O
motor	O
shows	O
and	O
consumer	O
electronics	O
events	O
everywhere	O
.	O
with	O
that	O
shift	O
,	O
our	O
mission	O
has	O
now	O
moved	O
well	O
beyond	O
providing	O
products	O
to	O
transport	O
people	O
from	O
point	O
a	O
to	O
point	O
b	O
.	O
we	O
no	O
longer	O
just	O
build	O
vehicles	O
,	O
we	O
’	O
re	O
in	O
the	O
business	O
of	O
providing	O
consumer	O
mobility	O
.	O
and	O
we	O
’	O
re	O
committed	O
to	O
doing	O
that	O
‘	O
better	O
’	O
on	O
behalf	O
of	O
our	O
customers	O
.	O
‘	O
mobility	O
’	O
can	O
mean	O
many	O
things	O
,	O
depending	O
on	O
who	O
you	O
ask	O
.	O
for	O
hyundai	ORG
,	O
mobility	O
isn	O
’	O
t	O
just	O
about	O
cars	O
and	O
trucks	O
.	O
it	O
’	O
s	O
about	O
how	O
we	O
move	O
,	O
communicate	O
and	O
interact	O
with	O
the	O
world	O
around	O
us	LOC
.	O
in	O
hyundai	ORG
’	O
s	O
vision	O
of	O
the	O
future	O
,	O
mobility	O
is	O
environmentally	O
friendly	O
,	O
it	O
’	O
s	O
infinitely	O
connected	O
,	O
it	O
’	O
s	O
easy	O
to	O
access	O
,	O
and	O
it	O
’	O
s	O
safe	O
.	O
the	O
initiatives	O
we	O
’	O
ve	O
been	O
advancing	O
on	O
our	O
own	O
for	O
some	O
time	O
are	O
absolutely	O
helping	O
to	O
make	O
that	O
vision	O
a	O
reality	O
.	O
our	O
blue	O
link	O
telematics	O
system	O
,	O
our	O
integration	O
of	O
smartwatch	O
controls	O
and	O
amazon	PERS
alexa	O
,	O
and	O
rapid	O
adoption	O
of	O
android	O
auto	O
and	O
apple	ORG
car	O
play	O
interfaces	O
have	O
put	O
us	LOC
at	O
the	O
forefront	O
of	O
providing	O
products	O
that	O
can	O
not	O
only	O
exceed	O
the	O
automotive	O
needs	O
for	O
owners	O
,	O
but	O
actually	O
improve	O
their	O
daily	O
lives	O
.	O
the	O
newest	O
tangible	O
element	O
of	O
hyundai	ORG
’	O
s	O
mobility	O
vision	O
is	O
our	O
electrified	O
ioniq	ORG
lineup	O
.	O
ioniq	ORG
is	O
much	O
larger	O
and	O
broader	O
in	O
scale	O
than	O
just	O
a	O
fully	O
dedicated	O
platform	O
offering	O
three	O
distinct	O
propulsion	O
systems	O
.	O
it	O
really	O
serves	O
as	O
a	O
linchpin	O
for	O
all	O
our	O
future	ORG
mobility	ORG
initiatives	O
.	O
we	O
call	O
it	O
‘	O
project	O
ioniq	ORG
’	O
because	O
it	O
’	O
s	O
more	O
than	O
just	O
a	O
great	O
new	O
product—it	O
’	O
s	O
a	O
way	O
to	O
concentrate	O
thought	O
leadership	O
and	O
incubate	O
these	O
great	O
ideas	O
and	O
bring	O
them	O
to	O
life	O
.	O
the	O
ioniq	ORG
unlimited	ORG
sounds	O
like	O
it	O
is	O
hyundai	ORG
’	O
s	O
way	O
to	O
get	O
millennials	O
to	O
subscribe	O
to	O
cars	O
.	O
what	O
is	O
the	O
strategy	O
and	O
initiatives	O
for	O
the	O
novel-alternative	O
model	O
work	O
?	O
and	O
how	O
are	O
you	O
trying	O
to	O
challenge	O
convention	O
?	O
we	O
are	O
challenging	O
convention	O
by	O
listening	O
to	O
our	O
customers	O
and	O
offering	O
new	O
ways	O
for	O
our	O
customers	O
,	O
including	O
millennials	O
,	O
to	O
engage	O
with	O
and	O
experience	O
our	O
brand	O
.	O
we	O
’	O
re	O
excited	O
to	O
offer	O
ioniq	ORG
unlimited	ORG
as	O
an	O
innovative	O
,	O
worry-free	O
means	O
of	O
clean	O
,	O
zero-emission	O
vehicle	O
ownership	O
with	O
our	O
new	O
ioniq	ORG
electric	ORG
vehicle	O
.	O
this	O
new	O
ownership	O
experience	O
adds	O
to	O
the	O
satisfaction	O
of	O
driving	O
a	O
no-compromise	O
,	O
clean	O
vehicle	O
with	O
unlimited	O
mileage	O
and	O
zero	O
hidden	O
costs	O
.	O
it	O
was	O
time	O
to	O
make	O
clean	O
vehicle	O
ownership	O
easy	O
for	O
everyone	O
.	O
hyundai	ORG
cmo	O
dean	PERS
evans	PERS
how	O
do	O
you	O
see	O
subscription	O
model	O
services	O
further	O
developing	O
in	O
the	O
future	O
?	O
do	O
you	O
think	O
there	O
is	O
a	O
sustainable	O
appetite	O
in	O
the	O
space	O
among	O
consumers	O
?	O
the	O
subscription	O
model	O
will	O
be	O
simplified	O
and	O
better	O
meet	O
the	O
needs	O
of	O
our	O
customers	O
.	O
our	O
brand	O
is	O
focused	O
on	O
‘	O
better	O
’	O
—meaning	O
we	O
focus	O
on	O
improving	O
the	O
lives	O
of	O
customers	O
through	O
better	O
thinking	O
and	O
better	O
products	O
.	O
hyundai	ORG
is	O
adding	O
value	O
to	O
that	O
experience	O
,	O
by	O
creating	O
a	O
better	O
ownership	O
model	O
with	O
the	O
ioniq	ORG
unlimited	ORG
plan	O
.	O
the	O
ioniq	ORG
unlimited	ORG
plan	O
gives	O
customers	O
a	O
different	O
path	O
to	O
emission-free	O
mobility	O
while	O
eliminating	O
the	O
confusion	O
of	O
purchasing	O
or	O
leasing	O
a	O
vehicle	O
.	O
traditional	O
add-ons	O
like	O
registration	O
,	O
doc	O
fees	O
and	O
other	O
miscellaneous	O
expenses	O
are	O
included	O
,	O
so	O
the	O
price	O
you	O
see	O
is	O
the	O
price	O
you	O
pay	O
.	O
what	O
differentiates	O
the	O
ioniq	ORG
unlimited	ORG
ownership	O
experience	O
from	O
a	O
traditional	O
purchase	O
or	O
lease	O
is	O
that	O
it	O
covers	O
all	O
vehicle	O
ownership	O
and	O
operating	O
costs	O
.	O
in	O
one	O
simple	O
monthly	O
payment	O
,	O
subscribers	O
get	O
a	O
‘	O
no	O
compromise	O
’	O
ev	O
with	O
america	LOC
’	O
s	O
best	O
warranty	O
,	O
and	O
lifetime	O
battery	O
warranty	O
.	O
to	O
make	O
purchasing	O
an	O
ioniq	ORG
unlimited	ORG
subscription	O
even	O
easier	O
,	O
we	O
’	O
re	O
also	O
offering	O
a	O
unique	O
online	O
buying	O
experience	O
.	O
customers	O
can	O
select	O
a	O
vehicle	O
from	O
their	O
preferred	O
dealer	O
’	O
s	O
inventory	O
,	O
choose	O
the	O
term	O
,	O
and	O
then	O
simply	O
go	O
to	O
the	O
dealership	O
to	O
complete	O
the	O
purchase	O
.	O
at	O
the	O
dealership	O
,	O
there	O
’	O
s	O
no	O
haggling	O
or	O
hassle	O
.	O
it	O
’	O
s	O
a	O
completely	O
transparent	O
,	O
stress-free	O
and	O
an	O
entirely	O
‘	O
better	O
’	O
purchase	O
experience	O
.	O
what	O
is	O
the	O
toughest	O
task	O
when	O
it	O
comes	O
to	O
marketing	O
electric	O
,	O
hybrid	O
and	O
plug-in	O
vehicles	O
?	O
what	O
’	O
s	O
the	O
message	O
you	O
want	O
to	O
convey	O
to	O
millennial	O
consumers	O
?	O
currently	O
,	O
there	O
are	O
a	O
large	O
group	O
of	O
consumers	O
that	O
consider	O
purchasing	O
an	O
electric	O
,	O
hybrid	O
or	O
plug-in	O
vehicle	O
,	O
but	O
ultimately	O
choose	O
a	O
traditional	O
gas	O
engine	O
car	O
.	O
our	O
biggest	O
challenge	O
is	O
convincing	O
these	O
‘	O
fence	O
sitters	O
’	O
that	O
alternative-powered	O
vehicles	O
are	O
right	O
for	O
them	O
.	O
we	O
’	O
ve	O
found	O
that	O
one	O
of	O
the	O
main	O
reasons	O
they	O
don	O
’	O
t	O
select	O
an	O
electric	O
,	O
hybrid	O
or	O
plug-in	O
is	O
because	O
of	O
customer	O
anxiety	O
over	O
the	O
unknown	O
when	O
it	O
comes	O
to	O
the	O
technology	O
and	O
ownership	O
experience	O
.	O
customers	O
are	O
limited	O
many	O
times	O
by	O
either	O
lack	O
of	O
understanding	O
in	O
terms	O
of	O
the	O
lease	O
,	O
cost	O
of	O
charging	O
,	O
cost	O
of	O
ownership	O
,	O
maintenance	O
and	O
miles	O
limitations	O
of	O
these	O
newer	O
technologies	O
.	O
we	O
’	O
ve	O
listened	O
to	O
the	O
customer	O
and	O
are	O
addressing	O
these	O
challenges	O
with	O
the	O
ioniq	ORG
unlimited	ORG
program	O
.	O
we	O
simplify	O
all	O
the	O
challenges	O
,	O
we	O
answer	O
their	O
questions	O
for	O
ease	O
and	O
joy	O
of	O
ownership	O
.	O
we	O
want	O
to	O
show	O
our	O
customers	O
that	O
we	O
listened	O
to	O
their	O
concerns	O
and	O
this	O
is	O
our	O
solution	O
.	O
how	O
are	O
you	O
going	O
to	O
get	O
the	O
word	O
out	O
about	O
subscription	O
model	O
?	O
is	O
influencer	O
marketing	O
a	O
strategy	O
you	O
see	O
working	O
here	O
?	O
has	O
hyundai	ORG
had	O
success	O
with	O
influencers	O
in	O
the	O
past	O
?	O
it	O
’	O
s	O
too	O
soon	O
to	O
discuss	O
the	O
specifics	O
of	O
our	O
marketing	O
plan	O
,	O
but	O
we	O
are	O
looking	O
at	O
various	O
ways	O
of	O
communicating	O
this	O
exciting	O
new	O
ownership	O
model	O
to	O
customers	O
.	O
influencers	O
have	O
been	O
and	O
will	O
continue	O
to	O
be	O
an	O
important	O
part	O
of	O
the	O
way	O
we	O
market	O
our	O
cars	O
today	O
.	O
they	O
have	O
a	O
great	O
ability	O
to	O
reach	O
audiences	O
and	O
tell	O
stories	O
in	O
a	O
way	O
that	O
is	O
authentic	O
to	O
their	O
fans	O
.	O
why	O
is	O
it	O
critical	O
to	O
reach	O
consumers	O
interested	O
in	O
ioniq	ORG
in	O
experiential	O
ways	O
with	O
partnerships	O
like	O
waivecar	O
.	O
how	O
will	O
you	O
measure	O
the	O
success	O
of	O
this	O
specific	O
activation	O
?	O
our	O
partnership	O
with	O
waivecar	O
gives	O
consumers	O
the	O
ability	O
to	O
drive	O
ioniq	ORG
evs	ORG
on-demand	O
for	O
two	O
hours	O
at	O
no	O
charge	O
.	O
this	O
is	O
a	O
stress-free	O
,	O
commitment-free	O
way	O
for	O
potential	O
customers	O
to	O
give	O
ioniq	ORG
a	O
try	O
.	O
we	O
feel	O
these	O
types	O
of	O
opportunities	O
for	O
potential	O
customers	O
opens	O
up	O
additional	O
paths	O
for	O
customers	O
to	O
feel	O
comfortable	O
and	O
informed	O
before	O
making	O
a	O
purchase	O
decision	O
.	O
what	O
kind	O
of	O
presence	O
will	O
you	O
have	O
at	O
ces	O
?	O
what	O
can	O
we	O
expect	O
?	O
at	O
ces	O
in	O
january	O
,	O
we	O
’	O
re	O
demo-ing	O
a	O
fully	O
autonomous	O
ioniq	ORG
concept	O
on	O
the	O
neon-and-sunlit	O
boulevards	O
of	O
las	LOC
vegas	LOC
and	O
will	O
also	O
be	O
demonstrating	O
hyundai	ORG
exoskeletons	O
.	O
you	O
will	O
be	O
able	O
to	O
see	O
our	O
robotic	O
exoskeletons	O
that	O
enable	O
paraplegics	O
to	O
walk	O
again	O
,	O
empower	O
the	O
military	O
to	O
run	O
up	O
to	O
run	O
at	O
12	O
kilometers	O
per	O
hour	O
with	O
assistive	O
joint	O
torques	O
,	O
and	O
give	O
factory	O
workers	O
the	O
ability	O
to	O
lift	O
up	O
to	O
eight	O
tims	O
what	O
they	O
normally	O
can	O
with	O
ease	O
.	O
at	O
our	O
press	O
conference	O
,	O
we	O
will	O
show	O
mobility	O
and	O
eco-friendly	O
transportation—developed	O
both	O
independently	O
and	O
collaboratively	O
with	O
industry-leading	O
partners	O
demonstrate	O
future	O
technologies	O
in	O
connectivity	O
,	O
autonomous	O
driving	O
,	O
health	O
care	O
and	O
personal	O
.	O
the	O
exoskeletons	O
will	O
be	O
featured	O
along	O
with	O
12	O
additional	O
tech	O
items	O
spanning	O
the	O
connected	O
home	O
,	O
healthcare	O
and	O
autonomous	O
vehicles	O
at	O
the	O
hyundai	ORG
booth	O
.	O
follow	O
manouk	O
akopyan	O
on	O
twitter	ORG
@	O
manouk_akopyan	O
the	O
post	O
hyundai	ORG
’	O
s	O
mobility	O
vision	O
is	O
driving	O
forward	O
with	O
the	O
ioniq	ORG
unlimited	ORG
platform	O
appeared	O
first	O
on	O
alistdaily	O
.	O
hyundai	ORG
motor	ORG
reveals	O
vision	O
for	O
'future	O
mobility	O
'	O
at	O
the	O
2017	O
consumer	O
electronics	O
show	O
hyundai	ORG
motor	ORG
reveals	O
vision	O
for	O
'future	O
mobility	O
'	O
at	O
the	O
2017	O
consumer	O
electronics	O
show	O
hyundai	ORG
motor	ORG
global	O
p.r	O
.	O
team	O
headquarters	O
+82+2-3464-2153	O
globalpr	O
@	O
hyundai.com	O
all	O
contacts	O
download	O
word	O
doc	O
(	O
.doc	O
)	O
10.6kb	O
html	O
(	O
.html	O
)	O
10.6kb	O
pdf	O
(	O
.pdf	O
)	O
109.9kb	O
text	O
(	O
.txt	O
)	O
6.5kb	O
id	O
:	O
47070	O
download	O
low	O
(	O
.jpg	O
)	O
52.6kb	O
high	O
(	O
.jpg	O
)	O
394.4kb	O
hyundai	ORG
motor	ORG
america	ORG
,	O
technology	O
id	O
:	O
47085	O
hyundai	ORG
motor	ORG
showcases	O
advanced	O
self-driving	O
technology	O
through	O
urban	O
trials	O
of	O
autonomous	O
ioniq	ORG
models	O
in	O
las	LOC
vegas	LOC
strategy	O
includes	O
hyper-connected	O
car	O
platform	O
to	O
seamlessly	O
link	O
mobility	O
with	O
the	O
home	O
and	O
workplace	O
hyundai	ORG
motor	ORG
’	O
s	O
vision	O
for	O
future	ORG
mobility	ORG
incorporates	O
wearable	O
robotics	O
,	O
micro-mobility	O
solutions	O
and	O
interactive	O
,	O
health-conscious	O
technology	O
jan.	O
4	O
,	O
2017	O
–	O
hyundai	ORG
motor	ORG
is	O
showcasing	O
key	O
elements	O
of	O
its	O
strategy	O
for	O
future	ORG
mobility	ORG
at	O
the	O
consumer	O
electronics	O
show	O
(	O
ces	O
)	O
held	O
in	O
las	LOC
vegas	LOC
,	O
from	O
january	O
5	O
to	O
8	O
,	O
2017	O
.	O
this	O
next	O
generation	O
of	O
convergent	O
technologies	O
focuses	O
on	O
linking	O
cars	O
to	O
customer	O
’	O
s	O
lives	O
,	O
through	O
intelligent	O
autonomous	O
driving	O
,	O
smart	O
hyper-connectivity	O
solutions	O
and	O
innovations	O
to	O
promote	O
wellness	O
in	O
mobility	O
.	O
autonomous	O
ioniq	ORG
concepts	O
reveal	O
advanced	O
self-driving	O
technologies	O
hyundai	ORG
motor	ORG
is	O
using	O
live	O
demonstrations	O
and	O
immersive	O
virtual	O
reality	O
displays	O
to	O
present	O
the	O
capabilities	O
of	O
its	O
latest	O
self-driving	O
technology	O
.	O
two	O
cars	O
are	O
navigating	O
test	O
routes	O
in	O
the	O
las	LOC
vegas	LOC
boulevards	O
as	O
part	O
of	O
ongoing	O
advanced	O
trials	O
in	O
urban	O
environments	O
,	O
while	O
ces	O
visitors	O
can	O
experience	O
a	O
driverless	O
journey	O
via	O
immersive	O
virtual	O
reality	O
simulators	O
at	O
the	O
hyundai	ORG
motor	ORG
booth	O
.	O
moving	O
forward	O
with	O
the	O
use	O
of	O
lidar	O
technology	O
,	O
hyundai	ORG
motor	ORG
has	O
hidden	O
the	O
hardware	O
behind	O
the	O
autonomous	O
ioniq	ORG
’	O
s	O
front	O
bumper	O
rather	O
than	O
using	O
the	O
typical	O
roof-mounted	O
approach	O
,	O
retaining	O
the	O
new	O
car	O
’	O
s	O
sleek	O
design	O
.	O
hyundai	ORG
motor	ORG
’	O
s	O
latest	O
technology	O
allows	O
the	O
cars	O
to	O
navigate	O
the	O
most	O
challenging	O
situations	O
safely	O
,	O
including	O
high	O
levels	O
of	O
pedestrian	O
traffic	O
,	O
stop	O
lights	O
and	O
signs	O
,	O
road	O
construction	O
and	O
road	O
blocks	O
,	O
speed	O
bumps	O
,	O
dogs	O
,	O
small	O
children	O
and	O
even	O
intersections	O
without	O
traffic	O
signals	O
.	O
connected	O
car	O
platform	O
combines	O
intelligent	O
automotive	O
and	O
it	O
technologies	O
another	O
interactive	O
experience	O
at	O
hyundai	ORG
motor	ORG
’	O
s	O
ces	O
booth	O
demonstrates	O
how	O
the	O
‘	O
hyper-connected	O
car	O
’	O
will	O
be	O
central	O
to	O
buying	O
greater	O
convenience	O
,	O
comfort	O
and	O
enjoyment	O
to	O
tomorrow	O
’	O
s	O
lifestyles	O
.	O
with	O
an	O
objective	O
to	O
create	O
hyper-connected	O
intelligent	O
cars	O
that	O
boast	O
the	O
safest	O
and	O
most	O
advanced	O
self-driving	O
systems	O
on	O
the	O
market	O
,	O
hyundai	ORG
motor	ORG
is	O
collaborating	O
with	O
cisco	ORG
,	O
a	O
worldwide	O
leader	O
in	O
it	O
and	O
security	O
technology	O
.	O
the	O
joint	O
program	O
will	O
create	O
a	O
platform	O
optimized	O
for	O
connected	O
cars	O
,	O
which	O
will	O
help	O
enable	O
two-way	O
communication	O
both	O
internally	O
between	O
the	O
car	O
’	O
s	O
system	O
and	O
externally	O
with	O
road	O
infrastructure	O
,	O
other	O
vehicles	O
,	O
internet	O
of	O
things	O
(	O
lot	O
)	O
devices	O
,	O
and	O
the	O
cloud	O
.	O
‘	O
mobility	O
vision	O
’	O
concept	O
converges	O
hyper-connectivity	O
and	O
smart	O
house	O
through	O
its	O
innovative	O
‘	O
mobility	O
vision	O
’	O
concept	O
,	O
hyundai	ORG
motor	ORG
is	O
demonstrating	O
the	O
potential	O
reach	O
of	O
its	O
advanced	O
technologies	O
.	O
the	O
smart	O
house	O
concept	O
shown	O
at	O
ces	O
seamlessly	O
integrates	O
the	O
car	O
into	O
the	O
daily	O
lives	O
of	O
users	O
,	O
blurring	O
the	O
line	O
between	O
mobility	O
and	O
customer	O
’	O
s	O
living	O
and	O
working	O
spaces	O
.	O
the	O
concept	O
on	O
show	O
suggests	O
how	O
the	O
car	O
could	O
integrate	O
itself	O
with	O
the	O
living	O
space	O
when	O
docked	O
,	O
before	O
becoming	O
a	O
mobile	O
living	O
space	O
when	O
customers	O
need	O
to	O
move	O
around	O
.	O
hyundai	ORG
motor	ORG
’	O
s	O
vision	O
sees	O
customers	O
living	O
,	O
without	O
interruption	O
,	O
while	O
on	O
the	O
move	O
as	O
the	O
comfort	O
,	O
convenience	O
and	O
connectivity	O
features	O
of	O
the	O
car	O
and	O
the	O
home	O
are	O
combined	O
into	O
‘	O
one	O
space	O
’	O
.	O
health	O
+	O
mobility	O
concept	O
for	O
wellness	O
in	O
mobility	O
also	O
at	O
ces	O
,	O
hyundai	ORG
motor	ORG
is	O
presenting	O
‘	O
health	O
+	O
mobility	O
concept	O
’	O
,	O
its	O
future	O
vision	O
for	O
health-conscious	O
vehicles	O
that	O
connect	O
mobility	O
and	O
wellness	O
.	O
an	O
immersive	O
virtual	O
reality	O
room	O
demonstrates	O
how	O
in-car	O
conditions	O
can	O
be	O
created	O
to	O
better	O
manage	O
stress	O
and	O
associated	O
consequences	O
resulting	O
from	O
commuting	O
,	O
allowing	O
drivers	O
to	O
intentionally	O
shift	O
modes	O
for	O
increased	O
personal	O
productivity	O
or	O
relaxation	O
.	O
the	O
interactive	O
health-conscious	O
technology	O
monitors	O
a	O
suite	O
of	O
health	O
and	O
wellbeing	O
indicators	O
via	O
a	O
series	O
of	O
sensors	O
throughout	O
the	O
cockpit	O
.	O
wearable	O
robotics	O
offer	O
new	O
freedom	O
in	O
mobility	O
hyundai	ORG
motor	ORG
has	O
revealed	O
new	O
wearable	O
powered	O
robots	O
that	O
are	O
set	O
to	O
revolutionize	O
the	O
future	O
of	O
personal	O
mobility	O
.	O
the	O
latest	O
innovations	O
in	O
advanced	O
assistive	O
exoskeletons	O
for	O
medical	O
,	O
work	O
and	O
daily	O
life	O
reveal	O
the	O
company	O
’	O
s	O
ambition	O
to	O
provide	O
assisted-mobility	O
support	O
beyond	O
the	O
automobile	O
for	O
the	O
well-being	O
of	O
customers	O
.	O
the	O
range	O
of	O
wearable	O
exoskeletons	O
presented	O
at	O
ces	O
feature	O
on-board	O
motion	O
control	O
systems	O
to	O
support	O
patients	O
with	O
lower	O
spinal	O
cord	O
injuries	O
,	O
or	O
provide	O
stroll	O
support	O
for	O
the	O
elderly	O
in	O
everyday	O
life	O
.	O
a	O
workplace-focused	O
exoskeleton	O
provides	O
upper-body	O
and	O
hip	O
support	O
to	O
prevent	O
back	O
injuries	O
for	O
workers	O
lifting	O
heavy	O
objects	O
.	O
ioniq	ORG
scooter	ORG
provides	O
final-mile	O
mobility	O
hyundai	ORG
motor	ORG
has	O
unveiled	O
the	O
ioniq	ORG
scooter	ORG
,	O
an	O
innovative	O
portable-mobility	O
concept	O
that	O
allows	O
customers	O
to	O
continue	O
their	O
journey	O
after	O
parking	O
to	O
easily	O
reach	O
their	O
final	O
destination	O
.	O
the	O
lightweight	O
,	O
electrically-powered	O
scooter	O
is	O
conveniently	O
stored	O
and	O
charged	O
in	O
the	O
front	O
door	O
of	O
the	O
ioniq	ORG
electric	ORG
,	O
with	O
an	O
easy	O
one-touch	O
folding	O
structure	O
for	O
maximized	O
portability	O
.	O
the	O
scooter	O
is	O
the	O
result	O
of	O
a	O
study	O
into	O
alternatives	O
for	O
‘	O
first-and-last	O
mile	O
mobility	O
’	O
,	O
and	O
is	O
another	O
innovation	O
from	O
hyundai	ORG
motor	ORG
’	O
s	O
long-term	O
research	O
and	O
development	O
program	O
,	O
project	O
ioniq	ORG
,	O
which	O
works	O
to	O
redefine	O
future	ORG
mobility	ORG
through	O
innovation	O
.	O
also	O
on	O
display	O
at	O
the	O
hyundai	ORG
motor	ORG
booth	O
at	O
ces	O
is	O
the	O
latest	O
ioniq	ORG
hybrid	ORG
model	O
,	O
which	O
includes	O
enhancements	O
to	O
further	O
its	O
reputation	O
as	O
one	O
of	O
the	O
world	O
’	O
s	O
most	O
fuel	O
efficient	O
cars	O
.	O
hyundai	ORG
motor	ORG
company	ORG
established	O
in	O
1967	O
,	O
hyundai	ORG
motor	ORG
company	ORG
is	O
committed	O
to	O
becoming	O
a	O
lifetime	O
partner	O
in	O
automobiles	O
and	O
beyond	O
.	O
the	O
company	O
leads	O
the	O
hyundai	ORG
motor	ORG
group	ORG
,	O
an	O
innovative	O
business	O
structure	O
capable	O
of	O
circulating	O
resources	O
from	O
molten	O
iron	O
to	O
finished	O
cars	O
.	O
hyundai	ORG
motor	ORG
has	O
eight	O
manufacturing	O
bases	O
and	O
seven	O
design	O
&	O
technical	O
centers	O
worldwide	O
and	O
in	O
2015	O
sold	O
4.96	O
million	O
vehicles	O
globally	O
.	O
with	O
more	O
than	O
110,000	O
employees	O
worldwide	O
,	O
hyundai	ORG
motor	ORG
continues	O
to	O
enhance	O
its	O
product	O
line-up	O
with	O
localised	O
models	O
and	O
strives	O
to	O
strengthen	O
its	O
leadership	O
in	O
clean	O
technology	O
,	O
starting	O
with	O
the	O
world	O
’	O
s	O
first	O
mass-produced	O
hydrogen-powered	O
vehicle	O
,	O
tucson	O
fuel	O
cell	O
and	O
ioniq	ORG
,	O
the	O
world	O
’	O
s	O
first	O
model	O
with	O
three	O
electrified	O
powertrains	O
.	O
more	O
information	O
about	O
hyundai	ORG
motor	ORG
and	O
its	O
products	O
can	O
be	O
found	O
at	O
:	O
http	O
:	O
//worldwide.hyundai.com	O
or	O
http	O
:	O
//globalpr.hyundai.com/	O
1	O
hyundai	ORG
motor	ORG
demonstrates	O
'mobility	O
vision	O
'	O
with	O
hyper-connected	O
car	O
and	O
smart	O
house	O
2	O
hyundai	ORG
motor	ORG
company	ORG
introduces	O
a	O
health	O
+	O
mobility	O
concept	O
for	O
wellness	O
in	O
mobility	O
3	O
hyundai	ORG
motor	ORG
showcases	O
autonomous	O
technology	O
at	O
the	O
2017	O
consumer	O
electronics	O
show	O
in	O
las	LOC
vegas	LOC
4	O
hyundai	ORG
motor	ORG
reveals	O
future	O
vision	O
for	O
connected	O
cars	O
hyundai	ORG
shares	O
vision	O
for	O
future	ORG
mobility	ORG
at	O
ces	O
hyundai	ORG
is	O
preparing	O
to	O
preview	O
its	O
vision	O
for	O
future	ORG
mobility	ORG
with	O
a	O
focus	O
on	O
vehicle	O
autonomy	O
and	O
high-level	O
connectivity	O
at	O
the	O
consumer	O
electronics	O
show	O
in	O
las	LOC
vegas	LOC
in	O
january	O
.	O
using	O
the	O
korean	O
company	O
’	O
s	O
new	O
ioniq	ORG
models	O
as	O
a	O
starting	O
point	O
,	O
an	O
autonomous	O
fleet	O
will	O
operate	O
on	O
test	O
routes	O
around	O
the	O
ces	O
site	O
,	O
while	O
inside	O
the	O
halls	O
visitors	O
will	O
be	O
able	O
to	O
experience	O
a	O
simulated	O
autonomous	O
ride	O
via	O
immersive	O
virtual	O
reality	O
.	O
so	O
called	O
‘	O
last	O
mile	O
’	O
mobility	O
will	O
also	O
be	O
covered	O
,	O
with	O
hyundai	ORG
presenting	O
its	O
micro	O
mobility	O
concept	O
.	O
though	O
no	O
images	O
have	O
been	O
released	O
yet	O
,	O
hyundai	ORG
says	O
last	O
mile	O
mobility	O
is	O
the	O
concept	O
of	O
taking	O
cars	O
and	O
congestion	O
out	O
of	O
city	O
centres	O
by	O
shifting	O
drivers	O
out	O
of	O
vehicles	O
and	O
into	O
other	O
,	O
more	O
compact	O
forms	O
of	O
transport	O
to	O
complete	O
the	O
last	O
part	O
of	O
their	O
journey	O
.	O
hyundai	ORG
isn	O
’	O
t	O
drawing	O
the	O
line	O
at	O
vehicle	O
technology	O
either	O
with	O
a	O
range	O
of	O
concepts	O
including	O
hyundai	ORG
’	O
s	O
motor	O
vision	O
which	O
brings	O
together	O
smart	O
house	O
and	O
connected	O
car	O
systems	O
(	O
with	O
the	O
help	O
of	O
it	O
firm	O
,	O
cisco	ORG
)	O
to	O
blur	O
the	O
lines	O
between	O
mobility	O
,	O
living	O
,	O
and	O
working	O
spaces	O
.	O
hyundai	ORG
will	O
also	O
present	O
a	O
range	O
of	O
advanced	O
wearable	O
exoskeletons	O
providing	O
assistance	O
for	O
customers	O
with	O
restricted	O
mobility	O
,	O
or	O
for	O
those	O
required	O
to	O
undertake	O
strenuous	O
,	O
or	O
repetitive	O
work	O
.	O
more	O
:	O
hyundai	ORG
news	O
and	O
reviews	O
previous	O
ford	ORG
next-gen	O
autonomous	O
development	O
vehicle	O
to	O
make	O
ces	O
debut	O
next	O
volkswagen	O
turns	O
to	O
video	O
game	O
experts	O
in	O
new	O
recruitment	O
push	O
get	O
the	O
best	O
deal	O
on	O
this	O
car	O
!	O
get	O
a	O
great	O
deal	O
from	O
our	O
national	O
accredited	O
supply	O
network	O
.	O
fill	O
in	O
the	O
form	O
or	O
call	O
1300	O
438	O
639	O
name	O
required	O
last	O
name	O
should	O
be	O
a	O
hidden	O
field	O
.	O
please	O
delete	O
if	O
you	O
are	O
a	O
real	O
person	O
.	O
valid	O
phone	O
required	O
valid	O
postcode	O
required	O
valid	O
email	O
required	O
thank	O
you	O
for	O
your	O
enquiry	O
.	O
one	O
of	O
our	O
accredited	O
supply	O
network	O
will	O
be	O
in	O
touch	O
in	O
the	O
next	O
24	O
hours	O
.	O
search	O
again	O
tweet	O
published	O
29-dec-2016	O
follow	O
kez	O
casey	O
on	O
filed	O
under	O
hyundai	ORG
technology	O
news	O
autonomous	O
consumer	O
electronics	O
show	O
infotainment	O
2017	O
hyundai	ORG
ioniq	ORG
2017	O
hyundai	ORG
ces	O
technology	O
view	O
more	O
images	O
mayor	O
walsh	PERS
releases	O
go	ORG
boston	ORG
2030	O
vision	O
and	O
action	O
plan	O
to	O
guide	O
city	O
's	O
transportation	O
future	O
mayor	O
walsh	PERS
releases	O
go	ORG
boston	ORG
2030	O
vision	O
and	O
action	O
plan	O
to	O
guide	O
city	O
's	O
transportation	O
future	O
plan	O
is	O
comprised	O
of	O
58	O
projects	O
and	O
policies	O
to	O
direct	O
the	O
city	O
of	O
boston	LOC
's	O
transportation	O
agenda	O
for	O
the	O
next	O
decade	O
and	O
beyond	O
boston	LOC
-	O
tuesday	O
,	O
march	O
7	O
,	O
2017-	O
mayor	O
martin	PERS
j.	PERS
walsh	PERS
today	O
released	O
the	O
go	ORG
boston	ORG
2030	O
vision	O
and	O
action	O
plan	O
that	O
will	O
direct	O
the	O
city	O
of	O
boston	LOC
's	O
transportation	O
agenda	O
for	O
the	O
next	O
decade	O
and	O
beyond	O
.	O
the	O
plan	O
is	O
comprised	O
of	O
58	O
transportation	O
projects	O
and	O
policies	O
that	O
are	O
designed	O
to	O
expand	O
access	O
to	O
a	O
variety	O
of	O
connected	O
transportation	O
options	O
,	O
improve	O
traffic-related	O
safety	O
on	O
boston	LOC
's	O
streets	O
,	O
and	O
ensure	O
reliability	O
of	O
service	O
for	O
the	O
city	O
's	O
residents	O
,	O
commuters	O
and	O
visitors	O
.	O
the	O
plan	O
highlights	O
projects	O
already	O
underway	O
and	O
presents	O
a	O
blueprint	O
for	O
the	O
city	O
to	O
direct	O
its	O
capital	O
plan	O
funding	O
.	O
``	O
go	ORG
boston	ORG
2030	O
addresses	O
the	O
transportation	O
challenges	O
that	O
we	O
face	O
as	O
a	O
city	O
and	O
a	O
region	O
,	O
and	O
lays	O
the	O
foundation	O
for	O
how	O
we	O
can	O
create	O
a	O
safer	O
,	O
more	O
equitable	O
transportation	O
future	O
,	O
''	O
said	O
mayor	O
walsh	PERS
.	O
``	O
shaped	O
by	O
the	O
feedback	O
from	O
thousands	O
of	O
residents	O
,	O
the	O
action	O
plan	O
includes	O
both	O
short	O
and	O
long-term	O
projects	O
that	O
will	O
create	O
greater	O
transportation	O
access	O
that	O
is	O
reliable	O
and	O
safe	O
for	O
all	O
users	O
of	O
our	O
city	O
's	O
streets	O
.	O
altogether	O
,	O
the	O
initiatives	O
in	O
this	O
plan	O
will	O
connect	O
people	O
to	O
the	O
region	O
's	O
fastest	O
growing	O
job	O
centers	O
,	O
tackle	O
transportation	O
inequality	O
,	O
prepare	O
our	O
transportation	O
networks	O
for	O
climate	O
change	O
and	O
increase	O
economic	O
mobility	O
for	O
the	O
people	O
of	O
boston	LOC
.	O
''	O
the	O
``	O
top	O
policies	O
and	O
projects	O
''	O
of	O
the	O
go	ORG
boston	ORG
2030	O
vision	O
and	O
action	O
plan	O
include	O
:	O
walking	O
and	O
bicycle	O
friendly	O
main	O
street	O
districts	O
-	O
improve	O
access	O
into	O
and	O
around	O
boston	LOC
's	O
neighborhood	O
commercial	O
districts	O
for	O
people	O
traveling	O
on	O
foot	O
and	O
by	O
bike	O
.	O
fairmount	O
line	O
service	O
improvements	O
and	O
urban	O
rail	O
-	O
provide	O
improved	O
connections	O
for	O
dorchester	O
and	O
mattapan	O
with	O
an	O
increase	O
to	O
the	O
frequency	O
of	O
service	O
and	O
better	O
payment	O
systems	O
,	O
and	O
then	O
introduce	O
new	O
rail	O
cars	O
to	O
create	O
a	O
rapid	O
transit	O
line	O
.	O
columbia	O
road	O
greenway	O
-	O
create	O
a	O
neighborhood	O
friendly	O
street	O
for	O
those	O
walking	O
,	O
biking	O
,	O
or	O
traveling	O
by	O
bus	O
along	O
this	O
corridor	O
,	O
that	O
connects	O
to	O
franklin	O
and	O
moakley	O
parks	O
.	O
neighborhood	O
mobility	ORG
microhubs	ORG
-	O
develop	O
prominent	O
neighborhood	O
access	O
points	O
to	O
help	O
residents	O
select	O
from	O
a	O
range	O
of	O
connected	O
travel	O
choices	O
including	O
subway	O
,	O
bus	O
,	O
bike-share	O
and	O
car-share	O
.	O
smart	O
signal	O
corridors	O
and	O
districts	O
-	O
program	O
traffic	O
lights	O
to	O
work	O
together	O
to	O
facilitate	O
movement	O
in	O
congested	O
parts	O
of	O
the	O
city	O
.	O
mattapan	O
to	O
lma	O
rapid	O
bus	O
-	O
design	O
high-quality	O
stops	O
,	O
signal	O
priority	O
,	O
all-door	O
boarding	O
,	O
and	O
some	O
exclusive	O
lanes	O
to	O
create	O
direct	O
access	O
from	O
mattapan	O
and	O
southwest	O
dorchester	O
to	O
jobs	O
and	O
medical	O
care	O
in	O
roxbury	O
,	O
mission	O
hill	O
,	O
and	O
the	O
longwood	O
medical	O
and	O
academic	O
area	O
.	O
north	O
station	O
to	O
south	O
boston	LOC
waterfront	O
rapid	O
bus	O
and	O
ferry	O
-	O
introduce	O
direct	O
bus	O
service	O
in	O
exclusive	O
lanes	O
between	O
the	O
seaport	O
and	O
northern	O
commuter	O
rail	O
in	O
tandem	O
with	O
ferry	O
service	O
.	O
top	O
policies	O
vision	O
zero	O
safety	O
initiatives	O
-	O
continue	O
to	O
implement	O
innovative	O
measures	O
to	O
reduce	O
traffic-related	O
fatalities	O
and	O
severe	O
injuries	O
due	O
to	O
crashes	O
on	O
boston	LOC
's	O
local	O
streets	O
.	O
state	O
of	O
good	O
repair	O
-	O
investments	O
by	O
the	O
city	O
to	O
repair	O
and	O
maintain	O
boston	LOC
's	O
roadways	O
and	O
bridges	O
for	O
the	O
decades	O
ahead	O
.	O
restructure	O
bus	O
routes	O
-	O
work	O
with	O
the	O
mbta	O
and	O
local	O
communities	O
to	O
develop	O
a	O
new	O
network	O
of	O
bus	O
routes	O
that	O
better	O
match	O
the	O
travel	O
needs	O
of	O
bostonians	O
.	O
autonomous	O
vehicles	O
-	O
develop	O
policies	O
to	O
prepare	O
for	O
self-driving	O
vehicles	O
and	O
support	O
on-street	O
testing	O
of	O
autonomous	O
vehicles	O
.	O
``	O
boston	LOC
is	O
booming	O
,	O
with	O
new	O
housing	O
and	O
new	O
businesses	O
opening	O
up	O
and	O
even	O
more	O
on	O
the	O
way	O
,	O
''	O
said	O
city	O
of	O
boston	LOC
chief	LOC
of	O
streets	O
chris	O
osgood	O
.	O
``	O
with	O
the	O
go	ORG
boston	ORG
2030	O
vision	O
and	O
action	O
plan	O
,	O
we	O
now	O
have	O
a	O
framework	O
to	O
provide	O
connections	O
between	O
boston	LOC
's	O
neighborhoods	O
and	O
to	O
new	O
job	O
centers	O
,	O
allowing	O
people	O
to	O
access	O
them	O
using	O
transportation	O
options	O
that	O
are	O
affordable	O
,	O
efficient	O
and	O
enjoyable.	O
''	O
``	O
in	O
2015	O
,	O
mayor	O
walsh	PERS
directed	O
btd	O
to	O
develop	O
a	O
plan	O
to	O
make	O
transportation	O
improvements	O
that	O
would	O
benefit	O
all	O
of	O
boston	LOC
's	O
diverse	O
communities	O
in	O
all	O
of	O
the	O
city	O
's	O
neighborhoods	O
,	O
in	O
both	O
the	O
short	O
and	O
the	O
long-term	O
,	O
''	O
said	O
boston	ORG
transportation	ORG
commissioner	O
gina	PERS
n.	PERS
fiandaca	PERS
.	O
``	O
an	O
unprecedented	O
public	O
engagement	O
process	O
was	O
undertaken	O
that	O
led	O
to	O
thousands	O
of	O
ideas	O
and	O
comments	O
being	O
submitted	O
by	O
residents	O
and	O
stakeholders	O
.	O
this	O
plan	O
,	O
and	O
the	O
aspirational	O
goals	O
and	O
targets	O
that	O
are	O
established	O
and	O
prioritized	O
in	O
it	O
,	O
is	O
the	O
direct	O
result	O
of	O
that	O
collaborative	O
process	O
.	O
''	O
five	O
thousand	O
ideas	O
were	O
submitted	O
to	O
the	O
city	O
during	O
the	O
first	O
round	O
of	O
the	O
public	O
engagement	O
process	O
,	O
helping	O
to	O
set	O
the	O
project	O
's	O
goals	O
and	O
metrics	O
.	O
moving	O
forward	O
from	O
goals	O
to	O
specific	O
projects	O
,	O
the	O
public	O
submitted	O
another	O
3,500	O
policy	O
and	O
project	O
ideas	O
.	O
after	O
analyzing	O
these	O
ideas	O
,	O
nearly	O
4,000	O
boston	LOC
residents	O
and	O
others	O
helped	O
to	O
prioritize	O
them	O
by	O
voting	O
for	O
their	O
top	O
choices	O
of	O
projects	O
.	O
several	O
go	ORG
boston	ORG
2030	O
projects	O
are	O
already	O
underway	O
and	O
are	O
having	O
a	O
positive	O
impact	O
on	O
the	O
city	O
's	O
streets	O
,	O
including	O
:	O
vision	O
zero	O
neighborhood	O
slow	O
streets	O
parkboston	O
performance	O
pricing	O
parking	O
meter	O
pilot	O
program	O
boston	LOC
's	O
safest	O
driver	O
contest	O
autonomous	O
vehicle	O
testing	O
driveboston	O
car-share	O
program	O
expansion	O
of	O
hubway	O
bike-share	O
program	O
installation	O
of	O
protected	O
bike	O
lanes	O
.	O
information	O
on	O
all	O
of	O
these	O
programs	O
can	O
be	O
found	O
at	O
www.boston.gov/transportation	O
.	O
``	O
the	O
vision	O
and	O
action	O
plan	O
represents	O
a	O
milestone	O
for	O
every	O
resident	O
in	O
the	O
city	O
because	O
it	O
the	O
first	O
time	O
that	O
a	O
plan	O
made	O
by	O
residents	O
,	O
for	O
residents	O
,	O
will	O
lead	O
to	O
better	O
travel	O
choices	O
for	O
neighborhoods	O
by	O
creating	O
more	O
equitable	O
distribution	O
of	O
investment	O
in	O
transportation	O
infrastructure	O
,	O
''	O
said	O
representative	O
russell	PERS
e.	PERS
holmes	PERS
(	O
d-mattapan	O
)	O
and	O
co-chair	O
of	O
go	ORG
boston	ORG
2030	O
.	O
``	O
it	O
is	O
gratifying	O
that	O
go	ORG
boston	ORG
listened	O
when	O
people	O
stepped	O
forward	O
to	O
say	O
that	O
our	O
transportation	O
must	O
foster	O
opportunity	O
across	O
neighborhoods	O
by	O
connecting	O
the	O
workforce	O
with	O
key	O
job	O
centers	O
.	O
this	O
bold	O
plan	O
will	O
serve	O
as	O
a	O
blueprint	O
for	O
communities	O
moving	O
forward	O
and	O
will	O
keep	O
boston	LOC
a	O
leader	O
among	O
world-class	O
cities	O
.	O
''	O
the	O
go	ORG
boston	ORG
2030	O
vision	O
and	O
action	O
plan	O
provides	O
a	O
blueprint	O
for	O
the	O
city	O
of	O
boston	LOC
to	O
direct	O
its	O
capital	O
plan	O
spending	O
and	O
to	O
work	O
with	O
state	O
transportation	O
agencies	O
to	O
begin	O
implementation	O
.	O
the	O
city	O
is	O
committing	O
to	O
a	O
five	O
year	O
investment	O
plan	O
in	O
order	O
to	O
jump-start	O
implementation	O
of	O
the	O
policies	O
and	O
projects	O
identified	O
in	O
the	O
go	ORG
boston	ORG
2030	O
action	O
plan	O
.	O
the	O
city	O
will	O
leverage	O
city	O
funding	O
to	O
attract	O
state	O
funding	O
through	O
the	O
boston	ORG
region	ORG
metropolitan	ORG
planning	ORG
organization	ORG
(	O
mpo	ORG
.	O
)	O
the	O
city	O
will	O
seek	O
development	O
mitigation	O
to	O
contribute	O
to	O
building	O
streets	O
and	O
sidewalks	O
to	O
enhance	O
public	O
investment	O
.	O
the	O
city	O
will	O
work	O
with	O
surrounding	O
cities	O
and	O
towns	O
to	O
connect	O
transportation	O
networks	O
cost-effectively	O
.	O
the	O
city	O
will	O
establish	O
a	O
go	ORG
boston	ORG
2030	O
mobility	ORG
lab	ORG
in	O
partnership	O
with	O
academia	O
and	O
stakeholders	O
to	O
track	O
progress	O
toward	O
achieving	O
its	O
goals	O
and	O
to	O
experiment	O
with	O
new	O
technology	O
,	O
with	O
an	O
eye	O
toward	O
accountability	O
.	O
``	O
the	O
go	ORG
boston	ORG
2030	O
vision	O
and	O
action	O
plan	O
is	O
a	O
tremendous	O
effort	O
that	O
brings	O
together	O
,	O
for	O
the	O
first	O
time	O
,	O
ideas	O
from	O
residents	O
,	O
stakeholders	O
and	O
the	O
business	O
community	O
,	O
delivering	O
a	O
result	O
that	O
is	O
ambitious	O
,	O
bold	O
and	O
truly	O
exciting	O
,	O
''	O
said	O
richard	PERS
a.	PERS
dimino	PERS
,	O
president	O
&	O
ceo	O
of	O
a	O
better	LOC
city	LOC
and	O
co-chair	O
of	O
go	ORG
boston	ORG
2030	O
.	O
``	O
from	O
the	O
perspective	O
of	O
the	O
business	O
community	O
,	O
the	O
plan	O
will	O
move	O
the	O
city	O
forward	O
because	O
it	O
is	O
squarely	O
focused	O
on	O
improving	O
mobility	O
,	O
including	O
by	O
protecting	O
infrastructure	O
that	O
is	O
vulnerable	O
to	O
sea	O
level	O
rise	O
and	O
extreme	O
weather	O
events	O
.	O
the	O
future	O
success	O
of	O
boston	LOC
depends	O
in	O
large	O
part	O
upon	O
its	O
ability	O
to	O
support	O
employer	O
and	O
worker	O
populations	O
that	O
demand	O
a	O
built	O
environment	O
with	O
a	O
fully	O
connected	O
network	O
of	O
walking	O
,	O
cycling	O
,	O
ride-sharing	O
and	O
transit	O
riding	O
choices	O
.	O
''	O
go	ORG
boston	ORG
2030	O
reflects	O
a	O
partnership	O
between	O
several	O
public	O
agencies	O
and	O
,	O
in	O
particular	O
,	O
complements	O
the	O
imagine	O
boston	LOC
2030	O
and	O
climate	O
ready	O
boston	LOC
initiatives	O
.	O
the	O
go	ORG
boston	ORG
2030	O
public	O
process	O
will	O
continue	O
through	O
the	O
execution	O
of	O
individual	O
projects	O
,	O
with	O
policies	O
and	O
projects	O
receiving	O
a	O
more	O
in-depth	O
planning	O
process	O
at	O
the	O
local	O
level	O
,	O
including	O
through	O
further	O
collaboration	O
with	O
residents	O
and	O
other	O
stakeholders	O
.	O
for	O
more	O
information	O
on	O
go	ORG
boston	ORG
2030	O
,	O
please	O
visit	O
here	O
.	O
mayor	O
walsh	PERS
releases	O
go	ORG
boston	ORG
2030	O
vision	O
and	O
action	O
plan	O
to	O
guide	O
city	O
’	O
s	O
transportation	O
future	O
mayor	O
martin	PERS
j.	PERS
walsh	PERS
today	O
released	O
the	O
go	ORG
boston	ORG
2030	O
vision	O
and	O
action	O
plan	O
that	O
will	O
direct	O
the	O
city	O
of	O
boston	LOC
’	O
s	O
transportation	O
agenda	O
for	O
the	O
next	O
decade	O
and	O
beyond	O
.	O
the	O
plan	O
is	O
comprised	O
of	O
58	O
transportation	O
projects	O
and	O
policies	O
that	O
are	O
designed	O
to	O
expand	O
access	O
to	O
a	O
variety	O
of	O
connected	O
transportation	O
options	O
,	O
improve	O
traffic-related	O
safety	O
on	O
boston	LOC
’	O
s	O
streets	O
,	O
and	O
ensure	O
reliability	O
of	O
service	O
for	O
the	O
city	O
’	O
s	O
residents	O
,	O
commuters	O
and	O
visitors	O
.	O
the	O
plan	O
highlights	O
projects	O
already	O
underway	O
and	O
presents	O
a	O
blueprint	O
for	O
the	O
city	O
to	O
direct	O
its	O
capital	O
plan	O
funding	O
.	O
“	O
go	ORG
boston	ORG
2030	O
addresses	O
the	O
transportation	O
challenges	O
that	O
we	O
face	O
as	O
a	O
city	O
and	O
a	O
region	O
,	O
and	O
lays	O
the	O
foundation	O
for	O
how	O
we	O
can	O
create	O
a	O
safer	O
,	O
more	O
equitable	O
transportation	O
future	O
,	O
”	O
said	O
mayor	O
walsh	PERS
.	O
“	O
shaped	O
by	O
the	O
feedback	O
from	O
thousands	O
of	O
residents	O
,	O
the	O
action	O
plan	O
includes	O
both	O
short	O
and	O
long-term	O
projects	O
that	O
will	O
create	O
greater	O
transportation	O
access	O
that	O
is	O
reliable	O
and	O
safe	O
for	O
all	O
users	O
of	O
our	O
city	O
’	O
s	O
streets	O
.	O
altogether	O
,	O
the	O
initiatives	O
in	O
this	O
plan	O
will	O
connect	O
people	O
to	O
the	O
region	O
’	O
s	O
fastest	O
growing	O
job	O
centers	O
,	O
tackle	O
transportation	O
inequality	O
,	O
prepare	O
our	O
transportation	O
networks	O
for	O
climate	O
change	O
and	O
increase	O
economic	O
mobility	O
for	O
the	O
people	O
of	O
boston.	O
”	O
the	O
“	O
top	O
policies	O
and	O
projects	O
”	O
of	O
the	O
go	ORG
boston	ORG
2030	O
vision	O
and	O
action	O
plan	O
include	O
:	O
walking	O
and	O
bicycle	O
friendly	O
main	O
street	O
districts	O
–	O
improve	O
access	O
into	O
and	O
around	O
boston	LOC
’	O
s	O
neighborhood	O
commercial	O
districts	O
for	O
people	O
traveling	O
on	O
foot	O
and	O
by	O
bike	O
.	O
fairmount	O
line	O
service	O
improvements	O
and	O
urban	O
rail	O
–	O
provide	O
improved	O
connections	O
for	O
dorchester	O
and	O
mattapan	O
with	O
an	O
increase	O
to	O
the	O
frequency	O
of	O
service	O
and	O
better	O
payment	O
systems	O
,	O
and	O
then	O
introduce	O
new	O
rail	O
cars	O
to	O
create	O
a	O
rapid	O
transit	O
line	O
.	O
columbia	O
road	O
greenway	O
–	O
create	O
a	O
neighborhood	O
friendly	O
street	O
for	O
those	O
walking	O
,	O
biking	O
,	O
or	O
traveling	O
by	O
bus	O
along	O
this	O
corridor	O
,	O
that	O
connects	O
to	O
franklin	O
and	O
moakley	O
parks	O
.	O
neighborhood	O
mobility	ORG
microhubs	ORG
–	O
develop	O
prominent	O
neighborhood	O
access	O
points	O
to	O
help	O
residents	O
select	O
from	O
a	O
range	O
of	O
connected	O
travel	O
choices	O
including	O
subway	O
,	O
bus	O
,	O
bike-share	O
and	O
car-share	O
.	O
smart	O
signal	O
corridors	O
and	O
districts	O
–	O
program	O
traffic	O
lights	O
to	O
work	O
together	O
to	O
facilitate	O
movement	O
in	O
congested	O
parts	O
of	O
the	O
city	O
.	O
mattapan	O
to	O
lma	O
rapid	O
bus	O
–	O
design	O
high-quality	O
stops	O
,	O
signal	O
priority	O
,	O
all-door	O
boarding	O
,	O
and	O
some	O
exclusive	O
lanes	O
to	O
create	O
direct	O
access	O
from	O
mattapan	O
and	O
southwest	O
dorchester	O
to	O
jobs	O
and	O
medical	O
care	O
in	O
roxbury	O
,	O
mission	O
hill	O
,	O
and	O
the	O
longwood	O
medical	O
and	O
academic	O
area	O
.	O
north	O
station	O
to	O
south	O
boston	LOC
waterfront	O
rapid	O
bus	O
and	O
ferry	O
–	O
introduce	O
direct	O
bus	O
service	O
in	O
exclusive	O
lanes	O
between	O
the	O
seaport	O
and	O
northern	O
commuter	O
rail	O
in	O
tandem	O
with	O
ferry	O
service	O
.	O
top	O
policies	O
vision	O
zero	O
safety	O
initiatives	O
–	O
continue	O
to	O
implement	O
innovative	O
measures	O
to	O
reduce	O
traffic-related	O
fatalities	O
and	O
severe	O
injuries	O
due	O
to	O
crashes	O
on	O
boston	LOC
’	O
s	O
local	O
streets	O
.	O
state	O
of	O
good	O
repair	O
–	O
investments	O
by	O
the	O
city	O
to	O
repair	O
and	O
maintain	O
boston	LOC
’	O
s	O
roadways	O
and	O
bridges	O
for	O
the	O
decades	O
ahead	O
.	O
restructure	O
bus	O
routes	O
–	O
work	O
with	O
the	O
mbta	O
and	O
local	O
communities	O
to	O
develop	O
a	O
new	O
network	O
of	O
bus	O
routes	O
that	O
better	O
match	O
the	O
travel	O
needs	O
of	O
bostonians	O
.	O
autonomous	O
vehicles	O
–	O
develop	O
policies	O
to	O
prepare	O
for	O
self-driving	O
vehicles	O
and	O
support	O
on-street	O
testing	O
of	O
autonomous	O
vehicles	O
.	O
“	O
boston	LOC
is	O
booming	O
,	O
with	O
new	O
housing	O
and	O
new	O
businesses	O
opening	O
up	O
and	O
even	O
more	O
on	O
the	O
way	O
,	O
”	O
said	O
city	O
of	O
boston	LOC
chief	LOC
of	O
streets	O
chris	O
osgood	O
.	O
“	O
with	O
the	O
go	ORG
boston	ORG
2030	O
vision	O
and	O
action	O
plan	O
,	O
we	O
now	O
have	O
a	O
framework	O
to	O
provide	O
connections	O
between	O
boston	LOC
’	O
s	O
neighborhoods	O
and	O
to	O
new	O
job	O
centers	O
,	O
allowing	O
people	O
to	O
access	O
them	O
using	O
transportation	O
options	O
that	O
are	O
affordable	O
,	O
efficient	O
and	O
enjoyable	O
.	O
”	O
“	O
in	O
2015	O
,	O
mayor	O
walsh	PERS
directed	O
btd	O
to	O
develop	O
a	O
plan	O
to	O
make	O
transportation	O
improvements	O
that	O
would	O
benefit	O
all	O
of	O
boston	LOC
’	O
s	O
diverse	O
communities	O
in	O
all	O
of	O
the	O
city	O
’	O
s	O
neighborhoods	O
,	O
in	O
both	O
the	O
short	O
and	O
the	O
long-term	O
,	O
”	O
said	O
boston	ORG
transportation	ORG
commissioner	O
gina	PERS
n.	PERS
fiandaca	PERS
.	O
“	O
an	O
unprecedented	O
public	O
engagement	O
process	O
was	O
undertaken	O
that	O
led	O
to	O
thousands	O
of	O
ideas	O
and	O
comments	O
being	O
submitted	O
by	O
residents	O
and	O
stakeholders	O
.	O
this	O
plan	O
,	O
and	O
the	O
aspirational	O
goals	O
and	O
targets	O
that	O
are	O
established	O
and	O
prioritized	O
in	O
it	O
,	O
is	O
the	O
direct	O
result	O
of	O
that	O
collaborative	O
process.	O
”	O
five	O
thousand	O
ideas	O
were	O
submitted	O
to	O
the	O
city	O
during	O
the	O
first	O
round	O
of	O
the	O
public	O
engagement	O
process	O
,	O
helping	O
to	O
set	O
the	O
project	O
’	O
s	O
goals	O
and	O
metrics	O
.	O
moving	O
forward	O
from	O
goals	O
to	O
specific	O
projects	O
,	O
the	O
public	O
submitted	O
another	O
3,500	O
policy	O
and	O
project	O
ideas	O
.	O
after	O
analyzing	O
these	O
ideas	O
,	O
nearly	O
4,000	O
boston	LOC
residents	O
and	O
others	O
helped	O
to	O
prioritize	O
them	O
by	O
voting	O
for	O
their	O
top	O
choices	O
of	O
projects	O
.	O
several	O
go	ORG
boston	ORG
2030	O
projects	O
are	O
already	O
underway	O
and	O
are	O
having	O
a	O
positive	O
impact	O
on	O
the	O
city	O
’	O
s	O
streets	O
,	O
including	O
:	O
vision	O
zero	O
neighborhood	O
slow	O
streets	O
parkboston	O
performance	O
pricing	O
parking	O
meter	O
pilot	O
program	O
boston	LOC
’	O
s	O
safest	O
driver	O
contest	O
autonomous	O
vehicle	O
testing	O
driveboston	O
car-share	O
program	O
expansion	O
of	O
hubway	O
bike-share	O
program	O
installation	O
of	O
protected	O
bike	O
lanes	O
.	O
information	O
on	O
all	O
of	O
these	O
programs	O
can	O
be	O
found	O
at	O
www.boston.gov/transportation	O
.	O
“	O
the	O
vision	O
and	O
action	O
plan	O
represents	O
a	O
milestone	O
for	O
every	O
resident	O
in	O
the	O
city	O
because	O
it	O
the	O
first	O
time	O
that	O
a	O
plan	O
made	O
by	O
residents	O
,	O
for	O
residents	O
,	O
will	O
lead	O
to	O
better	O
travel	O
choices	O
for	O
neighborhoods	O
by	O
creating	O
more	O
equitable	O
distribution	O
of	O
investment	O
in	O
transportation	O
infrastructure	O
,	O
”	O
said	O
representative	O
russell	PERS
e.	PERS
holmes	PERS
(	O
d-mattapan	O
)	O
and	O
co-chair	O
of	O
go	ORG
boston	ORG
2030	O
.	O
“	O
it	O
is	O
gratifying	O
that	O
go	ORG
boston	ORG
listened	O
when	O
people	O
stepped	O
forward	O
to	O
say	O
that	O
our	O
transportation	O
must	O
foster	O
opportunity	O
across	O
neighborhoods	O
by	O
connecting	O
the	O
workforce	O
with	O
key	O
job	O
centers	O
.	O
this	O
bold	O
plan	O
will	O
serve	O
as	O
a	O
blueprint	O
for	O
communities	O
moving	O
forward	O
and	O
will	O
keep	O
boston	LOC
a	O
leader	O
among	O
world-class	O
cities.	O
”	O
the	O
go	ORG
boston	ORG
2030	O
vision	O
and	O
action	O
plan	O
provides	O
a	O
blueprint	O
for	O
the	O
city	O
of	O
boston	LOC
to	O
direct	O
its	O
capital	O
plan	O
spending	O
and	O
to	O
work	O
with	O
state	O
transportation	O
agencies	O
to	O
begin	O
implementation	O
.	O
the	O
city	O
is	O
committing	O
to	O
a	O
five	O
year	O
investment	O
plan	O
in	O
order	O
to	O
jump-start	O
implementation	O
of	O
the	O
policies	O
and	O
projects	O
identified	O
in	O
the	O
go	ORG
boston	ORG
2030	O
action	O
plan	O
.	O
the	O
city	O
will	O
leverage	O
city	O
funding	O
to	O
attract	O
state	O
funding	O
through	O
the	O
boston	ORG
region	ORG
metropolitan	ORG
planning	ORG
organization	ORG
(	O
mpo	ORG
.	O
)	O
the	O
city	O
will	O
seek	O
development	O
mitigation	O
to	O
contribute	O
to	O
building	O
streets	O
and	O
sidewalks	O
to	O
enhance	O
public	O
investment	O
.	O
the	O
city	O
will	O
work	O
with	O
surrounding	O
cities	O
and	O
towns	O
to	O
connect	O
transportation	O
networks	O
cost-effectively	O
.	O
the	O
city	O
will	O
establish	O
a	O
go	ORG
boston	ORG
2030	O
mobility	ORG
lab	ORG
in	O
partnership	O
with	O
academia	O
and	O
stakeholders	O
to	O
track	O
progress	O
toward	O
achieving	O
its	O
goals	O
and	O
to	O
experiment	O
with	O
new	O
technology	O
,	O
with	O
an	O
eye	O
toward	O
accountability	O
.	O
“	O
the	O
go	ORG
boston	ORG
2030	O
vision	O
and	O
action	O
plan	O
is	O
a	O
tremendous	O
effort	O
that	O
brings	O
together	O
,	O
for	O
the	O
first	O
time	O
,	O
ideas	O
from	O
residents	O
,	O
stakeholders	O
and	O
the	O
business	O
community	O
,	O
delivering	O
a	O
result	O
that	O
is	O
ambitious	O
,	O
bold	O
and	O
truly	O
exciting	O
,	O
”	O
said	O
richard	PERS
a.	PERS
dimino	PERS
,	O
president	O
&	O
ceo	O
of	O
a	O
better	LOC
city	LOC
and	O
co-chair	O
of	O
go	ORG
boston	ORG
2030	O
.	O
“	O
from	O
the	O
perspective	O
of	O
the	O
business	O
community	O
,	O
the	O
plan	O
will	O
move	O
the	O
city	O
forward	O
because	O
it	O
is	O
squarely	O
focused	O
on	O
improving	O
mobility	O
,	O
including	O
by	O
protecting	O
infrastructure	O
that	O
is	O
vulnerable	O
to	O
sea	O
level	O
rise	O
and	O
extreme	O
weather	O
events	O
.	O
the	O
future	O
success	O
of	O
boston	LOC
depends	O
in	O
large	O
part	O
upon	O
its	O
ability	O
to	O
support	O
employer	O
and	O
worker	O
populations	O
that	O
demand	O
a	O
built	O
environment	O
with	O
a	O
fully	O
connected	O
network	O
of	O
walking	O
,	O
cycling	O
,	O
ride-sharing	O
and	O
transit	O
riding	O
choices.	O
”	O
go	ORG
boston	ORG
2030	O
reflects	O
a	O
partnership	O
between	O
several	O
public	O
agencies	O
and	O
,	O
in	O
particular	O
,	O
complements	O
the	O
imagine	O
boston	LOC
2030	O
and	O
climate	O
ready	O
boston	LOC
initiatives	O
.	O
the	O
go	ORG
boston	ORG
2030	O
public	O
process	O
will	O
continue	O
through	O
the	O
execution	O
of	O
individual	O
projects	O
,	O
with	O
policies	O
and	O
projects	O
receiving	O
a	O
more	O
in-depth	O
planning	O
process	O
at	O
the	O
local	O
level	O
,	O
including	O
through	O
further	O
collaboration	O
with	O
residents	O
and	O
other	O
stakeholders	O
.	O
for	O
more	O
information	O
on	O
go	ORG
boston	ORG
2030	O
,	O
please	O
visit	O
here	O
.	O
please	O
follow	O
and	O
like	O
us	O
:	O
the	O
future	O
of	O
driving	O
is	O
defining	O
the	O
future	O
of	O
transportation	O
when	O
nissan	ORG
's	O
tetsuya	PERS
iijima	PERS
(	O
pronounced	O
ee-ee-jee-mah	O
)	O
envisions	O
the	O
future	O
of	O
driving	O
,	O
he	O
's	O
not	O
only	O
thinking	O
about	O
how	O
autonomous	O
driving	O
will	O
impact	O
the	O
``	O
behind-the-wheel	O
''	O
experience	O
but	O
how	O
to	O
help	O
society	O
prepare	O
for	O
it	O
.	O
a	O
recent	O
report	O
by	O
the	O
boston	ORG
consulting	ORG
group	ORG
found	O
that	O
for	O
those	O
who	O
had	O
concerns	O
about	O
autonomous	O
vehicles	O
are	O
often	O
based	O
on	O
three	O
primary	O
factors	O
:	O
reliability	O
cybersecurity	O
safe	O
interaction	O
to	O
see	O
the	O
autonomous	O
driving	O
fully	O
integrate	O
into	O
daily	O
life	O
,	O
solving	O
the	O
many	O
technological	O
challenges	O
as	O
well	O
as	O
societal	O
acceptance	O
are	O
key	O
.	O
``	O
people	O
need	O
to	O
have	O
a	O
positive	O
mindset	O
to	O
introduce	O
the	O
technology	O
,	O
''	O
said	O
iijima	PERS
,	O
general	O
manager	O
of	O
autonomous	O
drive	O
technology	O
development	O
department	O
at	O
nissan	ORG
motor	O
co.	O
,	O
ltd.	O
for	O
consumers	O
,	O
adoption	O
of	O
new	O
technologies	O
is	O
about	O
trust	O
,	O
and	O
essential	O
to	O
that	O
is	O
understanding	O
.	O
according	O
to	O
iijima	PERS
,	O
``	O
for	O
society	O
to	O
change…	O
people	O
need	O
to	O
understand	O
that	O
this	O
is	O
good	O
for	O
their	O
future	O
.	O
then	O
,	O
customers	O
need	O
to	O
understand	O
what	O
the	O
technology	O
can	O
offer	O
.	O
''	O
this	O
is	O
not	O
a	O
new	O
concept	O
for	O
nissan	ORG
,	O
which	O
has	O
a	O
long	O
history	O
of	O
introducing	O
advanced	O
driver	O
assistance	O
systems	O
—	O
or	O
adas	O
—	O
using	O
a	O
step-by-step	O
approach	O
.	O
iijima	PERS
began	O
at	O
nissan	ORG
working	O
on	O
electric-controlled	O
suspension	O
,	O
in	O
which	O
cars	O
react	O
faster	O
and	O
absorb	O
more	O
bumps	O
on	O
the	O
road	O
.	O
iijima	PERS
also	O
helped	O
to	O
pioneer	O
nissan	ORG
's	O
adaptive	O
cruise	O
control	O
,	O
lane	O
departure	O
prevention	O
systems	O
and	O
emergency	O
braking	O
.	O
all	O
were	O
at	O
once	O
unknown	O
technologies	O
,	O
but	O
are	O
now	O
widely	O
adopted	O
and	O
have	O
helped	O
change	O
transportation	O
.	O
thanks	O
to	O
a	O
history	O
of	O
innovation	O
,	O
nissan	ORG
is	O
taking	O
a	O
step-by-step	O
approach	O
in	O
introducing	O
autonomous	O
driving	O
technologies	O
to	O
market	O
.	O
and	O
that	O
's	O
exactly	O
what	O
iijima	PERS
sees	O
as	O
the	O
focus	O
.	O
``	O
it	O
's	O
a	O
step-by-step	O
educational	O
approach	O
that	O
allows	O
drivers	O
to	O
experience	O
the	O
technology	O
one	O
feature	O
at	O
a	O
time	O
and	O
directly	O
see	O
the	O
value	O
it	O
offers	O
''	O
education	O
is	O
critical	O
,	O
but	O
it	O
's	O
not	O
the	O
only	O
focus	O
for	O
nissan	ORG
.	O
according	O
to	O
iijima	PERS
,	O
the	O
future	O
nissan	ORG
hopes	O
to	O
engineer	O
is	O
one	O
in	O
which	O
affordable	O
and	O
widely-deployed	O
autonomous	O
driving	O
technologies	O
enable	O
safe	O
and	O
efficient	O
transportation	O
for	O
many	O
.	O
this	O
can	O
be	O
seen	O
with	O
the	O
introduction	O
and	O
popularity	O
of	O
the	O
nissan	ORG
serena	O
in	O
japan	LOC
earlier	O
this	O
year	O
.	O
the	O
serena	O
is	O
now	O
a	O
top-selling	O
model	O
in	O
that	O
market	O
and	O
features	O
new	O
technologies	O
that	O
can	O
be	O
used	O
and	O
experienced	O
by	O
many	O
—	O
not	O
only	O
in	O
concept	O
cars	O
.	O
iijima	PERS
's	O
focus	O
now	O
?	O
nissan	ORG
's	O
autonomous	O
drive	O
technology	O
known	O
as	O
``	O
propilot	O
''	O
,	O
which	O
gives	O
drivers	O
the	O
choice	O
of	O
manually	O
operating	O
the	O
vehicle	O
or	O
handing	O
control	O
over	O
to	O
onboard	O
systems	O
in	O
certain	O
situations	O
.	O
the	O
first	O
of	O
these	O
technologies	O
,	O
introduced	O
in	O
august	O
,	O
allows	O
cars	O
to	O
assist	O
drivers	O
by	O
steering	O
,	O
braking	O
,	O
and	O
accelerating	O
automatically	O
and	O
safely	O
in	O
a	O
single	O
lane	O
on	O
highways	O
.	O
in	O
2018	O
,	O
nissan	ORG
expects	O
to	O
unveil	O
a	O
``	O
multiple-lane	O
control	O
''	O
application	O
that	O
can	O
autonomously	O
negotiate	O
hazards	O
and	O
change	O
lanes	O
during	O
highway	O
driving	O
.	O
two	O
years	O
later	O
,	O
it	O
plans	O
to	O
add	O
the	O
capability	O
for	O
the	O
vehicle	O
to	O
navigate	O
city	O
driving	O
and	O
intersections	O
without	O
driver	O
intervention	O
.	O
by	O
that	O
time	O
,	O
the	O
renault-nissan	ORG
alliance	ORG
plans	O
to	O
launch	O
more	O
than	O
10	O
models	O
with	O
significant	O
autonomous	O
driving	O
functionalities	O
in	O
the	O
u.s.	LOC
,	O
japan	LOC
,	O
europe	LOC
and	O
china	LOC
.	O
focusing	O
on	O
social	O
acceptance	O
will	O
also	O
allow	O
consumers	O
as	O
well	O
as	O
involved	O
governments	O
,	O
groups	O
and	O
other	O
agencies	O
,	O
the	O
time	O
to	O
consider	O
the	O
benefits	O
of	O
the	O
new	O
technologies	O
.	O
``	O
there	O
must	O
be	O
a	O
huge	O
change	O
in	O
government	O
and	O
society	O
''	O
once	O
autonomous	O
drive	O
technology	O
reaches	O
a	O
certain	O
level	O
of	O
technological	O
advance	O
,	O
decisions	O
must	O
be	O
made	O
on	O
driving	O
infrastructure	O
and	O
laws	O
to	O
ultimately	O
change	O
society	O
's	O
mindset	O
.	O
education	O
and	O
acceptance	O
will	O
be	O
important	O
as	O
the	O
technologies	O
further	O
evolve	O
.	O
as	O
iijima	PERS
notes	O
,	O
``	O
my	O
team	O
will	O
continue	O
to	O
work	O
on	O
advancing	O
what	O
's	O
possible	O
to	O
help	O
create	O
an	O
autonomous	O
driving	O
future	O
for	O
all	O
.	O
we	O
will	O
share	O
our	O
vision	O
so	O
that	O
one	O
day	O
everyone	O
can	O
picture	O
themselves	O
behind	O
the	O
steering	O
wheel	O
of	O
an	O
autonomous	O
vehicle	O
.	O
''	O
the	O
future	O
of	O
driving	O
is	O
defining	O
the	O
future	O
of	O
transportation	O
19	O
oct	O
2016	O
renault-nissan	ORG
alliance	ORG
team	O
the	O
future	O
of	O
driving	O
is	O
defining	O
the	O
future	O
of	O
transportation	O
when	O
nissan	ORG
’	O
s	O
tetsuya	PERS
iijima	PERS
envisions	O
the	O
future	O
of	O
driving	O
,	O
he	O
’	O
s	O
not	O
only	O
thinking	O
about	O
how	O
autonomous	O
driving	O
will	O
impact	O
the	O
“	O
behind-the-wheel	O
”	O
experience	O
but	O
how	O
to	O
help	O
society	O
prepare	O
for	O
it	O
.	O
a	O
recent	O
report	O
by	O
the	O
boston	ORG
consulting	ORG
group	ORG
found	O
that	O
for	O
those	O
who	O
had	O
concerns	O
about	O
autonomous	O
vehicles	O
are	O
often	O
based	O
on	O
three	O
primary	O
factors	O
:	O
reliability	O
cybersecurity	O
safe	O
interaction	O
to	O
see	O
the	O
autonomous	O
driving	O
fully	O
integrate	O
into	O
daily	O
life	O
,	O
solving	O
the	O
many	O
technological	O
challenges	O
as	O
well	O
as	O
societal	O
acceptance	O
are	O
key	O
.	O
“	O
people	O
need	O
to	O
have	O
a	O
positive	O
mindset	O
to	O
introduce	O
the	O
technology	O
,	O
”	O
said	O
iijima	PERS
,	O
general	O
manager	O
of	O
autonomous	ORG
drive	ORG
technology	ORG
development	ORG
department	ORG
at	O
nissan	ORG
motor	O
co.	O
,	O
ltd.	O
for	O
consumers	O
,	O
adoption	O
of	O
new	O
technologies	O
is	O
about	O
trust	O
,	O
and	O
essential	O
to	O
that	O
is	O
understanding	O
.	O
according	O
to	O
iijima	PERS
,	O
“	O
for	O
society	O
to	O
change…	O
people	O
need	O
to	O
understand	O
that	O
this	O
is	O
good	O
for	O
their	O
future	O
.	O
then	O
,	O
customers	O
need	O
to	O
understand	O
what	O
the	O
technology	O
can	O
offer.	O
”	O
thanks	O
to	O
a	O
history	O
of	O
innovation	O
,	O
nissan	ORG
is	O
taking	O
a	O
step-by-step	O
approach	O
in	O
introducing	O
autonomous	O
driving	O
technologies	O
to	O
market	O
.	O
and	O
that	O
’	O
s	O
exactly	O
what	O
iijima	PERS
sees	O
as	O
the	O
focus	O
.	O
“	O
it	O
’	O
s	O
a	O
step-by-step	O
educational	O
approach	O
that	O
allows	O
drivers	O
to	O
experience	O
the	O
technology	O
one	O
feature	O
at	O
a	O
time	O
and	O
directly	O
see	O
the	O
value	O
it	O
offers.	O
”	O
education	O
is	O
critical	O
,	O
but	O
it	O
’	O
s	O
not	O
the	O
only	O
focus	O
for	O
nissan	ORG
.	O
according	O
to	O
iijima	PERS
,	O
the	O
future	O
nissan	ORG
hopes	O
to	O
engineer	O
is	O
one	O
in	O
which	O
affordable	O
and	O
widely-deployed	O
autonomous	O
driving	O
technologies	O
enable	O
safe	O
and	O
efficient	O
transportation	O
for	O
many	O
.	O
iijima	PERS
’	O
s	O
focus	O
now	O
?	O
nissan	ORG
’	O
s	O
autonomous	O
drive	O
technology	O
known	O
as	O
“	O
propilot	O
”	O
,	O
which	O
gives	O
drivers	O
the	O
choice	O
of	O
manually	O
operating	O
the	O
vehicle	O
or	O
handing	O
control	O
over	O
to	O
onboard	O
systems	O
in	O
certain	O
situations	O
.	O
the	O
first	O
of	O
these	O
technologies	O
,	O
introduced	O
in	O
august	O
,	O
allows	O
cars	O
to	O
assist	O
drivers	O
by	O
steering	O
,	O
braking	O
,	O
and	O
accelerating	O
automatically	O
and	O
safely	O
in	O
a	O
single	O
lane	O
on	O
highways	O
.	O
in	O
2018	O
,	O
nissan	ORG
expects	O
to	O
unveil	O
a	O
“	O
multiple-lane	O
control	O
”	O
application	O
that	O
can	O
autonomously	O
negotiate	O
hazards	O
and	O
change	O
lanes	O
during	O
highway	O
driving	O
.	O
two	O
years	O
later	O
,	O
it	O
plans	O
to	O
add	O
the	O
capability	O
for	O
the	O
vehicle	O
to	O
navigate	O
city	O
driving	O
and	O
intersections	O
without	O
driver	O
intervention	O
.	O
by	O
that	O
time	O
,	O
the	O
renault-nissan	ORG
alliance	ORG
plans	O
to	O
launch	O
more	O
than	O
10	O
models	O
with	O
significant	O
autonomous	O
driving	O
functionalities	O
in	O
the	O
u.s.	LOC
,	O
japan	LOC
,	O
europe	LOC
and	O
china	LOC
.	O
focusing	O
on	O
social	O
acceptance	O
will	O
also	O
allow	O
consumers	O
as	O
well	O
as	O
involved	O
governments	O
,	O
groups	O
and	O
other	O
agencies	O
,	O
the	O
time	O
to	O
consider	O
the	O
benefits	O
of	O
the	O
new	O
technologies	O
.	O
“	O
there	O
must	O
be	O
a	O
huge	O
change	O
in	O
government	O
and	O
society.	O
”	O
once	O
autonomous	O
drive	O
technology	O
reaches	O
a	O
certain	O
level	O
of	O
technological	O
advance	O
,	O
decisions	O
must	O
be	O
made	O
on	O
driving	O
infrastructure	O
and	O
laws	O
to	O
ultimately	O
change	O
society	O
’	O
s	O
mindset	O
.	O
education	O
and	O
acceptance	O
will	O
be	O
important	O
as	O
the	O
technologies	O
further	O
evolve	O
.	O
as	O
iijima	PERS
notes	O
,	O
“	O
my	O
team	O
will	O
continue	O
to	O
work	O
on	O
advancing	O
what	O
’	O
s	O
possible	O
to	O
help	O
create	O
an	O
autonomous	O
driving	O
future	O
for	O
all	O
.	O
we	O
will	O
share	O
our	O
vision	O
so	O
that	O
one	O
day	O
everyone	O
can	O
picture	O
themselves	O
behind	O
the	O
steering	O
wheel	O
of	O
an	O
autonomous	O
vehicle.	O
”	O
read	O
the	O
full	O
article	O
here	O
.	O
print	O
tweet	O
west	O
of	O
england	LOC
joint	O
transport	O
study	O
:	O
transport	O
vision	O
response	O
i	O
've	O
been	O
trying	O
to	O
write	O
a	O
response	O
to	O
this	O
vision	O
and	O
i	O
see	O
it	O
as	O
a	O
disappointing	O
continuation	O
of	O
civil	O
servants	O
unwilling	O
to	O
take	O
the	O
necessary	O
politically	O
hard	O
steps	O
to	O
deliver	O
a	O
real	O
change	O
.	O
the	O
allocated	O
£7.5	O
billion	O
budget	O
in	O
the	O
vision	O
is	O
stunningly	O
naive	O
.	O
£0.4	O
billion	O
for	O
walking	O
and	O
cycling	O
£1	O
billion	O
for	O
metrobus	O
£2.5	O
billion	O
for	O
light	O
rapid	O
transit	O
(	O
trams	O
)	O
£1	O
billion	O
for	O
rail	O
£2.6	O
billion	O
for	O
highways	O
this	O
sounds	O
all	O
very	O
interesting	O
,	O
until	O
you	O
realise	O
there	O
are	O
no	O
target	O
modal-split	O
values	O
in	O
the	O
vision	O
.	O
the	O
poster	O
child	O
for	O
sustainable	O
cities	O
is	O
freiburg	LOC
in	O
germany	LOC
.	O
a	O
city	O
of	O
around	O
150km2	O
vs	O
bristol	LOC
's	O
110km2	O
.	O
looking	O
at	O
the	O
modal-split	O
in	O
freiburg	LOC
.	O
in	O
1982	O
35	O
%	O
of	O
people	O
walked	O
,	O
15	O
%	O
cycled	O
,	O
11	O
%	O
used	O
public	O
transport	O
(	O
trains	O
,	O
buses	O
,	O
trams	O
)	O
and	O
9	O
%	O
were	O
car	O
sharing	O
and	O
29	O
%	O
in	O
single	O
occupancy	O
vehicles	O
.	O
by	O
1999	O
,	O
17	O
years	O
later	O
23	O
%	O
walked	O
,	O
27	O
%	O
cycled	O
,	O
18	O
%	O
were	O
using	O
public	O
transport	O
,	O
6	O
%	O
car	O
shared	O
,	O
and	O
26	O
%	O
single	O
occupancy	O
vehicles	O
.	O
the	O
ambition	O
by	O
2020	O
is	O
to	O
have	O
24	O
%	O
walking	O
,	O
27	O
%	O
cycling	O
,	O
20	O
%	O
public	O
transport	O
,	O
5	O
%	O
car	O
sharing	O
and	O
24	O
%	O
single	O
occupancy	O
vehicles	O
.	O
this	O
is	O
a	O
big	O
city	O
.	O
freiburg	LOC
has	O
had	O
phenomenal	O
success	O
and	O
has	O
achieved	O
this	O
through	O
the	O
building	O
of	O
400km	O
of	O
segregated	O
cycle	O
tracks	O
.	O
so	O
when	O
you	O
look	O
at	O
the	O
west	O
of	O
england	LOC
transport	O
vision	O
it	O
utterly	O
and	O
absolutely	O
fails	O
to	O
answer	O
two	O
simple	O
questions	O
.	O
what	O
is	O
the	O
current	O
modal-split	O
by	O
city/region	O
?	O
what	O
is	O
the	O
target	O
modal-split	O
by	O
city/region	O
?	O
once	O
you	O
have	O
the	O
answer	O
to	O
these	O
two	O
questions	O
,	O
you	O
can	O
actually	O
begin	O
to	O
have	O
a	O
vision	O
.	O
at	O
the	O
moment	O
the	O
vision	O
just	O
feels	O
like	O
civil	O
servants	O
and	O
politicians	O
wanting	O
to	O
play	O
with	O
very	O
big	O
and	O
expensive	O
train	O
sets	O
.	O
it	O
's	O
embarrassingly	O
vague	O
and	O
i	O
feel	O
has	O
been	O
done	O
so	O
on	O
purpose	O
to	O
allow	O
a	O
lot	O
of	O
back	O
tracking	O
.	O
i	O
'm	O
extremely	O
concerned	O
that	O
walking	O
and	O
cycling	O
has	O
been	O
lumped	O
into	O
one	O
budget	O
.	O
this	O
type	O
of	O
lumping	O
in	O
creates	O
situations	O
where	O
council	O
misuse	O
money	O
intended	O
to	O
develop	O
good	O
