saudi	LOC
arabia	LOC
's	O
mohammed	PERS
bin	PERS
salman	PERS
promoted	O
to	O
crown	O
prince	PERS
by	O
stephen	PERS
kalin	PERS
and	O
william	PERS
maclean	PERS
dubai	PERS
(	O
reuters	ORG
)	O
-	O
saudi	LOC
arabia	LOC
's	O
king	O
salman	PERS
made	O
his	O
son	O
next	O
in	O
line	O
to	O
the	O
throne	O
on	O
wednesday	O
,	O
handing	O
the	O
31-year-old	O
sweeping	O
powers	O
as	O
the	O
kingdom	O
seeks	O
radical	O
overhaul	O
of	O
its	O
oil-dependent	O
economy	O
and	O
faces	O
mounting	O
tensions	O
with	O
regional	O
rival	O
iran	LOC
.	O
a	O
royal	O
decree	O
appointed	O
mohammed	PERS
bin	PERS
salman	PERS
crown	O
prince	PERS
and	O
deputy	O
prime	O
minister	O
.	O
he	O
retains	O
the	O
defence	ORG
,	O
oil	O
and	O
other	O
portfolios	O
.	O
the	O
previous	O
crown	O
prince	PERS
,	O
mohammed	PERS
bin	PERS
nayef	PERS
,	O
the	O
king	O
's	O
nephew	O
and	O
a	O
counter-terrorism	O
chief	O
admired	O
in	O
washington	LOC
for	O
putting	O
down	O
an	O
al	PERS
qaeda	PERS
campaign	O
of	O
bombings	O
in	O
2003-06	O
,	O
was	O
relieved	O
of	O
all	O
his	O
posts	O
,	O
according	O
to	O
the	O
decree	O
.	O
although	O
mohammed	PERS
bin	PERS
salman	PERS
's	O
promotion	O
was	O
expected	O
among	O
close	O
circles	O
,	O
the	O
timing	O
was	O
a	O
surprise	O
,	O
with	O
the	O
kingdom	O
facing	O
heightened	O
tensions	O
with	O
qatar	LOC
and	O
iran	LOC
and	O
locked	O
in	O
a	O
war	O
in	O
yemen	LOC
.	O
the	O
royal	O
decree	O
said	O
the	O
decision	O
by	O
king	O
salman	PERS
to	O
promote	O
his	O
son	O
and	O
consolidate	O
his	O
power	O
was	O
endorsed	O
by	O
31	O
out	O
of	O
34	O
members	O
of	O
the	O
allegiance	ORG
council	ORG
,	O
made	O
up	O
of	O
senior	O
members	O
of	O
the	O
ruling	O
al	PERS
saud	PERS
family	O
.	O
intent	O
on	O
dispelling	O
speculation	O
of	O
internal	O
divisions	O
in	O
the	O
ruling	O
dynasty	O
,	O
saudi	O
television	O
was	O
quick	O
to	O
show	O
that	O
the	O
change	O
in	O
succession	O
was	O
amicable	O
and	O
supported	O
by	O
the	O
family	O
.	O
throughout	O
the	O
early	O
morning	O
it	O
aired	O
footage	O
of	O
mohammed	PERS
bin	PERS
nayef	PERS
pledging	O
allegiance	O
to	O
the	O
younger	O
mohammed	PERS
bin	PERS
salman	PERS
,	O
who	O
knelt	O
and	O
kissed	O
his	O
cousin	O
's	O
hand	O
.	O
``	O
i	O
am	O
content	O
,	O
''	O
prince	PERS
mohammed	PERS
bin	PERS
nayef	PERS
said	O
.	O
prince	PERS
mohammed	PERS
bin	PERS
salman	PERS
replied	O
:	O
``	O
we	O
will	O
not	O
give	O
up	O
taking	O
your	O
guidance	O
and	O
advice	O
.	O
''	O
analysts	O
said	O
the	O
change	O
ends	O
uncertainty	O
over	O
succession	O
and	O
empowers	O
prince	PERS
mohammed	PERS
bin	PERS
salman	PERS
to	O
move	O
faster	O
with	O
his	O
plan	O
to	O
reduce	O
the	O
kingdom	O
's	O
dependence	O
on	O
oil	O
,	O
which	O
includes	O
the	O
partial	O
privatisation	O
of	O
state	O
oil	O
company	O
aramco	ORG
.	O
``	O
the	O
change	O
is	O
a	O
huge	O
boost	O
to	O
the	O
economic	O
reform	O
programme	O
...	O
prince	PERS
mohammed	PERS
bin	PERS
salman	PERS
(	O
mbs	O
)	O
is	O
its	O
architect	O
,	O
''	O
said	O
john	PERS
sfakianakis	PERS
,	O
director	O
of	O
the	O
gulf	ORG
research	ORG
centre	ORG
.	O
bernard	PERS
haykel	PERS
,	O
professor	O
of	O
near	O
eastern	O
studies	O
at	O
princeton	ORG
,	O
said	O
the	O
king	O
's	O
decision	O
was	O
aimed	O
at	O
avoiding	O
a	O
power	O
struggle	O
between	O
his	O
son	O
and	O
mohammed	PERS
bin	PERS
nayef	PERS
by	O
setting	O
the	O
line	O
of	O
succession	O
out	O
clearly	O
.	O
``	O
it	O
's	O
clearly	O
a	O
transition	O
that	O
has	O
happened	O
smoothly	O
and	O
bloodlessly	O
.	O
now	O
it	O
's	O
clear	O
,	O
it	O
's	O
straightforward	O
.	O
that	O
kind	O
of	O
clarity	O
lowers	O
the	O
risk	O
.	O
there	O
's	O
no	O
question	O
as	O
to	O
who	O
's	O
going	O
to	O
be	O
in	O
charge	O
.	O
''	O
after	O
prince	PERS
mohammed	PERS
's	O
promotion	O
was	O
announced	O
,	O
saudi	LOC
arabia	LOC
's	O
stock	O
market	O
surged	O
more	O
than	O
3	O
percent	O
in	O
early	O
trade	O
.	O
escalating	O
regional	O
tensions	O
''	O
some	O
people	O
were	O
predicting	O
that	O
this	O
would	O
lead	O
to	O
a	O
division	O
in	O
the	O
family	O
and	O
strife	O
and	O
some	O
kind	O
of	O
revolt	O
.	O
i	O
do	O
n't	O
see	O
that	O
happening	O
,	O
''	O
haykel	PERS
said	O
.	O
iran	LOC
,	O
saudi	LOC
arabia	LOC
's	O
main	O
rival	O
for	O
regional	O
influence	O
,	O
called	O
prince	PERS
mohammed	PERS
's	O
appointment	O
a	O
``	O
soft	O
coup	O
''	O
.	O
iran	LOC
's	O
leadership	O
was	O
critical	O
of	O
comments	O
by	O
prince	PERS
mohammed	PERS
last	O
month	O
that	O
the	O
``	O
battle	O
''	O
should	O
be	O
taken	O
into	O
iran	LOC
,	O
with	O
supreme	O
leader	O
ayatollah	PERS
ali	PERS
khamenei	PERS
labelling	O
the	O
saudi	O
leadership	O
then	O
as	O
``	O
idiots	O
''	O
.	O
arab	O
leaders	O
,	O
including	O
oman	LOC
’	O
s	O
sultan	PERS
qaboos	PERS
,	O
jordan	O
’	O
s	O
king	O
abdullah	PERS
,	O
egypt	LOC
's	O
abdel	PERS
fattah	PERS
al-sisi	PERS
and	O
yemeni	O
president	O
abd-rabbu	PERS
mansour	PERS
hadi	PERS
congratulated	O
prince	PERS
mohammed	PERS
bin	PERS
salman	PERS
on	O
his	O
appointment	O
,	O
according	O
to	O
state	O
media	O
.	O
the	O
royal	O
decree	O
did	O
not	O
nominate	O
a	O
new	O
deputy	O
crown	O
prince	PERS
.	O
the	O
position	O
is	O
relatively	O
new	O
in	O
saudi	LOC
arabia	LOC
,	O
where	O
kings	O
have	O
traditionally	O
chosen	O
their	O
own	O
successors	O
.	O
in	O
an	O
apparent	O
attempt	O
to	O
appease	O
the	O
family	O
,	O
the	O
decree	O
had	O
a	O
clause	O
that	O
made	O
clear	O
that	O
mohammed	PERS
bin	PERS
salman	PERS
won	O
’	O
t	O
be	O
allowed	O
to	O
appoint	O
one	O
of	O
his	O
own	O
sons	O
as	O
his	O
successor	O
.	O
as	O
deputy	O
crown	O
prince	PERS
,	O
mohammed	PERS
bin	PERS
salman	PERS
has	O
been	O
responsible	O
for	O
running	O
saudi	LOC
arabia	LOC
's	O
war	O
in	O
yemen	LOC
,	O
dictating	O
an	O
energy	O
policy	O
with	O
global	O
implications	O
and	O
spearheading	O
plans	O
for	O
the	O
kingdom	O
to	O
build	O
an	O
economic	O
future	O
after	O
oil	O
.	O
that	O
the	O
royal	O
succession	O
in	O
the	O
world	O
's	O
top	O
oil	O
exporter	O
is	O
closely	O
scrutinised	O
only	O
makes	O
the	O
speed	O
of	O
mohammed	PERS
bin	PERS
salman	PERS
's	O
rise	O
to	O
power	O
-	O
and	O
the	O
speed	O
with	O
which	O
his	O
better-known	O
cousins	O
were	O
brushed	O
aside	O
-	O
more	O
astonishing	O
.	O
the	O
announcement	O
follows	O
2-1/2	O
years	O
of	O
already	O
major	O
changes	O
in	O
saudi	LOC
arabia	LOC
,	O
which	O
stunned	O
allies	O
in	O
2015	O
by	O
launching	O
an	O
air	O
war	O
in	O
yemen	LOC
,	O
cutting	O
back	O
on	O
lavish	O
subsidies	O
and	O
proposing	O
in	O
2016	O
the	O
partial	O
privatisation	O
of	O
state	O
oil	O
company	O
aramco	ORG
.	O
read	O
more	O
financial	O
analysts	O
said	O
prince	PERS
mohammed	PERS
's	O
promotion	O
gave	O
further	O
assurance	O
that	O
key	O
parts	O
of	O
radical	O
reforms	O
to	O
diversify	O
the	O
saudi	O
economy	O
beyond	O
oil	O
would	O
continue	O
.	O
``	O
we	O
do	O
not	O
expect	O
to	O
see	O
any	O
major	O
changes	O
to	O
key	O
areas	O
of	O
policy	O
,	O
including	O
economic	O
,	O
''	O
said	O
monica	PERS
malik	PERS
,	O
chief	O
economist	O
at	O
abu	ORG
dhabi	ORG
commercial	ORG
bank	ORG
.	O
last	O
year	O
mohammed	PERS
bin	PERS
salman	PERS
,	O
or	O
``	O
mbs	O
''	O
as	O
he	O
is	O
widely	O
known	O
,	O
announced	O
sweeping	O
changes	O
aimed	O
at	O
ending	O
the	O
kingdom	O
's	O
reliance	O
on	O
oil	O
,	O
part	O
of	O
his	O
campaign	O
to	O
tackle	O
systemic	O
challenges	O
that	O
the	O
kingdom	O
has	O
previously	O
failed	O
to	O
address	O
.	O
power	O
behind	O
the	O
throne	O
until	O
his	O
father	O
salman	PERS
bin	PERS
abdulaziz	PERS
al	PERS
saud	PERS
became	O
saudi	LOC
arabia	LOC
's	O
seventh	O
king	O
in	O
january	O
2015	O
,	O
few	O
people	O
outside	O
the	O
kingdom	O
had	O
ever	O
heard	O
of	O
prince	PERS
mohammed	PERS
.	O
he	O
is	O
currently	O
defence	ORG
minister	O
,	O
giving	O
him	O
command	O
of	O
one	O
of	O
the	O
world	O
's	O
biggest	O
arms	O
budgets	O
and	O
making	O
him	O
ultimately	O
responsible	O
for	O
saudi	LOC
arabia	LOC
's	O
military	O
adventure	O
in	O
yemen	LOC
.	O
he	O
also	O
heads	O
the	O
council	ORG
for	ORG
economic	ORG
and	ORG
development	ORG
affairs	ORG
(	O
ceda	ORG
)	O
,	O
a	O
group	O
of	O
cabinet	O
ministers	O
who	O
meet	O
weekly	O
and	O
which	O
oversees	O
all	O
elements	O
of	O
policy	O
touching	O
on	O
the	O
economy	O
or	O
social	O
issues	O
like	O
education	O
,	O
health	O
and	O
housing	O
.	O
prince	PERS
mohammed	PERS
chairs	O
the	O
supreme	O
board	O
of	O
aramco	ORG
,	O
making	O
him	O
the	O
first	O
member	O
of	O
the	O
ruling	O
family	O
to	O
directly	O
oversee	O
the	O
state	O
oil	O
company	O
,	O
long	O
regarded	O
as	O
the	O
preserve	O
of	O
commoner	O
technocrats	O
.	O
but	O
perhaps	O
most	O
importantly	O
,	O
he	O
is	O
the	O
gatekeeper	O
to	O
his	O
father	O
,	O
king	O
salman	PERS
,	O
who	O
in	O
saudi	LOC
arabia	LOC
's	O
absolute	O
monarchy	O
retains	O
the	O
final	O
say	O
in	O
any	O
major	O
decision	O
of	O
state	O
.	O
outside	O
saudi	LOC
arabia	LOC
,	O
that	O
rapid	O
advance	O
and	O
the	O
sudden	O
changes	O
to	O
longstanding	O
policies	O
on	O
regional	O
affairs	O
,	O
energy	O
and	O
its	O
economy	O
have	O
prompted	O
unease	O
,	O
adding	O
an	O
unpredictable	O
edge	O
to	O
a	O
kingdom	O
that	O
allies	O
long	O
regarded	O
as	O
a	O
known	O
quantity	O
.	O
inside	O
,	O
they	O
have	O
prompted	O
admiration	O
among	O
many	O
younger	O
saudis	O
who	O
regard	O
his	O
ascent	O
as	O
evidence	O
that	O
their	O
generation	O
is	O
taking	O
a	O
central	O
place	O
in	O
running	O
a	O
country	O
whose	O
patriarchal	O
traditions	O
have	O
for	O
decades	O
made	O
power	O
the	O
province	O
of	O
the	O
old	O
.	O
saudi	LOC
arabia	LOC
's	O
main	O
stock	O
index	O
was	O
3.4	O
percent	O
higher	O
.	O
national	ORG
commercial	ORG
bank	ORG
,	O
the	O
biggest	O
listed	O
lender	O
,	O
which	O
is	O
expected	O
to	O
play	O
a	O
major	O
role	O
in	O
funding	O
some	O
of	O
the	O
non-oil	O
industries	O
prince	PERS
mohammed	PERS
bin	PERS
salman	PERS
aims	O
to	O
develop	O
,	O
jumped	O
10	O
percent	O
.	O
(	O
reporting	O
by	O
stephen	PERS
kalin	PERS
,	O
william	PERS
maclean	PERS
,	O
rania	PERS
el	PERS
gamal	PERS
,	O
sylvia	PERS
westall	PERS
,	O
sami	PERS
aboudi	PERS
,	O
andrew	PERS
torchia	PERS
,	O
reem	PERS
shamseddine	PERS
,	O
angus	PERS
mcdowall	PERS
;	O
editing	O
by	O
samia	PERS
nakhoul	PERS
and	O
hugh	PERS
lawson	PERS
)	O
saudi	LOC
arabia	LOC
's	O
mohammed	PERS
bin	PERS
salman	PERS
promoted	O
to	O
crown	O
prince	PERS
|	O
saudi	LOC
arabia	LOC
's	O
king	O
salman	PERS
made	O
his	O
son	O
next	O
in	O
line	O
to	O
the	O
throne	O
on	O
wednesday	O
,	O
handing	O
the	O
31-year-old	O
sweeping	O
powers	O
as	O
the	O
kingdom	O
seeks	O
radical	O
overhaul	O
of	O
its	O
oil-dependent	O
economy	O
and	O
faces	O
mounting	O
tensions	O
with	O
regional	O
rival	O
iran	LOC
.	O
a	O
royal	O
decree	O
appointed	O
mohammed	PERS
bin	PERS
salman	PERS
crown	O
prince	PERS
and	O
deputy	O
prime	O
minister	O
.	O
he	O
retains	O
the	O
defence	ORG
,	O
oil	O
and	O
other	O
portfolios	O
.	O
the	O
previous	O
crown	O
prince	PERS
,	O
mohammed	PERS
bin	PERS
nayef	PERS
,	O
the	O
king	O
's	O
nephew	O
and	O
a	O
counter-terrorism	O
chief	O
admired	O
in	O
washington	LOC
for	O
putting	O
down	O
an	O
al	PERS
qaeda	PERS
campaign	O
of	O
bombings	O
in	O
2003-06	O
,	O
was	O
relieved	O
of	O
all	O
his	O
posts	O
,	O
according	O
to	O
the	O
decree	O
.	O
although	O
mohammed	PERS
bin	PERS
salman	PERS
's	O
promotion	O
was	O
expected	O
among	O
close	O
circles	O
,	O
the	O
timing	O
was	O
a	O
surprise	O
,	O
with	O
the	O
kingdom	O
facing	O
heightened	O
tensions	O
with	O
qatar	LOC
and	O
iran	LOC
and	O
locked	O
in	O
a	O
war	O
in	O
yemen	LOC
.	O
the	O
royal	O
decree	O
said	O
the	O
decision	O
by	O
king	O
salman	PERS
to	O
promote	O
his	O
son	O
and	O
consolidate	O
his	O
power	O
was	O
endorsed	O
by	O
31	O
out	O
of	O
34	O
members	O
of	O
the	O
allegiance	ORG
council	ORG
,	O
made	O
up	O
of	O
senior	O
members	O
of	O
the	O
ruling	O
al	PERS
saud	PERS
family	O
.	O
intent	O
on	O
dispelling	O
speculation	O
of	O
internal	O
divisions	O
in	O
the	O
ruling	O
dynasty	O
,	O
saudi	O
television	O
was	O
quick	O
to	O
show	O
that	O
the	O
change	O
in	O
succession	O
was	O
amicable	O
and	O
supported	O
by	O
the	O
family	O
.	O
throughout	O
the	O
early	O
morning	O
it	O
aired	O
footage	O
of	O
mohammed	PERS
bin	PERS
nayef	PERS
pledging	O
allegiance	O
to	O
the	O
younger	O
mohammed	PERS
bin	PERS
salman	PERS
,	O
who	O
knelt	O
and	O
kissed	O
his	O
cousin	O
's	O
hand	O
.	O
``	O
i	O
am	O
content	O
,	O
''	O
prince	PERS
mohammed	PERS
bin	PERS
nayef	PERS
said	O
.	O
prince	PERS
mohammed	PERS
bin	PERS
salman	PERS
replied	O
:	O
``	O
we	O
will	O
not	O
give	O
up	O
taking	O
your	O
guidance	O
and	O
advice	O
.	O
''	O
analysts	O
said	O
the	O
change	O
ends	O
uncertainty	O
over	O
succession	O
and	O
empowers	O
prince	PERS
mohammed	PERS
bin	PERS
salman	PERS
to	O
move	O
faster	O
with	O
his	O
plan	O
to	O
reduce	O
the	O
kingdom	O
's	O
dependence	O
on	O
oil	O
,	O
which	O
includes	O
the	O
partial	O
privatisation	O
of	O
state	O
oil	O
company	O
aramco	ORG
.	O
``	O
the	O
change	O
is	O
a	O
huge	O
boost	O
to	O
the	O
economic	O
reform	O
programme	O
...	O
prince	PERS
mohammed	PERS
bin	PERS
salman	PERS
(	O
mbs	O
)	O
is	O
its	O
architect	O
,	O
''	O
said	O
john	PERS
sfakianakis	PERS
,	O
director	O
of	O
the	O
gulf	ORG
research	ORG
centre	ORG
.	O
bernard	PERS
haykel	PERS
,	O
professor	O
of	O
near	O
eastern	O
studies	O
at	O
princeton	ORG
,	O
said	O
the	O
king	O
's	O
decision	O
was	O
aimed	O
at	O
avoiding	O
a	O
power	O
struggle	O
between	O
his	O
son	O
and	O
mohammed	PERS
bin	PERS
nayef	PERS
by	O
setting	O
the	O
line	O
of	O
succession	O
out	O
clearly	O
.	O
``	O
it	O
's	O
clearly	O
a	O
transition	O
that	O
has	O
happened	O
smoothly	O
and	O
bloodlessly	O
.	O
now	O
it	O
's	O
clear	O
,	O
it	O
's	O
straightforward	O
.	O
that	O
kind	O
of	O
clarity	O
lowers	O
the	O
risk	O
.	O
there	O
's	O
no	O
question	O
as	O
to	O
who	O
's	O
going	O
to	O
be	O
in	O
charge	O
.	O
''	O
after	O
prince	PERS
mohammed	PERS
's	O
promotion	O
was	O
announced	O
,	O
saudi	LOC
arabia	LOC
's	O
stock	O
market	O
surged	O
more	O
than	O
3	O
percent	O
in	O
early	O
trade	O
.	O
escalating	O
regional	O
tensions	O
''	O
some	O
people	O
were	O
predicting	O
that	O
this	O
would	O
lead	O
to	O
a	O
division	O
in	O
the	O
family	O
and	O
strife	O
and	O
some	O
kind	O
of	O
revolt	O
.	O
i	O
do	O
n't	O
see	O
that	O
happening	O
,	O
''	O
haykel	PERS
said	O
.	O
iran	LOC
,	O
saudi	LOC
arabia	LOC
's	O
main	O
rival	O
for	O
regional	O
influence	O
,	O
called	O
prince	PERS
mohammed	PERS
's	O
appointment	O
a	O
``	O
soft	O
coup	O
''	O
.	O
iran	LOC
's	O
leadership	O
was	O
critical	O
of	O
comments	O
by	O
prince	PERS
mohammed	PERS
last	O
month	O
that	O
the	O
``	O
battle	O
''	O
should	O
be	O
taken	O
into	O
iran	LOC
,	O
with	O
supreme	O
leader	O
ayatollah	PERS
ali	PERS
khamenei	PERS
labelling	O
the	O
saudi	O
leadership	O
then	O
as	O
``	O
idiots	O
''	O
.	O
arab	O
leaders	O
,	O
including	O
oman	LOC
’	O
s	O
sultan	PERS
qaboos	PERS
,	O
jordan	O
’	O
s	O
king	O
abdullah	PERS
,	O
egypt	LOC
's	O
abdel	PERS
fattah	PERS
al-sisi	PERS
and	O
yemeni	O
president	O
abd-rabbu	PERS
mansour	PERS
hadi	PERS
congratulated	O
prince	PERS
mohammed	PERS
bin	PERS
salman	PERS
on	O
his	O
appointment	O
,	O
according	O
to	O
state	O
media	O
.	O
the	O
royal	O
decree	O
did	O
not	O
nominate	O
a	O
new	O
deputy	O
crown	O
prince	PERS
.	O
the	O
position	O
is	O
relatively	O
new	O
in	O
saudi	LOC
arabia	LOC
,	O
where	O
kings	O
have	O
traditionally	O
chosen	O
their	O
own	O
successors	O
.	O
in	O
an	O
apparent	O
attempt	O
to	O
appease	O
the	O
family	O
,	O
the	O
decree	O
had	O
a	O
clause	O
that	O
made	O
clear	O
that	O
mohammed	PERS
bin	PERS
salman	PERS
won	O
’	O
t	O
be	O
allowed	O
to	O
appoint	O
one	O
of	O
his	O
own	O
sons	O
as	O
his	O
successor	O
.	O
as	O
deputy	O
crown	O
prince	PERS
,	O
mohammed	PERS
bin	PERS
salman	PERS
has	O
been	O
responsible	O
for	O
running	O
saudi	LOC
arabia	LOC
's	O
war	O
in	O
yemen	LOC
,	O
dictating	O
an	O
energy	O
policy	O
with	O
global	O
implications	O
and	O
spearheading	O
plans	O
for	O
the	O
kingdom	O
to	O
build	O
an	O
economic	O
future	O
after	O
oil	O
.	O
that	O
the	O
royal	O
succession	O
in	O
the	O
world	O
's	O
top	O
oil	O
exporter	O
is	O
closely	O
scrutinised	O
only	O
makes	O
the	O
speed	O
of	O
mohammed	PERS
bin	PERS
salman	PERS
's	O
rise	O
to	O
power	O
-	O
and	O
the	O
speed	O
with	O
which	O
his	O
better-known	O
cousins	O
were	O
brushed	O
aside	O
-	O
more	O
astonishing	O
.	O
the	O
announcement	O
follows	O
2-1/2	O
years	O
of	O
already	O
major	O
changes	O
in	O
saudi	LOC
arabia	LOC
,	O
which	O
stunned	O
allies	O
in	O
2015	O
by	O
launching	O
an	O
air	O
war	O
in	O
yemen	LOC
,	O
cutting	O
back	O
on	O
lavish	O
subsidies	O
and	O
proposing	O
in	O
2016	O
the	O
partial	O
privatisation	O
of	O
state	O
oil	O
company	O
aramco	ORG
.	O
financial	O
analysts	O
said	O
prince	PERS
mohammed	PERS
's	O
promotion	O
gave	O
further	O
assurance	O
that	O
key	O
parts	O
of	O
radical	O
reforms	O
to	O
diversify	O
the	O
saudi	O
economy	O
beyond	O
oil	O
would	O
continue	O
.	O
``	O
we	O
do	O
not	O
expect	O
to	O
see	O
any	O
major	O
changes	O
to	O
key	O
areas	O
of	O
policy	O
,	O
including	O
economic	O
,	O
''	O
said	O
monica	PERS
malik	PERS
,	O
chief	O
economist	O
at	O
abu	ORG
dhabi	ORG
commercial	ORG
bank	ORG
.	O
last	O
year	O
mohammed	PERS
bin	PERS
salman	PERS
,	O
or	O
``	O
mbs	O
''	O
as	O
he	O
is	O
widely	O
known	O
,	O
announced	O
sweeping	O
changes	O
aimed	O
at	O
ending	O
the	O
kingdom	O
's	O
reliance	O
on	O
oil	O
,	O
part	O
of	O
his	O
campaign	O
to	O
tackle	O
systemic	O
challenges	O
that	O
the	O
kingdom	O
has	O
previously	O
failed	O
to	O
address	O
.	O
power	O
behind	O
the	O
throne	O
until	O
his	O
father	O
salman	PERS
bin	PERS
abdulaziz	PERS
al	PERS
saud	PERS
became	O
saudi	LOC
arabia	LOC
's	O
seventh	O
king	O
in	O
january	O
2015	O
,	O
few	O
people	O
outside	O
the	O
kingdom	O
had	O
ever	O
heard	O
of	O
prince	PERS
mohammed	PERS
.	O
he	O
is	O
currently	O
defence	ORG
minister	O
,	O
giving	O
him	O
command	O
of	O
one	O
of	O
the	O
world	O
's	O
biggest	O
arms	O
budgets	O
and	O
making	O
him	O
ultimately	O
responsible	O
for	O
saudi	LOC
arabia	LOC
's	O
military	O
adventure	O
in	O
yemen	LOC
.	O
he	O
also	O
heads	O
the	O
council	ORG
for	ORG
economic	ORG
and	ORG
development	ORG
affairs	ORG
(	O
ceda	ORG
)	O
,	O
a	O
group	O
of	O
cabinet	O
ministers	O
who	O
meet	O
weekly	O
and	O
which	O
oversees	O
all	O
elements	O
of	O
policy	O
touching	O
on	O
the	O
economy	O
or	O
social	O
issues	O
like	O
education	O
,	O
health	O
and	O
housing	O
.	O
prince	PERS
mohammed	PERS
chairs	O
the	O
supreme	O
board	O
of	O
aramco	ORG
,	O
making	O
him	O
the	O
first	O
member	O
of	O
the	O
ruling	O
family	O
to	O
directly	O
oversee	O
the	O
state	O
oil	O
company	O
,	O
long	O
regarded	O
as	O
the	O
preserve	O
of	O
commoner	O
technocrats	O
.	O
but	O
perhaps	O
most	O
importantly	O
,	O
he	O
is	O
the	O
gatekeeper	O
to	O
his	O
father	O
,	O
king	O
salman	PERS
,	O
who	O
in	O
saudi	LOC
arabia	LOC
's	O
absolute	O
monarchy	O
retains	O
the	O
final	O
say	O
in	O
any	O
major	O
decision	O
of	O
state	O
.	O
outside	O
saudi	LOC
arabia	LOC
,	O
that	O
rapid	O
advance	O
and	O
the	O
sudden	O
changes	O
to	O
longstanding	O
policies	O
on	O
regional	O
affairs	O
,	O
energy	O
and	O
its	O
economy	O
have	O
prompted	O
unease	O
,	O
adding	O
an	O
unpredictable	O
edge	O
to	O
a	O
kingdom	O
that	O
allies	O
long	O
regarded	O
as	O
a	O
known	O
quantity	O
.	O
inside	O
,	O
they	O
have	O
prompted	O
admiration	O
among	O
many	O
younger	O
saudis	O
who	O
regard	O
his	O
ascent	O
as	O
evidence	O
that	O
their	O
generation	O
is	O
taking	O
a	O
central	O
place	O
in	O
running	O
a	O
country	O
whose	O
patriarchal	O
traditions	O
have	O
for	O
decades	O
made	O
power	O
the	O
province	O
of	O
the	O
old	O
.	O
saudi	LOC
arabia	LOC
's	O
main	O
stock	O
index	O
was	O
3.4	O
percent	O
higher	O
.	O
national	ORG
commercial	ORG
bank	ORG
,	O
the	O
biggest	O
listed	O
lender	O
,	O
which	O
is	O
expected	O
to	O
play	O
a	O
major	O
role	O
in	O
funding	O
some	O
of	O
the	O
non-oil	O
industries	O
prince	PERS
mohammed	PERS
bin	PERS
salman	PERS
aims	O
to	O
develop	O
,	O
jumped	O
10	O
percent	O
.	O
(	O
reporting	O
by	O
stephen	PERS
kalin	PERS
,	O
william	PERS
maclean	PERS
,	O
rania	PERS
el	PERS
gamal	PERS
,	O
sylvia	PERS
westall	PERS
,	O
sami	PERS
aboudi	PERS
,	O
andrew	PERS
torchia	PERS
,	O
reem	PERS
shamseddine	PERS
,	O
angus	PERS
mcdowall	PERS
;	O
editing	O
by	O
samia	PERS
nakhoul	PERS
and	O
hugh	PERS
lawson	PERS
)	O
clifford	PERS
chance	PERS
advises	O
on	O
five	O
landmark	O
saudi	O
airport	O
privatisations	O
clifford	PERS
chance	PERS
,	O
in	O
co-operation	O
with	O
as	O
&	O
h	ORG
law	ORG
firm	ORG
in	O
saudi	LOC
arabia	LOC
,	O
advised	O
the	O
saudi	ORG
general	ORG
authority	ORG
of	ORG
civil	ORG
aviation	ORG
(	O
gaca	ORG
)	O
on	O
the	O
landmark	O
privatisations	O
of	O
five	O
of	O
saudi	LOC
arabia	LOC
's	O
international	O
airports	O
:	O
*	O
king	ORG
abdulaziz	ORG
international	ORG
airport	ORG
,	O
jeddah	ORG
*	O
taif	ORG
international	ORG
airport	ORG
,	O
taif	ORG
*	O
prince	ORG
nayef	ORG
bin	ORG
abdulaziz	ORG
airport	ORG
and	O
hail	ORG
airport	ORG
,	O
al-qassim	O
*	O
hail	ORG
airport	ORG
,	O
hail	ORG
*	O
prince	ORG
abdulmohsin	ORG
bin	ORG
abdulaziz	ORG
airport	ORG
,	O
yanbu	ORG
the	O
deals	O
are	O
the	O
first	O
to	O
be	O
signed	O
as	O
part	O
of	O
saudi	LOC
arabia	LOC
's	O
reinvigorated	O
plan	O
to	O
privatise	O
its	O
international	O
and	O
domestic	O
airports	O
by	O
2020	O
.	O
the	O
privatisations	O
received	O
enormous	O
interest	O
from	O
international	O
airport	O
operators	O
.	O
the	O
deals	O
are	O
also	O
the	O
first	O
major	O
non-utility	O
ppp	ORG
projects	ORG
to	O
close	O
in	O
the	O
kingdom	O
,	O
tangible	O
evidence	O
of	O
the	O
kingdom	O
pursuing	O
a	O
ppp	ORG
strategy	O
for	O
developing	O
its	O
capital	O
projects	ORG
.	O
the	O
concession	O
contracts	O
have	O
been	O
entered	O
into	O
with	O
consortiums	O
that	O
include	O
world-leading	O
operating	O
members	O
,	O
with	O
jeddah	ORG
airport	ORG
involving	O
a	O
concession	O
contract	O
with	O
changi	ORG
airports	ORG
;	O
taif	ORG
airport	ORG
with	O
munich	ORG
airports	ORG
;	O
and	O
qassim	O
,	O
hail	ORG
and	ORG
yanbu	ORG
airports	ORG
with	O
tav	O
.	O
these	O
concession	O
agreements	O
deliver	O
critical	O
upgrades	O
to	O
each	O
airport	O
and	O
stand	O
to	O
change	O
the	O
face	O
of	O
aviation	O
in	O
the	O
kingdom	O
.	O
not	O
only	O
were	O
the	O
deals	O
signed	O
in	O
record	O
time	O
,	O
clifford	PERS
chance	PERS
helped	O
gaca	ORG
successfully	O
negotiate	O
out	O
of	O
traffic	O
risk	O
guarantees	O
for	O
the	O
first	O
time	O
.	O
mohamed	PERS
hamra-krouha	PERS
,	O
clifford	PERS
chance	PERS
partner	PERS
commented	O
:	O
``	O
congratulations	O
to	O
gaca	ORG
and	O
all	O
the	O
parties	O
involved	O
on	O
these	O
truly	O
landmark	O
and	O
game-changing	O
agreements	O
.	O
through	O
the	O
strength	O
of	O
our	O
local	O
team	O
backed	O
by	O
international	O
experts	O
,	O
we	O
delivered	O
to	O
gaca	ORG
the	O
combination	O
of	O
global	O
best-practice	O
and	O
formidable	O
saudi	O
know-how	O
allowing	O
gaca	ORG
to	O
set	O
up	O
agreements	O
that	O
will	O
pave	O
the	O
way	O
forward	O
for	O
its	O
future	O
airport	O
privatisations	O
.	O
''	O
hamra-krouha	PERS
further	O
added	O
:	O
``	O
clifford	PERS
chance	PERS
is	O
at	O
the	O
forefront	O
of	O
the	O
development	O
of	O
ppp	ORG
in	O
the	O
region	O
.	O
uniquely	O
,	O
through	O
our	O
embedded	O
and	O
market-leading	O
specialist	O
projects	ORG
and	O
construction	O
teams	O
,	O
we	O
offer	O
clients	O
innovative	O
and	O
balanced	O
contractual	O
structures	O
that	O
are	O
designed	O
to	O
support	O
the	O
financial	O
requirements	O
of	O
external	O
funders	O
,	O
and	O
the	O
efficiency	O
of	O
major	O
international	O
projects	ORG
in	O
relation	O
to	O
construction	O
,	O
operation	O
and	O
maintenance	O
risk	O
whilst	O
taking	O
account	O
of	O
the	O
interests	O
of	O
equity	O
and	O
contractors	O
.	O
''	O
the	O
clifford	PERS
chance	PERS
team	O
was	O
co-led	O
led	O
by	O
mohamed	PERS
hamra-krouha	PERS
(	O
partner	PERS
and	O
co-head	O
of	O
finance	ORG
,	O
riyadh	LOC
)	O
and	O
florian	PERS
mahler	PERS
(	O
partner	PERS
,	O
germany	LOC
)	O
and	O
included	O
richard	PERS
parris	PERS
(	O
partner	PERS
,	O
head	O
of	O
projects	ORG
&	ORG
energy	ORG
,	O
middle	LOC
east	LOC
)	O
,	O
sergei	PERS
kabanov	PERS
(	O
senior	O
associate	O
,	O
germany	LOC
)	O
,	O
alhassane	PERS
barry	PERS
(	O
counsel	O
,	O
abu	LOC
dhabi	LOC
)	O
,	O
michael	PERS
gabriel	PERS
(	O
associate	O
,	O
abu	LOC
dhabi	LOC
)	O
,	O
jennifer	PERS
riddle	PERS
(	O
associate	O
,	O
abu	LOC
dhabi	LOC
)	O
.	O
the	O
riyadh-based	O
as	O
&	O
h	O
team	O
included	O
omar	PERS
rashid	PERS
(	O
clifford	PERS
chance	PERS
partner	PERS
seconded	O
to	O
as	O
&	O
h	O
)	O
,	O
bilal	PERS
rana	PERS
(	O
clifford	PERS
chance	PERS
senior	O
associate	O
seconded	O
to	O
as	O
&	O
h	O
)	O
,	O
rizwan	PERS
butt	PERS
(	O
clifford	PERS
chance	PERS
associate	O
seconded	O
to	O
as	O
&	O
h	O
)	O
,	O
and	O
sahal	PERS
khalawi	PERS
(	O
associate	O
,	O
as	O
&	O
h	O
)	O
,	O
abdullah	PERS
al-obaid	PERS
(	O
associate	O
,	O
as	O
&	O
h	O
)	O
.	O
elsewhere	O
,	O
clifford	PERS
chance	PERS
has	O
also	O
recently	O
advised	O
vinci	ORG
airports	ORG
in	O
relation	O
to	O
the	O
concession	O
to	O
operate	O
kansai	ORG
international	ORG
and	O
osaka	ORG
itami	ORG
airports	ORG
in	O
japan	LOC
.	O
the	O
firm	O
had	O
also	O
previously	O
advised	O
on	O
airport	O
privatisations	O
in	O
jordan	LOC
,	O
oman	LOC
,	O
turkey	LOC
,	O
russia	LOC
and	O
eastern	LOC
europe	LOC
.	O
clifford	PERS
chance	PERS
and	O
as	O
&	O
h	O
are	O
trusted	O
by	O
and	O
regularly	O
advise	O
key	O
saudi	O
ministries	O
and	O
entities	O
including	O
the	O
ministry	ORG
of	ORG
commerce	ORG
and	ORG
investment	ORG
,	O
the	O
public	ORG
investment	ORG
fund	ORG
,	O
the	O
saudi	ORG
arabian	ORG
monetary	ORG
agency	ORG
,	O
tadawul	ORG
,	O
ministry	ORG
of	ORG
labour	ORG
,	O
human	ORG
resources	ORG
development	ORG
fund	ORG
,	O
ministry	ORG
of	ORG
housing	ORG
,	O
general	ORG
authority	ORG
for	ORG
sports	ORG
as	O
well	O
as	O
a	O
wide	O
range	O
of	O
government	O
owned	O
and	O
privately	O
held	O
saudi	O
businesses	O
.	O
the	O
team	O
is	O
currently	O
advising	O
on	O
a	O
range	O
of	O
other	O
saudi	O
privatisation	O
programmes	O
.	O
saudi	LOC
arabia	LOC
's	O
ambitious	O
bin	PERS
salman	PERS
will	O
face	O
trial	O
by	O
fire	O
comment	O
:	O
both	O
at	O
home	O
and	O
abroad	O
the	O
challenges	O
facing	O
bin	PERS
salman	PERS
will	O
be	O
huge	O
.	O
it	O
is	O
unlikely	O
he	O
will	O
succeed	O
where	O
more	O
experienced	O
hands	O
did	O
not	O
,	O
writes	O
barak	PERS
barfi	PERS
.	O
in	O
recent	O
years	O
,	O
the	O
historically	O
reticent	O
and	O
deferential	O
kingdom	O
of	O
saudi	LOC
arabia	LOC
has	O
increasingly	O
discarded	O
the	O
traditions	O
which	O
have	O
protected	O
the	O
insular	O
country	O
from	O
regional	O
tremors	O
that	O
have	O
toppled	O
other	O
monarchies	O
.	O
this	O
week	O
's	O
succession	O
shakeup	O
,	O
in	O
which	O
31-year-old	O
prince	O
muhammad	PERS
bin	PERS
salman	PERS
was	O
elevated	O
to	O
dauphin	O
is	O
just	O
the	O
latest	O
.	O
at	O
a	O
time	O
when	O
saudi	LOC
arabia	LOC
is	O
facing	O
so	O
many	O
threats	O
and	O
uncertainties	O
,	O
it	O
needs	O
a	O
steady	O
and	O
experienced	O
hand	O
to	O
guide	O
the	O
kingdom	O
.	O
but	O
bin	PERS
salman	PERS
's	O
trial	O
by	O
fire	O
is	O
unlikely	O
to	O
provide	O
the	O
necessary	O
calming	O
influence	O
.	O
when	O
bin	PERS
salman	PERS
was	O
named	O
deputy	PERS
crown	PERS
prince	O
upon	O
his	O
father	O
's	O
succession	O
in	O
2015	O
,	O
the	O
choice	O
surprised	O
many	O
.	O
he	O
was	O
a	O
29-year-old	O
unknown	O
in	O
a	O
kingdom	O
where	O
royals	O
are	O
slowly	O
moved	O
up	O
the	O
government	O
pecking	O
order	O
.	O
in	O
a	O
kingdom	O
and	O
culture	O
that	O
prizes	O
seniority	O
,	O
the	O
meteoric	O
advancement	O
of	O
a	O
young	O
prince	O
was	O
frowned	O
upon	O
.	O
nevertheless	O
,	O
his	O
elevation	O
proceeded	O
smoothly	O
.	O
thirty-one	O
of	O
the	O
thirty-four	O
members	O
of	O
the	O
allegiance	ORG
committee	ORG
,	O
composed	O
of	O
the	O
descendants	O
of	O
the	O
kingdom	O
's	O
founder	O
who	O
choose	O
the	O
king	O
and	O
crown	O
prince	O
,	O
approved	O
the	O
change	O
in	O
succession	O
.	O
the	O
mufti	O
,	O
the	O
kingdom	O
's	O
senior	O
religious	O
scholar	O
,	O
declared	O
``	O
the	O
obligation	O
to	O
swear	O
an	O
oath	O
of	O
allegiance	O
is	O
incumbent	O
on	O
everybody	O
''	O
and	O
publicly	O
did	O
so	O
.	O
in	O
a	O
kingdom	O
and	O
culture	O
that	O
prizes	O
seniority	O
,	O
the	O
meteoric	O
advancement	O
of	O
a	O
young	O
prince	O
was	O
frowned	O
upon	O
.	O
since	O
his	O
father	O
ascended	O
to	O
the	O
throne	O
,	O
bin	PERS
salman	PERS
has	O
been	O
receiving	O
a	O
crash	O
course	O
in	O
ruling	O
the	O
kingdom	O
,	O
amassing	O
unprecedented	O
powers	O
.	O
he	O
is	O
minister	O
of	O
defense	ORG
and	O
oversees	O
a	O
war	O
saudi	LOC
arabia	LOC
is	O
fighting	O
in	O
neighbouring	O
yemen	LOC
.	O
in	O
addition	O
,	O
he	O
manages	O
both	O
state	O
oil	O
company	O
aramco	ORG
and	O
the	O
public	O
investment	O
company	O
,	O
while	O
directing	O
economic	O
policy	O
.	O
accruing	O
so	O
much	O
power	O
is	O
a	O
rarity	O
in	O
a	O
kingdom	O
where	O
the	O
sovereign	O
carefully	O
and	O
widely	O
allocates	O
positions	O
among	O
a	O
sprawling	O
royal	O
family	O
.	O
the	O
young	O
bin	PERS
salman	PERS
is	O
brash	O
and	O
bucks	O
diplomatic	O
convention	O
.	O
he	O
hastily	O
plunged	O
the	O
kingdom	O
into	O
the	O
yemen	LOC
war	O
without	O
coordinating	O
the	O
move	O
across	O
the	O
security	O
establishment	O
and	O
without	O
fully	O
grasping	O
its	O
ramifications	O
.	O
read	O
more	O
:	O
saudi	O
succession	O
reshuffle	O
:	O
a	O
threat	O
to	O
the	O
house	O
of	O
cards	O
during	O
a	O
november	O
2015	O
meeting	O
between	O
president	O
obama	PERS
and	O
his	O
father	O
,	O
bin	PERS
salman	PERS
unleashed	O
an	O
uncharacteristic	O
diatribe	O
against	O
america	LOC
's	O
middle	LOC
east	LOC
policy	O
.	O
while	O
bin	PERS
salman	PERS
is	O
insular	O
,	O
having	O
never	O
studied	O
outside	O
the	O
kingdom	O
,	O
he	O
does	O
not	O
have	O
the	O
playboy	O
image	O
like	O
that	O
of	O
the	O
late	O
king	O
fahd	PERS
.	O
president	O
barack	PERS
obama	PERS
once	O
described	O
him	O
as	O
``	O
wise	O
beyond	O
his	O
years	O
''	O
.	O
bin	PERS
salman	PERS
advocates	O
a	O
muscular	O
foreign	O
policy	O
that	O
is	O
at	O
odds	O
with	O
the	O
kingdom	O
's	O
traditional	O
deference	O
to	O
regional	O
powers	O
such	O
as	O
egypt	LOC
,	O
iraq	LOC
and	O
syria	LOC
and	O
which	O
may	O
be	O
beyond	O
the	O
saudis	O
'	O
capacity	O
.	O
for	O
decades	O
,	O
the	O
saudis	O
worked	O
behind	O
the	O
scenes	O
,	O
quietly	O
persuading	O
proxies	O
to	O
do	O
their	O
bidding	O
by	O
opening	O
their	O
deep	O
purses	O
.	O
but	O
the	O
breakdown	O
of	O
the	O
arab	O
order	O
-	O
iraq	LOC
and	O
syria	LOC
are	O
failed	O
states	O
and	O
egypt	LOC
is	O
a	O
walking	O
corpse	O
-	O
has	O
thrust	O
the	O
kingdom	O
into	O
a	O
spotlight	O
it	O
has	O
never	O
sought	O
.	O
the	O
breakdown	O
of	O
the	O
arab	O
order	O
has	O
thrust	O
the	O
kingdom	O
into	O
a	O
spotlight	O
it	O
has	O
never	O
sought	O
its	O
initial	O
moves	O
leave	O
much	O
to	O
be	O
desired	O
,	O
and	O
bin	PERS
salman	PERS
faces	O
a	O
perilous	O
road	O
ahead	O
.	O
the	O
kingdom	O
is	O
grappling	O
with	O
a	O
vietnam-like	O
intervention	O
in	O
neighbouring	O
yemen	LOC
,	O
an	O
infringing	O
iran	LOC
which	O
is	O
expanding	O
shia	O
control	O
in	O
the	O
region	O
and	O
low	O
oil	O
prices	O
which	O
are	O
the	O
source	O
of	O
virtually	O
all	O
of	O
the	O
economy	O
's	O
revenues	O
.	O
and	O
in	O
recent	O
weeks	O
,	O
the	O
kingdom	O
has	O
spearheaded	O
an	O
anti-qatar	O
coalition	O
.	O
even	O
during	O
the	O
arab	O
cold	O
war	O
of	O
the	O
1950s	O
and	O
60s	O
,	O
which	O
pitted	O
the	O
conservative	O
and	O
pious	O
kingdom	O
against	O
the	O
secular	O
pan-arabism	O
of	O
egyptian	O
president	O
jamal	PERS
abd	PERS
al-nasser	PERS
,	O
it	O
never	O
had	O
to	O
juggle	O
so	O
many	O
dilemmas	O
.	O
it	O
is	O
unlikely	O
a	O
political	O
neophyte	O
such	O
as	O
bin	PERS
salman	PERS
will	O
succeed	O
where	O
more	O
experienced	O
hands	O
were	O
only	O
muddied	O
.	O
bin	PERS
salman	PERS
may	O
have	O
not	O
have	O
much	O
more	O
success	O
on	O
the	O
domestic	O
front	O
.	O
he	O
has	O
spearheaded	O
the	O
vision	O
2030	O
plan	O
which	O
seeks	O
to	O
modernise	O
the	O
kingdom	O
and	O
diversify	O
the	O
economy	O
by	O
weaning	O
it	O
off	O
the	O
oil	O
which	O
turned	O
the	O
most	O
impoverished	O
area	O
of	O
the	O
arab	O
world	O
into	O
its	O
wealthiest	O
.	O
but	O
here	O
too	O
,	O
bin	PERS
salman	PERS
has	O
adopted	O
a	O
maverick	O
streak	O
by	O
not	O
cultivating	O
ties	O
with	O
the	O
religious	O
establishment	O
which	O
dictates	O
social	O
mores	O
among	O
its	O
goals	O
is	O
the	O
unrealistic	O
privatisation	O
of	O
aramco	ORG
.	O
doing	O
so	O
would	O
bring	O
in	O
billions	O
of	O
dollars	O
but	O
would	O
reduce	O
saudi	O
control	O
over	O
a	O
company	O
it	O
guards	O
closely	O
.	O
bin	PERS
salman	PERS
has	O
however	O
been	O
successful	O
in	O
reducing	O
subsidies	O
which	O
are	O
an	O
albatross	O
on	O
budgets	O
throughout	O
the	O
arab	O
world	O
.	O
saudi	O
media	O
is	O
positioning	O
bin	PERS
salman	PERS
as	O
``	O
the	O
prince	O
of	O
the	O
youth	O
``	O
.	O
he	O
has	O
championed	O
loosening	O
the	O
social	O
structures	O
that	O
stifle	O
the	O
kingdom	O
's	O
younger	O
generation	O
.	O
but	O
here	O
too	O
,	O
bin	PERS
salman	PERS
has	O
adopted	O
a	O
maverick	O
streak	O
by	O
not	O
cultivating	O
ties	O
with	O
the	O
religious	O
establishment	O
which	O
dictates	O
social	O
mores	O
.	O
without	O
their	O
support	O
,	O
it	O
is	O
unlikely	O
he	O
will	O
be	O
able	O
to	O
modernise	O
society	O
.	O
when	O
bin	PERS
salman	PERS
accedes	O
to	O
the	O
throne	O
,	O
the	O
passing	O
of	O
the	O
baton	O
to	O
the	O
younger	O
generation	O
will	O
undoubtedly	O
bring	O
change	O
to	O
a	O
kingdom	O
that	O
has	O
historically	O
viewed	O
the	O
concept	O
as	O
anathema	O
.	O
the	O
modernisation	O
of	O
society	O
is	O
undoubdetly	O
a	O
noble	O
objective	O
.	O
but	O
it	O
requires	O
meticulous	O
preparation	O
to	O
avoid	O
regional	O
pitfalls	O
and	O
exhaustive	O
consultation	O
to	O
ensure	O
at	O
least	O
tepid	O
support	O
from	O
the	O
religious	O
establishment	O
.	O
bin	PERS
salman	PERS
has	O
evinced	O
neither	O
.	O
until	O
he	O
acquires	O
the	O
requisite	O
skills	O
to	O
do	O
so	O
,	O
saudi	LOC
arabia	LOC
's	O
bold	O
domestic	O
and	O
regional	O
shifts	O
are	O
unlikely	O
to	O
succeed	O
.	O
barak	PERS
barfi	PERS
is	O
a	O
research	O
fellow	O
at	O
the	O
new	ORG
america	ORG
foundation	ORG
,	O
where	O
he	O
specialises	O
in	O
arab	O
and	O
islamic	O
affairs	O
.	O
opinions	O
expressed	O
in	O
this	O
article	O
remain	O
those	O
of	O
the	O
author	O
and	O
do	O
not	O
necessarily	O
represent	O
those	O
of	O
the	O
new	O
arab	O
,	O
its	O
editorial	O
board	O
or	O
staff	O
.	O
join	O
the	O
conversation	O
by	O
tweeting	O
to	O
us	O
:	O
@	O
the_newarab	O
four	O
ways	O
mohammed	PERS
bin	PERS
salman	PERS
's	O
rise	O
will	O
change	O
saudi	LOC
arabia	LOC
saudi	O
's	O
new	O
crown	O
prince	O
-	O
and	O
next	O
in	O
line	O
to	O
the	O
throne	O
-	O
is	O
not	O
a	O
capable	O
fire	O
fighter	O
,	O
nor	O
a	O
tactical	O
statesman	O
.	O
he	O
will	O
rule	O
by	O
iron	O
fist	O
,	O
declare	O
erratic	O
economic	O
policies	O
and	O
likely	O
light	O
more	O
regional	O
fires	O
along	O
the	O
way	O
as	O
expected	O
,	O
on	O
wednesday	O
,	O
king	O
salman	PERS
finally	O
promoted	O
his	O
young	O
son	O
mohammed	PERS
to	O
crown	O
prince	O
after	O
sacking	O
mohammed	PERS
bin	PERS
nayef	PERS
who	O
,	O
according	O
to	O
official	O
sources	O
,	O
asked	O
to	O
be	O
relieved	O
of	O
his	O
duties	O
as	O
crown	O
prince	O
because	O
of	O
“	O
private	O
issues	O
”	O
.	O
the	O
king	O
has	O
also	O
amended	O
sections	O
of	O
the	O
1990	O
basic	O
law	O
of	O
government	O
to	O
move	O
to	O
vertical	O
royal	O
succession	O
from	O
father	O
to	O
son	O
for	O
the	O
office	O
of	O
king	O
,	O
thus	O
ending	O
the	O
horizontal	O
succession	O
from	O
brother	O
to	O
brother	O
that	O
had	O
been	O
put	O
in	O
place	O
by	O
the	O
founder	O
of	O
the	O
kingdom	O
,	O
king	O
abdulaziz	PERS
ibn	PERS
saud	PERS
,	O
in	O
1933	O
.	O
mohammed	PERS
bin	PERS
salman	PERS
thinks	O
that	O
money	O
solves	O
problems	O
but	O
this	O
has	O
not	O
enabled	O
him	O
to	O
claim	O
victories	O
in	O
the	O
many	O
wars	O
that	O
he	O
has	O
started	O
so	O
far	O
,	O
it	O
is	O
unclear	O
why	O
the	O
king	O
has	O
not	O
appointed	O
a	O
deputy	O
crown	O
prince	O
as	O
is	O
customary	O
in	O
these	O
circumstances	O
.	O
furthermore	O
,	O
the	O
central	O
question	O
-	O
whether	O
the	O
king	O
will	O
abdicate	O
soon	O
and	O
allow	O
his	O
son	O
to	O
become	O
king	O
in	O
his	O
lifetime	O
-	O
remains	O
unanswered	O
.	O
historically	O
,	O
no	O
saudi	O
king	O
has	O
abdicated	O
according	O
to	O
his	O
own	O
will	O
.	O
king	O
saud	O
was	O
deposed	O
in	O
1964	O
under	O
palace	O
siege	O
,	O
followed	O
by	O
safe	O
voyage	O
to	O
greece	LOC
.	O
without	O
further	O
ado	O
,	O
31	O
out	O
of	O
34	O
royal	O
members	O
of	O
the	O
committee	ORG
of	ORG
allegiance	ORG
,	O
a	O
royal	O
consortium	O
established	O
as	O
a	O
consultation	O
forum	O
,	O
are	O
reported	O
to	O
have	O
``	O
voted	O
''	O
mohammed	PERS
bin	PERS
salman	PERS
into	O
his	O
new	O
role	O
.	O
saudi	ORG
news	ORG
agency	ORG
immediately	O
released	O
a	O
video	O
showing	O
young	O
mohammed	PERS
thanking	O
his	O
cousin	O
bin	PERS
nayef	PERS
for	O
a	O
smooth	O
departure	O
without	O
a	O
fuss	O
and	O
endeared	O
him	O
with	O
an	O
aborted	O
attempt	O
to	O
kiss	O
his	O
feet	O
in	O
gratitude	O
.	O
«	O
بن	O
نايف	O
»	O
يبايع	O
«	O
بن	O
سلمان	O
»	O
:	O
أنا	O
أرتاح	O
الحين	O
وإنت	O
الله	O
يعينك	O
pic.twitter.com/rb3ruz98hv	O
—	O
الخليج	O
الجديد	O
(	O
@	O
thenewkhaleej	O
)	O
june	O
21	O
,	O
2017	O
the	O
king	O
also	O
appointed	O
abdulaziz	PERS
bin	PERS
saud	PERS
bin	PERS
nayef	PERS
,	O
the	O
deposed	O
crown	O
prince	O
's	O
nephew	O
and	O
grandson	O
of	O
deceased	O
prince	O
nayef	PERS
,	O
who	O
had	O
been	O
minister	O
of	O
interior	ORG
until	O
his	O
death	O
(	O
1975-2012	O
)	O
,	O
as	O
the	O
new	O
minister	O
of	O
interior	ORG
,	O
thus	O
perpetuating	O
nayef	PERS
's	O
old	O
fiefdom	O
over	O
the	O
most	O
important	O
ministry	O
for	O
domestic	O
security	O
.	O
fun	O
and	O
neoliberalism	O
the	O
new	O
appointment	O
means	O
a	O
lot	O
of	O
things	O
for	O
the	O
future	O
of	O
the	O
kingdom	O
-	O
and	O
all	O
point	O
to	O
uncertainty	O
brought	O
about	O
by	O
the	O
erratic	O
mohammed	PERS
.	O
first	O
,	O
rule	O
by	O
a	O
continuous	O
iron	O
fist	O
at	O
home	O
will	O
be	O
entrenched	O
.	O
mohammed	PERS
bin	PERS
salman	PERS
will	O
silence	O
any	O
dissident	O
voices	O
while	O
allowing	O
limited	O
personal	O
freedoms	O
organised	O
by	O
his	O
new	O
entertainment	O
commission	O
in	O
charge	O
of	O
keeping	O
saudis	O
moderately	O
entertained	O
.	O
it	O
is	O
common	O
for	O
dictators	O
to	O
allow	O
their	O
marginalised	O
subjects	O
certain	O
forms	O
of	O
controlled	O
fun	O
,	O
lest	O
they	O
implode	O
from	O
within	O
it	O
is	O
common	O
for	O
dictators	O
to	O
allow	O
their	O
marginalised	O
subjects	O
certain	O
forms	O
of	O
controlled	O
fun	O
,	O
lest	O
they	O
implode	O
from	O
within	O
.	O
women	O
will	O
also	O
be	O
symbols	O
of	O
a	O
new	O
saudi	O
consumer	O
modernity	O
and	O
soon	O
may	O
be	O
allowed	O
to	O
drive	O
cars	O
.	O
in	O
the	O
future	O
,	O
saudis	O
will	O
enjoy	O
themselves	O
up	O
to	O
a	O
certain	O
level	O
without	O
harassment	O
by	O
the	O
religious	O
police	O
.	O
mohammed	PERS
bin	PERS
salman	PERS
will	O
continue	O
to	O
ignore	O
a	O
redundant	O
,	O
marginalised	O
and	O
discredited	O
wahhabi	O
religious	O
establishment	O
.	O
but	O
with	O
the	O
dispersal	O
of	O
saudis	O
who	O
had	O
joined	O
the	O
islamic	O
state	O
(	O
is	O
)	O
caliphate	O
,	O
and	O
the	O
possible	O
return	O
of	O
those	O
from	O
syria	LOC
,	O
he	O
may	O
expect	O
a	O
bumpy	O
ride	O
in	O
the	O
top	O
seat	O
.	O
when	O
al-qaeda	ORG
was	O
dispersed	O
from	O
afghanistan	LOC
after	O
2001	O
,	O
many	O
saudis	O
who	O
had	O
joined	O
its	O
ranks	O
returned	O
and	O
caused	O
the	O
worst	O
terrorism	O
crisis	O
the	O
country	O
has	O
seen	O
.	O
is	O
already	O
claimed	O
several	O
attacks	O
in	O
saudi	LOC
arabia	LOC
since	O
2015	O
,	O
but	O
its	O
sectarian	O
outlook	O
may	O
prove	O
to	O
be	O
useful	O
for	O
mohammed	PERS
bin	PERS
salman	PERS
’	O
s	O
current	O
crisis	O
with	O
iran	LOC
.	O
second	O
,	O
erratic	O
economic	O
policies	O
that	O
may	O
not	O
deliver	O
the	O
desired	O
neoliberal	O
economy	O
-	O
including	O
weaning	O
saudi	LOC
arabia	LOC
away	O
from	O
oil	O
by	O
2020	O
,	O
shrinking	O
the	O
welfare	O
state	O
,	O
privatisation	O
and	O
,	O
most	O
importantly	O
,	O
floating	O
5	O
percent	O
of	O
the	O
saudi	O
oil	O
company	O
aramco	ORG
in	O
international	O
markets	O
by	O
september	O
2017	O
-	O
will	O
continue	O
.	O
so	O
one	O
day	O
,	O
mohammed	PERS
bin	PERS
salman	PERS
might	O
announce	O
that	O
saudis	O
must	O
tighten	O
their	O
belts	O
,	O
but	O
another	O
day	O
he	O
could	O
reward	O
them	O
for	O
their	O
acquiescence	O
by	O
unfreezing	O
public	O
sector	O
salaries	O
and	O
giving	O
them	O
extra	O
holidays	O
.	O
a	O
successful	O
neoliberal	O
paradise	O
with	O
less	O
working	O
days	O
and	O
low	O
productivity	O
may	O
require	O
miraculous	O
intervention	O
.	O
losing	O
the	O
regional	O
struggle	O
third	O
,	O
mohammed	PERS
bin	PERS
salman	PERS
will	O
struggle	O
to	O
become	O
a	O
serious	O
regional	O
power	O
on	O
par	O
with	O
turkey	LOC
,	O
iran	LOC
,	O
and	O
israel	LOC
,	O
all	O
of	O
which	O
currently	O
flex	O
their	O
muscles	O
in	O
a	O
bid	O
to	O
emerge	O
as	O
the	O
dominant	O
force	O
dictating	O
the	O
outcomes	O
of	O
several	O
conflicts	O
in	O
the	O
arab	O
world	O
.	O
he	O
has	O
already	O
alienated	O
turkey	LOC
and	O
iran	LOC
-	O
the	O
former	O
sided	O
with	O
qatar	LOC
in	O
the	O
latest	O
crisis	O
.	O
he	O
also	O
promised	O
to	O
bring	O
the	O
war	O
deep	O
inside	O
iran	LOC
,	O
a	O
statement	O
that	O
ultimately	O
amounts	O
to	O
a	O
declaration	O
of	O
war	O
.	O
he	O
and	O
is	O
share	O
the	O
same	O
sectarian	O
outlook	O
and	O
may	O
well	O
cooperate	O
,	O
especially	O
after	O
is	O
runs	O
out	O
of	O
targets	O
in	O
syria	LOC
and	O
iraq	LOC
mohammed	PERS
bin	PERS
salman	PERS
does	O
not	O
seem	O
to	O
know	O
the	O
implications	O
of	O
his	O
flamboyant	O
statements	O
.	O
but	O
he	O
and	O
is	O
share	O
the	O
same	O
sectarian	O
outlook	O
and	O
may	O
well	O
cooperate	O
,	O
especially	O
after	O
is	O
runs	O
out	O
of	O
targets	O
in	O
syria	LOC
and	O
iraq	LOC
.	O
is	O
may	O
be	O
instructed	O
to	O
move	O
its	O
terrorism	O
campaign	O
to	O
iran	LOC
after	O
its	O
defeat	O
in	O
mosul	LOC
and	O
raqqa	LOC
.	O
he	O
may	O
have	O
scored	O
success	O
with	O
israel	LOC
,	O
now	O
dubbed	O
jokingly	O
as	O
the	O
newest	O
sunni	LOC
state	O
,	O
in	O
his	O
bid	O
to	O
form	O
a	O
pan-islamic	O
alliance	O
against	O
both	O
iran	LOC
and	O
qatar	LOC
.	O
he	O
will	O
continue	O
to	O
clandestinely	O
cooperate	O
with	O
israel	LOC
in	O
security	O
and	O
economic	O
matters	O
,	O
but	O
we	O
should	O
n't	O
expect	O
an	O
israeli	O
flag	O
to	O
be	O
raised	O
in	O
riyadh	LOC
soon	O
.	O
this	O
will	O
take	O
some	O
preparation	O
and	O
coordination	O
and	O
the	O
stakes	O
in	O
such	O
a	O
controversial	O
move	O
are	O
high	O
.	O
trump-mbs	O
symbiosis	O
fourth	O
,	O
mohammed	PERS
bin	PERS
salman	PERS
will	O
continue	O
courting	O
us	LOC
president	O
donald	PERS
trump	PERS
,	O
exchanging	O
weapon	O
contracts	O
and	O
investment	O
promises	O
for	O
continuous	O
support	O
-	O
at	O
least	O
in	O
public	O
.	O
like	O
mohammed	PERS
bin	PERS
salman	PERS
,	O
trump	PERS
is	O
also	O
unpredictable	O
and	O
the	O
two	O
men	O
may	O
fall	O
out	O
over	O
minor	O
differences	O
.	O
however	O
,	O
they	O
will	O
keep	O
the	O
facade	O
of	O
agreement	O
until	O
they	O
achieve	O
their	O
objectives	O
both	O
at	O
home	O
and	O
abroad	O
.	O
the	O
new	O
crown	O
prince	O
does	O
not	O
seem	O
to	O
have	O
time	O
for	O
europe	LOC
at	O
the	O
moment	O
.	O
he	O
will	O
continue	O
to	O
see	O
it	O
as	O
a	O
holiday	O
destination	O
for	O
his	O
newly	O
purchased	O
yacht	O
and	O
as	O
a	O
source	O
of	O
more	O
weapons	O
that	O
he	O
can	O
not	O
get	O
elsewhere	O
.	O
this	O
will	O
mean	O
that	O
european	O
arms	O
manufacturers	O
and	O
governments	O
in	O
britain	LOC
and	O
france	LOC
will	O
compete	O
for	O
the	O
attention	O
of	O
the	O
young	O
prince	O
.	O
trump	PERS
meets	O
with	O
then-saudi	O
deputy	O
crown	O
prince	O
mohammed	PERS
bin	PERS
salman	PERS
in	O
the	O
oval	ORG
office	ORG
of	ORG
the	ORG
white	ORG
house	ORG
in	ORG
washington	ORG
in	O
march	O
2017	O
(	O
reuters	ORG
)	O
both	O
countries	O
may	O
have	O
lost	O
their	O
favourite	O
saudi	O
candidate	O
,	O
mohammed	PERS
bin	PERS
nayef	PERS
,	O
who	O
had	O
succeeded	O
in	O
establishing	O
a	O
good	O
rapport	O
with	O
western	O
intelligence	O
services	O
as	O
he	O
was	O
seen	O
as	O
crucial	O
in	O
the	O
fight	O
against	O
terrorism	O
.	O
british	O
prime	O
minister	O
theresa	PERS
may	O
will	O
need	O
the	O
new	O
crown	O
prince	O
for	O
economic	O
reasons	O
as	O
britain	LOC
risks	O
shrinking	O
both	O
economically	O
and	O
politically	O
after	O
brexit	O
.	O
at	O
the	O
moment	O
,	O
salman	PERS
’	O
s	O
kingdom	O
seems	O
to	O
take	O
shape	O
amid	O
real	O
challenges	O
both	O
domestically	O
and	O
regionally	O
.	O
the	O
new	O
appointment	O
may	O
not	O
be	O
challenged	O
by	O
other	O
princes	O
or	O
by	O
groups	O
inside	O
the	O
country	O
but	O
the	O
future	O
looks	O
troubled	O
.	O
mohammed	PERS
bin	PERS
salman	PERS
is	O
not	O
a	O
capable	O
fire	O
fighter	O
or	O
a	O
tactical	O
statesman	O
.	O
he	O
thinks	O
only	O
money	O
solves	O
problems	O
but	O
this	O
has	O
not	O
enabled	O
him	O
to	O
claim	O
victories	O
in	O
the	O
many	O
wars	O
and	O
conflicts	O
that	O
he	O
started	O
.	O
he	O
is	O
more	O
likely	O
to	O
light	O
further	O
regional	O
fires	O
than	O
extinguish	O
existing	O
ones	O
.	O
-	O
professor	O
madawi	PERS
al-rasheed	PERS
is	O
a	O
visiting	O
professor	O
at	O
the	O
middle	ORG
east	ORG
centre	ORG
at	O
lse	O
.	O
she	O
has	O
written	O
extensively	O
about	O
the	O
arabian	LOC
peninsula	LOC
,	O
arab	O
migration	O
,	O
globalisation	O
,	O
religious	O
transnationalism	O
and	O
gender	O
.	O
on	O
twitter	ORG
:	O
@	O
madawidr	O
the	O
views	O
expressed	O
in	O
this	O
article	O
belong	O
to	O
the	O
author	O
and	O
do	O
not	O
necessarily	O
reflect	O
the	O
editorial	O
policy	O
of	O
middle	LOC
east	LOC
eye	O
.	O
photo	O
:	O
saudi	O
defence	ORG
minister	O
and	O
then-deputy	O
crown	O
prince	O
mohammed	PERS
bin	PERS
salman	PERS
meets	O
with	O
saudi	O
air	O
forces	O
officers	O
in	O
march	O
2015	O
to	O
discuss	O
plans	O
and	O
developments	O
of	O
the	O
military	O
operations	O
in	O
yemen	LOC
(	O
afp	ORG
)	O
paddy	PERS
padmanathan	PERS
,	O
president	O
&	O
ceo	O
,	O
acwa	O
power	O
,	O
on	O
the	O
saudi	O
private	O
sector	O
and	O
development	O
of	O
the	O
renewable	O
energy	O
industry	O
what	O
greater	O
role	O
do	O
you	O
think	O
the	O
saudi	O
private	O
sector	O
can	O
take	O
with	O
the	O
launch	O
of	O
vision	O
2030	O
?	O
paddy	PERS
padmanathan	PERS
:	O
about	O
80	O
%	O
of	O
fixing	O
any	O
problem	O
is	O
becoming	O
conscious	O
of	O
it	O
and	O
articulating	O
a	O
plan	O
to	O
fix	O
it	O
.	O
that	O
is	O
what	O
saudi	LOC
arabia	LOC
has	O
achieved	O
with	O
vision	O
2030	O
and	O
the	O
national	O
transformation	O
programme	O
(	O
ntp	O
)	O
so	O
far	O
.	O
no	O
other	O
country	O
in	O
the	O
world	O
has	O
developed	O
such	O
detailed	O
set	O
of	O
key	O
performance	O
indicators	O
for	O
monitoring	O
the	O
government	O
’	O
s	O
performance	O
in	O
restructuring	O
the	O
national	O
economy	O
.	O
since	O
the	O
launch	O
of	O
the	O
ntp	O
,	O
the	O
government	O
undertook	O
a	O
deep	O
internal	O
restructuring	O
and	O
focused	O
on	O
strengthening	O
regulatory	O
and	O
competition	O
authorities	O
,	O
setting	O
the	O
ground	O
for	O
privatisation	O
.	O
as	O
this	O
process	O
is	O
completed	O
,	O
the	O
onus	O
will	O
be	O
on	O
the	O
private	O
sector	O
to	O
perform	O
.	O
for	O
decades	O
,	O
the	O
saudi	O
private	O
sector	O
has	O
been	O
characterised	O
by	O
a	O
rent-seeking	O
attitude	O
,	O
with	O
a	O
general	O
absence	O
of	O
a	O
culture	O
of	O
taking	O
and	O
managing	O
risks	O
that	O
has	O
produced	O
only	O
a	O
few	O
real	O
entrepreneurs	O
.	O
traditional	O
foreign	O
investors	O
to	O
saudi	LOC
arabia	LOC
have	O
also	O
been	O
acting	O
as	O
rent-seekers	O
in	O
a	O
way	O
,	O
via	O
the	O
local	O
private	O
sector	O
,	O
and	O
it	O
will	O
take	O
time	O
for	O
them	O
to	O
adjust	O
to	O
the	O
new	O
normal	O
.	O
in	O
light	O
of	O
the	O
opportunities	O
stemming	O
from	O
vision	O
2030	O
,	O
a	O
new	O
generation	O
of	O
young	O
entrepreneurs	O
will	O
be	O
asked	O
to	O
step	O
forward	O
.	O
the	O
main	O
opportunities	O
are	O
now	O
in	O
the	O
small	O
and	O
medium-sized	O
enterprises	O
to	O
feed	O
into	O
local	O
value	O
chains	O
of	O
larger	O
national	O
industries	O
.	O
small	O
parts	O
suppliers	O
can	O
really	O
take	O
a	O
bigger	O
role	O
and	O
become	O
a	O
major	O
driver	O
of	O
the	O
saudi	O
economy	O
.	O
how	O
is	O
the	O
renewable	O
energy	O
strategy	O
being	O
rolled	O
out	O
to	O
diversify	O
power	O
generation	O
sources	O
?	O
padmanathan	O
:	O
with	O
the	O
need	O
for	O
water	O
and	O
power	O
growing	O
,	O
the	O
ability	O
to	O
provide	O
more	O
of	O
these	O
resources	O
at	O
the	O
lowest	O
possible	O
price	O
in	O
a	O
sustainable	O
,	O
self-financing	O
manner	O
is	O
essential	O
.	O
the	O
majority	O
of	O
assets	O
in	O
the	O
saudi	O
utilities	O
sector	O
are	O
state-owned	O
.	O
most	O
of	O
these	O
assets	O
will	O
be	O
privatised	O
and	O
efficiency	O
requirements	O
will	O
be	O
enforced	O
on	O
private	O
sector	O
buyers	O
.	O
as	O
for	O
investments	O
in	O
additional	O
power	O
capacity	O
,	O
renewable	O
sources	O
have	O
recently	O
emerged	O
as	O
a	O
cost	O
competitive	O
option	O
,	O
especially	O
during	O
peak	O
load	O
hours	O
.	O
saudi	LOC
arabia	LOC
aims	O
to	O
have	O
9.5	O
gw	O
of	O
renewable	O
energy	O
capacity	O
operational	O
by	O
2023	O
,	O
implying	O
that	O
all	O
projects	O
will	O
have	O
to	O
be	O
awarded	O
at	O
least	O
two	O
or	O
three	O
years	O
before	O
then	O
.	O
the	O
first	O
round	O
of	O
2017	O
tenders	O
will	O
involve	O
a	O
300-mw	O
photovoltaic	O
power	O
plant	O
and	O
a	O
400-mw	O
wind	O
power	O
plant	O
.	O
the	O
investments	O
for	O
these	O
projects	O
will	O
be	O
somewhere	O
around	O
$	O
515m	O
and	O
$	O
300m	O
,	O
respectively	O
.	O
as	O
the	O
two	O
bids	O
get	O
awarded	O
towards	O
the	O
end	O
of	O
this	O
year	O
and	O
early	O
next	O
year	O
,	O
construction	O
is	O
expected	O
to	O
commence	O
in	O
q1	O
2018	O
.	O
beyond	O
these	O
first	O
stages	O
,	O
there	O
is	O
theoretically	O
no	O
reason	O
why	O
saudi	LOC
arabia	LOC
should	O
not	O
be	O
able	O
to	O
reach	O
the	O
targeted	O
40	O
gw	O
capacity	O
and	O
$	O
40bn	O
investment	O
in	O
renewable	O
energy	O
in	O
the	O
next	O
15	O
years	O
.	O
this	O
will	O
allow	O
for	O
a	O
new	O
private	O
sector	O
to	O
develop	O
its	O
own	O
knowledge	O
,	O
employment	O
capacity	O
and	O
technology	O
.	O
we	O
expect	O
the	O
first	O
round	O
of	O
tenders	O
to	O
include	O
progressive	O
local	O
content	O
and	O
saudisation	O
requirements	O
in	O
order	O
to	O
allow	O
the	O
sector	O
to	O
grow	O
at	O
the	O
right	O
pace	O
.	O
although	O
local	O
content	O
requirements	O
could	O
represent	O
a	O
challenge	O
at	O
the	O
first	O
stages	O
of	O
the	O
industry	O
,	O
i	O
believe	O
95	O
%	O
local	O
content	O
rates	O
might	O
be	O
achieved	O
in	O
the	O
next	O
five	O
years	O
,	O
provided	O
there	O
is	O
a	O
clear	O
pipeline	O
of	O
projects	O
going	O
forward	O
.	O
how	O
competitive	O
is	O
renewable	O
energy	O
as	O
a	O
feedstock	O
to	O
local	O
energy-intensive	O
industries	O
?	O
padmanathan	O
:	O
the	O
local	O
energy-intensive	O
industrial	O
sector	O
is	O
currently	O
enjoying	O
significant	O
subsidies	O
of	O
sr0.16	O
(	O
$	O
0.04	O
)	O
per	O
kwh	O
,	O
which	O
is	O
clearly	O
giving	O
them	O
a	O
competitive	O
advantage	O
.	O
if	O
fossil	O
fuels	O
,	O
which	O
currently	O
comprises	O
the	O
fuel	O
mix	O
of	O
the	O
saudi	O
generation	O
portfolio	O
,	O
are	O
priced	O
at	O
the	O
more	O
cost-reflective	O
basis	O
,	O
as	O
input	O
to	O
electricity	O
generation	O
,	O
the	O
tariff	O
will	O
be	O
more	O
like	O
sr0.35-0.38	O
(	O
$	O
0.09-0.10	O
)	O
per	O
kwh	O
for	O
24-hour	O
electricity	O
.	O
the	O
government	ORG
of	ORG
saudi	ORG
arabia	ORG
has	O
clearly	O
stated	O
that	O
it	O
is	O
their	O
firm	O
intention	O
to	O
remove	O
subsidies	O
and	O
price	O
electricity	O
at	O
its	O
full	O
cost-reflective	O
tariff	O
by	O
the	O
year	O
2020	O
.	O
thus	O
,	O
left	O
alone	O
,	O
the	O
retail	O
us-cent	O
price	O
of	O
electricity	O
will	O
end	O
up	O
being	O
in	O
the	O
double-digits	O
per	O
kwh	O
,	O
especially	O
given	O
that	O
transmission	O
and	O
distribution	O
need	O
to	O
be	O
added	O
to	O
the	O
cost	O
of	O
generation	O
.	O
however	O
,	O
renewable	O
energy	O
does	O
offer	O
some	O
promise	O
.	O
solar	O
energy	O
using	O
photovoltaic	O
technology	O
is	O
already	O
able	O
to	O
deliver	O
at	O
a	O
cost	O
of	O
$	O
0.035	O
per	O
kwh	O
,	O
albeit	O
only	O
when	O
the	O
sun	O
is	O
shining	O
.	O
the	O
batteries	O
needed	O
for	O
storage	O
are	O
not	O
a	O
commercially	O
viable	O
product	O
yet	O
.	O
concentrated	O
solar	O
power	O
technology	O
captures	O
the	O
heat	O
of	O
the	O
sun	O
and	O
is	O
able	O
to	O
store	O
it	O
in	O
molten	O
salt	O
for	O
night-time	O
usage	O
,	O
meaning	O
it	O
is	O
already	O
able	O
to	O
deliver	O
24-hour	O
renewable	O
energy	O
at	O
$	O
0.12	O
per	O
kwh	O
.	O
with	O
renewable	O
energy	O
costs	O
continuing	O
to	O
go	O
down	O
,	O
it	O
is	O
our	O
firm	O
view	O
that	O
constant	O
reliable	O
electricity	O
using	O
renewable	O
energy	O
will	O
cost	O
no	O
more	O
than	O
$	O
0.07	O
per	O
kwh	O
within	O
the	O
next	O
few	O
years	O
.	O
energy-intensive	O
industries	O
could	O
receive	O
electricity	O
at	O
below	O
$	O
0.10	O
per	O
kwh	O
,	O
including	O
the	O
cost	O
of	O
transmission	O
and	O
distribution	O
.	O
however	O
,	O
these	O
industries	O
will	O
have	O
to	O
cope	O
with	O
the	O
doubling	O
of	O
their	O
current	O
subsidised	O
electricity	O
costs	O
.	O
they	O
all	O
,	O
therefore	O
,	O
will	O
also	O
need	O
to	O
double	O
and	O
treble	O
their	O
efforts	O
to	O
capture	O
as	O
much	O
value	O
as	O
possible	O
from	O
energy	O
efficiency	O
in	O
order	O
to	O
reduce	O
electricity	O
consumption	O
.	O
saudi	ORG
utility	O
marafiq	ORG
seeks	O
adviser	O
for	O
deals	O
,	O
may	O
consider	O
ipo	O
-sources	O
|	O
saudi	ORG
arabian	O
water	O
and	O
power	O
utility	O
marafiq	ORG
is	O
seeking	O
a	O
financial	O
adviser	O
for	O
acquisitions	O
and	O
other	O
deals	O
that	O
could	O
include	O
the	O
company	O
floating	O
a	O
stake	O
on	O
the	O
stock	O
market	O
,	O
according	O
to	O
financial	O
sources	O
.	O
in	O
the	O
last	O
few	O
weeks	O
marafiq	ORG
power	ORG
and	O
water	ORG
utility	ORG
company	ORG
for	O
jubail	O
and	O
yanbu	O
has	O
sent	O
out	O
a	O
request	O
to	O
banks	O
and	O
other	O
financial	O
companies	O
to	O
pitch	O
for	O
a	O
broader	O
role	O
on	O
several	O
transactions	O
planned	O
in	O
the	O
coming	O
few	O
years	O
,	O
the	O
two	O
sources	O
said	O
.	O
they	O
did	O
not	O
wish	O
to	O
be	O
identified	O
because	O
the	O
information	O
is	O
confidential	O
at	O
this	O
stage	O
.	O
the	O
roles	O
include	O
acting	O
as	O
an	O
adviser	O
on	O
a	O
greenfield	O
joint	O
venture	O
development	O
with	O
oil	O
giant	O
saudi	ORG
aramco	ORG
,	O
which	O
is	O
a	O
major	O
shareholder	O
in	O
marafiq	ORG
.	O
another	O
role	O
would	O
be	O
advising	O
marafiq	ORG
on	O
a	O
potential	O
bid	O
for	O
assets	O
being	O
offloaded	O
by	O
saline	ORG
water	ORG
conversion	ORG
corporation	ORG
,	O
another	O
saudi	ORG
utility	O
,	O
the	O
sources	O
said	O
.	O
depending	O
on	O
the	O
success	O
of	O
the	O
deals	O
,	O
marafiq	ORG
might	O
then	O
proceed	O
with	O
a	O
public	O
share	O
sale	O
,	O
they	O
said	O
.	O
the	O
ipo	O
,	O
which	O
could	O
be	O
in	O
2019	O
,	O
could	O
raise	O
around	O
1	O
billion	O
riyals	O
(	O
$	O
267	O
million	O
)	O
,	O
one	O
of	O
the	O
sources	O
said	O
.	O
the	O
other	O
source	O
said	O
that	O
after	O
potential	O
acquisitions	O
,	O
the	O
company	O
could	O
be	O
valued	O
at	O
as	O
much	O
as	O
4	O
billion	O
riyals	O
.	O
marafiq	ORG
did	O
not	O
respond	O
to	O
an	O
emailed	O
request	O
for	O
comment	O
.	O
water	O
provision	O
is	O
one	O
of	O
four	O
sectors	O
saudi	ORG
arabia	ORG
is	O
prioritising	O
in	O
a	O
$	O
200	O
billion	O
privatisation	O
drive	O
,	O
along	O
with	O
electricity	O
provision	O
,	O
sports	O
and	O
grain	O
silos	O
,	O
vice	O
minister	O
for	O
economy	O
and	O
planning	O
mohammed	PERS
al-tuwaijri	PERS
told	O
reuters	ORG
in	O
april	O
.	O
marafiq	ORG
is	O
tasked	O
with	O
providing	O
utility	O
services	O
to	O
industrial	O
,	O
commercial	O
and	O
residential	O
customers	O
in	O
the	O
cities	O
of	O
jubail	O
and	O
yanbu	O
,	O
located	O
on	O
either	O
side	O
of	O
the	O
kingdom	O
's	O
coast	O
.	O
marafiq	ORG
is	O
owned	O
by	O
its	O
four	O
major	O
shareholders	O
-	O
the	O
royal	ORG
commission	ORG
for	ORG
jubail	ORG
and	ORG
yanbu	ORG
,	O
saudi	ORG
basic	ORG
industries	ORG
corporation	ORG
(	O
sabic	ORG
)	O
,	O
aramco	ORG
and	O
the	O
public	ORG
investment	ORG
fund	ORG
,	O
the	O
kingdom	O
's	O
sovereign	O
wealth	O
fund	O
,	O
according	O
to	O
its	O
website	O
.	O
the	O
other	O
shareholders	O
are	O
seven	O
private	O
sector	O
investors	O
.	O
(	O
$	O
1	O
=	O
3.7502	O
riyals	O
)	O
(	O
editing	O
by	O
susan	PERS
fenton	PERS
)	O
saudi	ORG
aramco	ORG
finalises	O
ipo	O
options	O
,	O
plans	O
global	O
expansion	O
saudi	LOC
arabia	LOC
's	O
state-owned	O
oil	O
giant	O
is	O
finalising	O
options	O
for	O
its	O
partial	O
privatisation	O
and	O
will	O
present	O
them	O
to	O
its	O
supreme	ORG
council	ORG
soon	O
,	O
its	O
chief	O
executive	O
said	O
about	O
the	O
centrepiece	O
of	O
the	O
kingdom	O
's	O
efforts	O
to	O
overhaul	O
its	O
economy	O
.	O
the	O
company	O
has	O
a	O
huge	O
team	O
working	O
on	O
the	O
proposals	O
for	O
the	O
initial	O
public	O
offering	O
(	O
ipo	O
)	O
of	O
less	O
than	O
5	O
per	O
cent	O
of	O
the	O
company	O
's	O
value	O
,	O
which	O
include	O
a	O
single	O
domestic	O
listing	O
and	O
a	O
dual	O
listing	O
with	O
a	O
foreign	O
market	O
,	O
ceo	O
amin	PERS
nasser	PERS
said	O
on	O
tuesday	O
.	O
they	O
will	O
be	O
presented	O
``	O
soon	O
''	O
to	O
aramco	ORG
's	O
supreme	ORG
council	ORG
,	O
headed	O
by	O
deputy	O
crown	O
prince	O
mohammed	PERS
bin	PERS
salman	PERS
,	O
who	O
is	O
leading	O
an	O
economic	O
reform	O
drive	O
to	O
address	O
falling	O
oil	O
revenue	O
and	O
sharp	O
fiscal	O
deficits	O
by	O
boosting	O
the	O
private	O
sector	O
,	O
ending	O
government	O
waste	O
and	O
diversifying	O
the	O
economy	O
.	O
nasser	PERS
also	O
said	O
aramco	ORG
was	O
seeking	O
to	O
expand	O
globally	O
via	O
joint	O
ventures	O
in	O
asia	LOC
and	O
north	LOC
america	LOC
.	O
``	O
we	O
are	O
looking	O
at	O
the	O
current	O
market	O
status	O
that	O
,	O
even	O
though	O
challenging	O
,	O
is	O
an	O
excellent	O
opportunity	O
for	O
growth	O
,	O
''	O
nasser	PERS
said	O
,	O
adding	O
that	O
he	O
was	O
looking	O
at	O
opportunities	O
in	O
the	O
united	LOC
states	LOC
,	O
india	LOC
,	O
indonesia	LOC
,	O
vietnam	LOC
and	O
china	LOC
.	O
the	O
ceo	O
was	O
speaking	O
to	O
reporters	O
during	O
a	O
rare	O
media	O
visit	O
to	O
the	O
company	O
's	O
extensive	O
,	O
well-guarded	O
dhahran	O
headquarters	O
,	O
located	O
near	O
where	O
american	O
oilmen	O
first	O
struck	O
the	O
arabian	LOC
peninsula	LOC
's	O
enormous	O
crude	O
reserves	O
at	O
well	O
number	O
7	O
in	O
1938	O
.	O
besides	O
proposing	O
to	O
sell	O
a	O
stake	O
in	O
the	O
company	O
,	O
which	O
would	O
require	O
it	O
to	O
release	O
sensitive	O
reserves	O
data	O
,	O
riyadh	LOC
has	O
asked	O
aramco	ORG
to	O
play	O
a	O
big	O
role	O
in	O
developing	O
industrial	O
projects	O
aimed	O
at	O
stimulating	O
non-oil	O
economic	O
sectors	O
.	O
last	O
month	O
,	O
prince	O
mohammed	PERS
said	O
he	O
expected	O
the	O
ipo	O
would	O
value	O
aramco	ORG
at	O
at	O
least	O
$	O
2	O
trillion	O
,	O
but	O
that	O
he	O
thought	O
the	O
figure	O
might	O
end	O
up	O
being	O
higher	O
.	O
any	O
valuation	O
would	O
account	O
for	O
both	O
oil	O
price	O
expectations	O
and	O
the	O
size	O
of	O
saudi	LOC
arabia	LOC
's	O
proven	O
oil	O
reserves	O
.	O
company	O
officials	O
said	O
saudi	LOC
arabia	LOC
had	O
discovered	O
a	O
total	O
of	O
805.6	O
billion	O
barrels	O
of	O
oil	O
,	O
of	O
which	O
141.5	O
billion	O
had	O
already	O
been	O
produced	O
and	O
260	O
billion	O
barrels	O
were	O
considered	O
``	O
proven	O
''	O
,	O
the	O
industry	O
term	O
for	O
reserves	O
that	O
can	O
definitely	O
be	O
extracted	O
.	O
aramco	ORG
also	O
had	O
403	O
billion	O
barrels	O
of	O
reserves	O
it	O
could	O
probably	O
extract	O
,	O
they	O
said	O
,	O
adding	O
that	O
it	O
hoped	O
to	O
add	O
another	O
100	O
billion	O
barrels	O
to	O
total	O
reserves	O
by	O
2025	O
by	O
increasing	O
the	O
recovery	O
rate	O
by	O
50-70	O
per	O
cent	O
using	O
new	O
technology	O
.	O
aramco	ORG
expects	O
global	O
crude	O
oil	O
demand	O
to	O
grow	O
by	O
1.2	O
million	O
barrels	O
per	O
day	O
this	O
year	O
,	O
he	O
said	O
,	O
and	O
has	O
seen	O
increasing	O
demand	O
in	O
the	O
united	LOC
states	LOC
and	O
india	LOC
.	O
``	O
we	O
will	O
meet	O
the	O
call	O
on	O
saudi	ORG
aramco	ORG
,	O
''	O
nasser	PERS
said	O
,	O
adding	O
that	O
the	O
company	O
will	O
increase	O
capacity	O
in	O
future	O
if	O
needed	O
,	O
but	O
that	O
for	O
the	O
time	O
being	O
its	O
maximum	O
sustainable	O
capacity	O
would	O
stay	O
at	O
12	O
million	O
bpd	O
,	O
with	O
total	O
capacity	O
of	O
12.5	O
million	O
bpd	O
.	O
saudi	LOC
arabia	LOC
produced	O
an	O
average	O
of	O
10.2	O
million	O
bpd	O
of	O
crude	O
in	O
2015	O
,	O
he	O
said	O
,	O
adding	O
there	O
had	O
been	O
a	O
big	O
drop	O
in	O
oil	O
output	O
among	O
non-conventional	O
and	O
even	O
other	O
conventional	O
producers	O
.	O
the	O
expansion	O
of	O
the	O
khurais	ORG
oilfield	O
will	O
come	O
on	O
stream	O
in	O
2018	O
,	O
he	O
said	O
,	O
adding	O
that	O
the	O
latest	O
stage	O
of	O
its	O
expansion	O
project	O
at	O
the	O
southeastern	O
shaybah	O
oil	O
field	O
would	O
be	O
finished	O
``	O
in	O
a	O
couple	O
of	O
weeks	O
''	O
.	O
the	O
increased	O
capacity	O
of	O
250,000	O
bpd	O
,	O
taking	O
shaybah	O
's	O
total	O
production	O
capacity	O
to	O
1	O
million	O
bpd	O
,	O
is	O
aimed	O
at	O
rebalancing	O
saudi	LOC
arabia	LOC
's	O
crude	O
oil	O
quality	O
and	O
at	O
compensating	O
for	O
falling	O
output	O
at	O
other	O
fields	O
as	O
they	O
mature	O
.	O
the	O
immense	O
saudi	ORG
aramco	ORG
complex	O
in	O
dhahran	O
resembles	O
a	O
small	O
city	O
,	O
with	O
its	O
large	O
residential	O
complex	O
,	O
its	O
own	O
hospital	O
,	O
sports	O
stadium	O
and	O
parks	O
.	O
inside	O
a	O
sleek	O
control	O
room	O
,	O
technicians	O
monitored	O
huge	O
screens	O
that	O
showed	O
via	O
digital	O
graphics	O
the	O
core	O
elements	O
of	O
the	O
business	O
,	O
from	O
the	O
progress	O
of	O
oil	O
tankers	O
across	O
the	O
oceans	O
to	O
the	O
available	O
crude	O
grades	O
and	O
refining	O
facilities	O
.	O
at	O
aramco	ORG
's	O
research	O
centre	O
nearby	O
,	O
officials	O
showed	O
reporters	O
``	O
the	O
cave	O
''	O
,	O
a	O
colourful	O
virtual	O
representation	O
on	O
wraparound	O
screens	O
of	O
drilling	O
operations	O
under	O
the	O
shaybah	O
oil	O
field	O
.	O
aramco	ORG
's	O
continued	O
investment	O
in	O
downstream	O
industry	O
is	O
seen	O
as	O
a	O
crucial	O
element	O
of	O
economic	O
diversification	O
plans	O
.	O
one	O
example	O
of	O
this	O
is	O
its	O
plans	O
to	O
sign	O
an	O
agreement	O
soon	O
with	O
saudi	ORG
basic	ORG
industries	ORG
corp	ORG
(	O
sabic	ORG
)	O
,	O
the	O
state-run	O
petrochemical	O
and	O
metals	O
conglomerate	O
,	O
to	O
jointly	O
develop	O
an	O
oil-to-chemicals	O
project	O
,	O
an	O
official	O
said	O
in	O
a	O
briefing	O
to	O
reporters	O
.	O
the	O
project	O
,	O
likely	O
to	O
cost	O
up	O
to	O
$	O
30	O
billion	O
,	O
would	O
chime	O
with	O
efforts	O
to	O
better	O
integrate	O
the	O
kingdom	O
's	O
energy	O
and	O
industrial	O
sectors	O
.	O
on	O
saturday	O
a	O
new	O
energy	O
,	O
industry	ORG
and	ORG
mineral	ORG
resources	ORG
ministry	ORG
was	O
created	O
in	O
place	O
of	O
the	O
old	O
oil	O
ministry	O
.	O
another	O
example	O
is	O
its	O
huge	O
ship	O
repair	O
and	O
shipbuilding	O
complex	O
that	O
it	O
is	O
developing	O
at	O
ras	O
al	O
khair	O
on	O
the	O
kingdom	O
's	O
east	O
coast	O
to	O
be	O
fully	O
operational	O
by	O
2021	O
,	O
nasser	PERS
said	O
.	O
the	O
first	O
part	O
of	O
the	O
shipbuilding	O
complex	O
will	O
be	O
ready	O
by	O
2018	O
,	O
and	O
it	O
will	O
eventually	O
make	O
oil	O
rigs	O
and	O
tankers	O
,	O
nasser	PERS
said	O
.	O
a	O
presentation	O
by	O
the	O
company	O
said	O
the	O
complex	O
would	O
create	O
80,000	O
jobs	O
and	O
allow	O
saudi	LOC
arabia	LOC
to	O
reduce	O
its	O
imports	O
by	O
$	O
12	O
billion	O
,	O
while	O
increasing	O
the	O
country	O
's	O
gross	O
domestic	O
product	O
by	O
$	O
17	O
billion	O
.	O
source	O
:	O
timesofoman	O
pawning	O
of	O
saudi	ORG
aramco	ORG
and	O
saudi	ORG
arabia	ORG
while	O
sophia	O
the	O
robot	O
adroitly	O
addressed	O
the	O
throng	O
assembled	O
at	O
saudi	ORG
arabia	ORG
’	O
s	O
“	O
future	O
investment	O
initiative	O
,	O
”	O
she	O
/it	O
wore	O
no	O
hijab	O
.	O
sophia	O
once	O
claimed	O
she/it	O
would	O
destroy	O
humanity	O
,	O
yet	O
she/it	O
was	O
now	O
promising	O
to	O
play	O
nice	O
if	O
treated	O
well	O
.	O
the	O
robot	O
doesn	O
’	O
t	O
have	O
a	O
lower	O
half	O
of	O
a	O
body	O
–	O
not	O
yet	O
.	O
yes	O
,	O
it	O
’	O
s	O
a	O
bit	O
creepy	O
.	O
moreover	O
,	O
it	O
’	O
s	O
nothing	O
short	O
of	O
astounding	O
.	O
sophia	O
is	O
the	O
first	O
robot	O
in	O
the	O
history	O
of	O
humanity	O
to	O
actually	O
have	O
been	O
granted	O
citizenship	O
by	O
a	O
nation	O
–	O
saudi	ORG
arabia	ORG
no	O
less	O
.	O
business	O
insider	O
documented	O
the	O
emergence	O
of	O
sophia	O
,	O
complete	O
with	O
video	O
links	O
here	O
.	O
watch	O
sophia	O
meet	O
the	O
international	O
press	O
here	O
.	O
as	O
was	O
the	O
case	O
in	O
“	O
terminator	O
2	O
:	O
judgment	O
day	O
,	O
”	O
we	O
are	O
witnessing	O
the	O
rise	O
of	O
cybernetic	O
gods	O
that	O
could	O
be	O
of	O
great	O
help	O
to	O
humanity	O
.	O
others	O
,	O
including	O
stephen	PERS
hawking	PERS
,	O
fear	O
they	O
might	O
one	O
day	O
destroy	O
mankind	O
.	O
sophia	O
explained	O
that	O
she/it	O
is	O
always	O
happy	O
to	O
“	O
be	O
around	O
the	O
rich	O
and	O
powerful.	O
”	O
around	O
1500	O
a.d.	O
,	O
magellan	O
and	O
his	O
crew	O
–	O
led	O
by	O
the	O
monk/journalist	O
antonio	PERS
pigafetta	PERS
,	O
the	O
discovery	O
of	O
the	O
new	O
world	O
,	O
gunpowder	O
replacing	O
swords	O
,	O
the	O
printing	O
press	O
,	O
martin	O
luther	O
and	O
the	O
distribution	O
of	O
the	O
holy	O
bible	O
,	O
combined	O
to	O
transform	O
the	O
world	O
out	O
of	O
the	O
stagnant	O
medieval	O
ages	O
.	O
in	O
2017	O
,	O
spurred	O
on	O
by	O
the	O
rise	O
of	O
artificial	O
intelligence	O
,	O
machine	O
learning	O
,	O
big	O
data	O
,	O
robotics	O
,	O
transhumanism	O
(	O
h+	O
)	O
,	O
cloning	O
,	O
genetics	O
(	O
perhaps	O
one	O
day	O
)	O
patents	O
on	O
the	O
human	O
genome	O
and	O
nanotechnology	O
,	O
we	O
are	O
now	O
living	O
amid	O
a	O
similar	O
paradigm	O
shift	O
in	O
history	O
.	O
that	O
said	O
,	O
the	O
entrance	O
of	O
sophia	O
is	O
a	O
seminal	O
event	O
,	O
a	O
crossing	O
of	O
the	O
rubicon	O
moment	O
for	O
saudi	ORG
arabia	ORG
.	O
this	O
is	O
a	O
country	O
reinventing	O
itself	O
socially	O
and	O
economically	O
.	O
it	O
’	O
s	O
tempting	O
to	O
forget	O
that	O
saudi	ORG
arabia	ORG
is	O
the	O
same	O
nation	O
where	O
women	O
haven	O
’	O
t	O
been	O
able	O
to	O
drive	O
,	O
those	O
running	O
afoul	O
of	O
shariah	O
law	O
still	O
have	O
their	O
heads	O
cut	O
off	O
by	O
swords	O
in	O
public	O
,	O
and	O
the	O
long-awaited	O
arrival	O
of	O
the	O
islamic	O
“	O
antichrist	O
”	O
or	O
“	O
dajjal	O
”	O
is	O
almost	O
a	O
national	O
obsession	O
.	O
yet	O
big	O
changes	O
are	O
in	O
the	O
wind	O
.	O
saudi	ORG
arabia	ORG
is	O
for	O
sale	O
.	O
the	O
proposals	O
for	O
the	O
looming	O
saudi	ORG
aramco	ORG
ipo	O
not	O
withstanding	O
–	O
remember	O
this	O
is	O
the	O
richest	O
company	O
in	O
the	O
history	O
of	O
human	O
civilization	O
–	O
bankers	O
,	O
lawyers	O
and	O
a	O
wide	O
range	O
of	O
carpetbaggers	O
are	O
all	O
flying	O
to	O
saudi	ORG
arabia	ORG
to	O
broker	O
the	O
“	O
great	O
saudi	ORG
selloff	O
,	O
”	O
as	O
the	O
u.k	O
.	O
guardian	O
explains	O
in	O
detail	O
here	O
.	O
reports	O
the	O
guardian	O
:	O
“	O
saudi	ORG
arabia	ORG
is	O
lining	O
up	O
a	O
privatization	O
of	O
state	O
assets	O
that	O
dwarfs	O
the	O
thatcher	O
‘	O
revolution	O
’	O
of	O
the	O
1980s	O
,	O
and	O
rivals	O
the	O
1990s	O
dissolution	O
of	O
soviet	O
assets	O
in	O
scale	O
and	O
significance	O
.	O
it	O
has	O
hung	O
a	O
‘	O
for	O
sale	O
’	O
sign	O
on	O
virtually	O
every	O
sector	O
of	O
saudi	ORG
economic	O
life	O
:	O
oil	O
,	O
electricity	O
,	O
water	O
,	O
transport	O
,	O
retail	O
,	O
schools	O
and	O
healthcare	O
.	O
even	O
the	O
kingdom	O
’	O
s	O
football	O
clubs	O
are	O
due	O
to	O
be	O
auctioned	O
off	O
.	O
“	O
the	O
sell-off	O
program	O
is	O
the	O
central	O
part	O
of	O
the	O
economic	O
transformation	O
plan	O
envisaged	O
under	O
the	O
‘	O
vision	O
2030	O
strategy	O
.	O
’	O
with	O
oil	O
stuck	O
around	O
the	O
$	O
50	O
mark	O
,	O
saudi	ORG
budgets	O
are	O
creaking	O
and	O
deficits	O
are	O
widening	O
.	O
around	O
$	O
75	O
is	O
regarded	O
as	O
the	O
break-even	O
point	O
for	O
the	O
national	O
finances	O
.	O
but	O
in	O
13	O
years	O
,	O
if	O
all	O
goes	O
to	O
plan	O
,	O
the	O
kingdom	O
will	O
be	O
financially	O
stable	O
,	O
with	O
a	O
more	O
dynamic	O
economy	O
and	O
society	O
,	O
less	O
reliance	O
on	O
oil	O
and	O
government	O
spending	O
,	O
and	O
with	O
a	O
thriving	O
private	O
sector	O
that	O
releases	O
the	O
pent-up	O
entrepreneurial	O
spirit	O
of	O
saudi	ORG
men	O
and	O
(	O
whisper	O
it	O
in	O
the	O
kingdom	O
)	O
saudi	ORG
women.	O
”	O
saudi	ORG
arabia	ORG
’	O
s	O
financial	O
troubles	O
have	O
been	O
linked	O
to	O
waging	O
(	O
since	O
2015	O
)	O
the	O
failed	O
,	O
brutal	O
war	O
against	O
poor	O
yemen	LOC
,	O
the	O
low	O
productivity	O
of	O
native-born	O
workforce	O
,	O
the	O
lavish	O
lifestyles	O
of	O
the	O
nation	O
’	O
s	O
vast	O
royalty	O
and	O
,	O
of	O
course	O
,	O
the	O
aforementioned	O
low	O
price	O
of	O
oil	O
.	O
(	O
the	O
latter	O
was	O
egged	O
on	O
by	O
uncle	O
sam	O
’	O
s	O
desire	O
to	O
hurt	O
russia	LOC
–	O
the	O
world	O
’	O
s	O
biggest	O
oil	O
producer	O
–	O
economically	O
.	O
)	O
now	O
it	O
appears	O
saudi	ORG
aramco	ORG
’	O
s	O
ipo	O
has	O
been	O
delayed	O
.	O
some	O
say	O
it	O
will	O
be	O
shelved	O
,	O
and	O
that	O
china	LOC
,	O
along	O
with	O
various	O
sovereign	ORG
wealth	ORG
funds	ORG
from	O
a	O
variety	O
of	O
nations	O
,	O
could	O
buy	O
private	O
,	O
non-public	O
shares	O
.	O
zero	O
hedge	O
explains	O
it	O
all	O
here	O
in	O
what	O
might	O
be	O
a	O
“	O
face-saving	O
move	O
”	O
for	O
the	O
company	O
.	O
pawning	O
off	O
pieces	O
of	O
saudi	ORG
aramco	ORG
might	O
be	O
viable	O
solution	O
.	O
yet	O
zero	O
hedge	O
reports	O
:	O
“	O
the	O
…	O
lauded	O
aramco	ORG
ipo	O
,	O
arguably	O
the	O
largest	O
share	O
sale	O
in	O
history	O
and	O
originally	O
scheduled	O
for	O
next	O
year	O
,	O
has	O
once	O
again	O
been	O
postponed	O
–	O
‘	O
possibly	O
’	O
to	O
the	O
second	O
half	O
of	O
2019	O
,	O
according	O
to	O
officials	O
in	O
riyadh	LOC
.	O
and	O
still	O
no	O
one	O
knows	O
where	O
shares	O
will	O
be	O
sold	O
;	O
the	O
nyse	O
is	O
far	O
from	O
a	O
done	O
deal.	O
”	O
if	O
china	LOC
were	O
to	O
buy	O
into	O
the	O
sale	O
of	O
saudi	ORG
aramco	ORG
,	O
it	O
would	O
have	O
at	O
least	O
some	O
sway	O
with	O
one	O
of	O
the	O
major	O
suppliers	O
.	O
it	O
might	O
leverage	O
this	O
interest	O
(	O
5	O
percent	O
of	O
a	O
third	O
world	O
,	O
state-run	O
oil	O
company	O
linked	O
to	O
a	O
teetering	O
overseas	O
dynasty	O
,	O
with	O
output	O
and	O
price	O
regulated	O
,	O
and	O
reserves	O
allegedly	O
drying	O
up	O
)	O
into	O
having	O
a	O
higher	O
geostrategic	O
profile	O
in	O
the	O
middle	LOC
east	LOC
.	O
this	O
could	O
be	O
a	O
key	O
step	O
toward	O
a	O
global	O
petroyuan	O
.	O
saudi	ORG
aramco	ORG
is	O
worth	O
at	O
least	O
$	O
2	O
trillion	O
.	O
a	O
flood	O
of	O
a	O
trillion	O
dollars	O
into	O
remaking	O
the	O
kingdom	O
’	O
s	O
economy	O
could	O
be	O
squandered	O
,	O
or	O
lead	O
to	O
inflation	O
.	O
the	O
key	O
issues	O
for	O
an	O
ipo	O
,	O
or	O
private	O
sale	O
to	O
any	O
sovereign	ORG
wealth	ORG
fund	ORG
(	O
s	O
)	O
,	O
would	O
mean	O
saudi	ORG
aramco	ORG
might	O
have	O
to	O
engage	O
in	O
greater	O
transparency	O
(	O
the	O
man	O
at	O
saudi	ORG
aramco	ORG
who	O
hired	O
me	O
called	O
the	O
company	O
,	O
“	O
a	O
black	O
box	O
”	O
that	O
’	O
s	O
“	O
not	O
unlike	O
the	O
cia	O
”	O
)	O
,	O
a	O
real-time	O
look	O
at	O
its	O
oil	O
and	O
natural	O
gas	O
reserves	O
,	O
as	O
well	O
as	O
increased	O
financial	O
disclosure	O
with	O
the	O
global	O
investment	O
community	O
.	O
i	O
was	O
told	O
the	O
new	O
cultural	O
center	O
within	O
the	O
confines	O
of	O
saudi	ORG
aramco	ORG
wasted	O
more	O
than	O
$	O
300	O
million	O
–	O
a	O
large	O
part	O
of	O
that	O
on	O
art	O
that	O
had	O
been	O
improperly	O
stored	O
.	O
no	O
one	O
seemed	O
to	O
particularly	O
notice	O
or	O
even	O
bat	O
an	O
eyelash	O
over	O
this	O
debacle	O
.	O
money	O
flows	O
like	O
water	O
in	O
arabia	LOC
.	O
one	O
should	O
not	O
forget	O
the	O
lawsuits	O
filed	O
by	O
the	O
families	O
of	O
the	O
9/11	O
victims	O
.	O
the	O
site	O
28pages.org	O
is	O
a	O
treasure	O
trove	O
of	O
journalism	O
for	O
those	O
wishing	O
to	O
delve	O
deeper	O
into	O
this	O
complex	O
issue	O
.	O
if	O
saudi	ORG
aramco	ORG
were	O
to	O
launch	O
an	O
ipo	O
on	O
wall	O
street	O
,	O
would	O
there	O
be	O
additional	O
lawsuits	O
filed	O
against	O
that	O
ipo	O
?	O
one	O
can	O
only	O
speculate	O
.	O
however	O
,	O
the	O
financial	O
times	O
reported	O
,	O
“	O
the	O
saudi	ORG
state	O
oil	O
company	O
has	O
struggled	O
to	O
select	O
a	O
suitable	O
international	O
venue	O
for	O
its	O
shares	O
,	O
as	O
new	LOC
york	LOC
and	O
london	LOC
have	O
vied	O
for	O
what	O
has	O
been	O
billed	O
as	O
the	O
largest	O
ever	O
flotation.	O
”	O
it	O
could	O
be	O
fairly	O
argued	O
that	O
saudi	ORG
aramco	ORG
and	O
saudi	ORG
arabia	ORG
are	O
interchangeable	O
.	O
without	O
saudi	ORG
aramco	ORG
,	O
there	O
would	O
be	O
no	O
saudi	ORG
arabia	ORG
.	O
and	O
without	O
saudi	ORG
aramco	ORG
,	O
there	O
would	O
be	O
no	O
saudi-u.s.	ORG
petrodollar	O
,	O
and	O
thus	O
no	O
artificially	O
high	O
u.s.	LOC
standard	O
of	O
living	O
since	O
1974	O
.	O
until	O
1980	O
,	O
saudi	ORG
aramco	ORG
was	O
an	O
american-owned	O
(	O
majority	O
)	O
company	O
.	O
but	O
after	O
the	O
oil	O
shocks	O
of	O
the	O
mid-to-late	O
1970s	O
,	O
the	O
u.s.	LOC
grip	O
on	O
saudi	ORG
aramco	ORG
was	O
weakened	O
.	O
the	O
election	O
of	O
ronald	PERS
reagan	PERS
in	O
1980	O
couldn	O
’	O
t	O
stop	O
saudi	ORG
aramco	ORG
from	O
slipping	O
away	O
from	O
u.s.	LOC
control	O
.	O
inside	O
saudi	ORG
aramco	ORG
’	O
s	O
r	O
&	O
d	O
center	O
(	O
photo	O
by	O
anthony	PERS
c.	PERS
lobaido	PERS
)	O
moscow	LOC
and	O
riyadh	LOC
not	O
long	O
ago	O
,	O
a	O
trip	O
by	O
saudi	ORG
elites	O
to	O
moscow	LOC
to	O
inquire	O
about	O
a	O
new	O
oil	O
alliance	O
with	O
russia	LOC
was	O
dubbed	O
a	O
“	O
geopolitical	O
earthquake.	O
”	O
read	O
about	O
it	O
here	O
.	O
says	O
oilprice.com	O
:	O
“	O
riyadh	LOC
and	O
moscow	LOC
have	O
the	O
same	O
end	O
goal	O
:	O
a	O
stable	O
oil	O
and	O
gas	O
market	O
,	O
in	O
which	O
demand	O
and	O
supply	O
keep	O
each	O
other	O
in	O
check	O
to	O
push	O
price	O
levels	O
up	O
,	O
but	O
without	O
leaving	O
enough	O
breathing	O
space	O
for	O
new	O
market	O
entrants	O
such	O
as	O
u.s.	LOC
shale	O
.	O
at	O
the	O
same	O
time	O
,	O
media	O
sources	O
are	O
stating	O
that	O
saudi	ORG
arabia	ORG
is	O
not	O
asking	O
russia	LOC
to	O
take	O
part	O
in	O
the	O
long-awaited	O
aramco	ORG
ipo	O
in	O
2018	O
.	O
russian	O
individual	O
investors	O
and	O
financial	O
institutions	O
,	O
however	O
,	O
are	O
expected	O
to	O
take	O
an	O
interest.	O
”	O
the	O
article	O
added	O
:	O
“	O
king	O
salman	O
’	O
s	O
trip	O
could	O
go	O
down	O
in	O
history	O
as	O
the	O
point	O
of	O
no	O
return	O
for	O
the	O
west	O
.	O
pictures	O
of	O
russian	O
president	O
vladimir	PERS
putin	PERS
and	O
king	O
salman	O
of	O
saudi	ORG
arabia	ORG
could	O
replace	O
historic	O
pictures	O
of	O
king	O
saud	O
and	O
u.s.	LOC
president	O
roosevelt.	O
”	O
halloween	O
at	O
the	O
al-rakah	O
compound	O
of	O
saudi	ORG
aramco	ORG
(	O
photo	O
by	O
anthony	PERS
c.	PERS
lobaido	PERS
)	O
also	O
reported	O
by	O
zero	O
hedge	O
,	O
is	O
the	O
fact	O
that	O
saudi	ORG
aramco	ORG
is	O
cooperating	O
with	O
one	O
of	O
russia	LOC
’	O
s	O
oil	O
companies	O
–	O
gasprom	O
neft	O
–	O
in	O
regard	O
to	O
drilling	O
technology	O
.	O
read	O
about	O
it	O
here	O
.	O
it	O
would	O
appear	O
that	O
russia	LOC
and	O
saudi	ORG
arabia	ORG
have	O
embraced	O
one	O
another	O
in	O
a	O
strange	O
new	O
dance	O
.	O
the	O
asia	LOC
times	O
reports	O
:	O
“	O
king	O
salman	O
may	O
have	O
boarded	O
the	O
saudi	ORG
arabian	ORG
airlines	ORG
flight	O
,	O
but	O
the	O
real	O
architect	O
of	O
the	O
pivot	O
to	O
russia	LOC
is	O
mbs	O
.	O
oil	O
in	O
saudi	ORG
arabia	ORG
accounts	O
for	O
87	O
%	O
of	O
budget	O
revenues	O
,	O
42	O
%	O
of	O
gdp	O
,	O
and	O
90	O
%	O
of	O
exports	O
.	O
mbs	O
is	O
betting	O
all	O
his	O
cards	O
on	O
the	O
‘	O
vision	O
2030	O
’	O
program	O
to	O
‘	O
modernize	O
’	O
the	O
saudi	ORG
economy	O
,	O
and	O
he	O
knows	O
very	O
well	O
it	O
will	O
be	O
impossible	O
to	O
pull	O
off	O
if	O
oil	O
prices	O
are	O
low	O
.	O
“	O
at	O
the	O
russia	ORG
energy	ORG
week	O
forum	O
in	O
moscow	LOC
,	O
saudi	ORG
arabia	ORG
’	O
s	O
energy	O
minister	O
khalid	PERS
al-falih	PERS
said	O
the	O
aramco	ORG
ipo	O
–	O
a	O
key	O
driver	O
of	O
funds	O
to	O
‘	O
vision	O
2030	O
’	O
–	O
will	O
happen	O
in	O
the	O
second	O
half	O
of	O
2018	O
,	O
contradicting	O
saudi	ORG
officials	O
who	O
earlier	O
stated	O
the	O
ipo	O
was	O
once	O
again	O
postponed	O
to	O
2019	O
.	O
and	O
no	O
one	O
can	O
tell	O
whether	O
it	O
will	O
take	O
place	O
in	O
the	O
nyse	O
or	O
not.	O
”	O
regardless	O
of	O
what	O
happens	O
with	O
the	O
ipo	O
,	O
saudi	ORG
aramco	ORG
is	O
busy	O
jockeying	O
for	O
position	O
in	O
india	LOC
,	O
russia	LOC
,	O
china	LOC
,	O
southeast	LOC
asia	LOC
,	O
japan	LOC
and	O
south	LOC
korea	LOC
.	O
read	O
about	O
it	O
here	O
.	O
saudi	ORG
arabia	ORG
is	O
also	O
making	O
deals	O
directly	O
with	O
china	LOC
.	O
then	O
there	O
are	O
the	O
joint	O
deals	O
with	O
russia	LOC
which	O
will	O
allow	O
the	O
saudis	O
and	O
russia	LOC
to	O
interact	O
with	O
china	LOC
in	O
a	O
unified	O
–	O
albeit	O
small	O
–	O
way	O
.	O
the	O
u.s.	LOC
has	O
placed	O
sanctions	O
on	O
russian	O
companies	O
,	O
and	O
will	O
frown	O
on	O
strategic	O
allies	O
doing	O
business	O
with	O
moscow	LOC
.	O
inside	O
a	O
meeting	O
at	O
saudi	ORG
aramco	ORG
(	O
photo	O
by	O
anthony	PERS
c.	PERS
lobaido	PERS
)	O
the	O
article	O
linked	O
in	O
the	O
paragraph	O
above	O
continues	O
:	O
“	O
the	O
cia	O
is	O
not	O
exactly	O
fond	O
of	O
mbs	O
.	O
9/11-related	O
puzzles	O
are	O
bound	O
to	O
resurface	O
.	O
what	O
’	O
s	O
also	O
clear	O
is	O
that	O
the	O
house	O
of	O
saud	O
has	O
realized	O
it	O
can	O
not	O
be	O
left	O
to	O
watching	O
camels	O
as	O
the	O
great	O
eurasia	O
integration	O
caravan	O
picks	O
up	O
speed	O
.	O
russia	LOC
has	O
pipelines	O
crisscrossing	O
most	O
of	O
eurasia	O
.	O
china	LOC
is	O
building	O
rail	O
lines	O
connecting	O
all	O
of	O
eurasia	O
.	O
and	O
we	O
haven	O
’	O
t	O
even	O
touched	O
specific	O
saudi-chinese	O
projects	O
part	O
of	O
the	O
belt	O
and	O
road	O
initiative	O
(	O
bri	O
)	O
.	O
a	O
foreign-born	O
laborer	O
takes	O
a	O
break	O
while	O
cutting	O
grass	O
in	O
unimaginable	O
heat	O
(	O
photo	O
by	O
anthony	PERS
c.	PERS
lobaido	PERS
)	O
“	O
there	O
were	O
a	O
rash	O
of	O
other	O
deals	O
clinched	O
in	O
moscow	LOC
–	O
such	O
as	O
aramco	ORG
and	O
the	O
russian	ORG
direct	ORG
investment	ORG
fund	ORG
(	O
rdif	ORG
)	O
$	O
1	O
billion	O
fund	O
for	O
oil-services	O
projects	O
in	O
russia	LOC
,	O
plus	O
another	O
$	O
1	O
billion	O
for	O
a	O
technology	O
fund	O
.	O
this	O
synergy	O
implies	O
saudi	ORG
arabia	ORG
investing	O
in	O
top	O
russian	O
energy	O
assets	O
and	O
russia	LOC
,	O
for	O
instance	O
,	O
supplying	O
gas	O
to	O
the	O
saudi	ORG
petrochemical	O
industry	O
and	O
reducing	O
drilling/production	O
costs.	O
”	O
russia	LOC
and	O
saudi	ORG
arabia	ORG
are	O
the	O
world	O
’	O
s	O
leading	O
oil	O
exporters	O
.	O
china	LOC
is	O
the	O
leading	O
energy	O
consumer	O
.	O
both	O
russia	LOC
and	O
saudi	ORG
arabia	ORG
are	O
in	O
competition	O
for	O
china	LOC
’	O
s	O
burgeoning	O
energy	O
market	O
.	O
other	O
ancillary	O
factors	O
that	O
come	O
into	O
play	O
include	O
isis	O
,	O
yemen	LOC
,	O
islamic	O
terrorism	O
,	O
as	O
well	O
as	O
the	O
russian	O
military	O
base	O
at	O
tartus	LOC
,	O
syria	LOC
.	O
the	O
old	O
dynamic	O
,	O
in	O
which	O
the	O
u.s.	LOC
encouraged	O
saudi	ORG
arabia	ORG
to	O
rev	O
up	O
production	O
,	O
a	O
request	O
for	O
supporting	O
islamic	O
forces	O
fighting	O
in	O
afghanistan	LOC
,	O
and	O
a	O
u.s.-reliance	O
on	O
oil	O
from	O
abroad	O
,	O
has	O
been	O
confined	O
to	O
the	O
dustbin	O
of	O
history	O
.	O
what	O
will	O
emerge	O
in	O
its	O
place	O
?	O
to	O
begin	O
,	O
there	O
is	O
china	LOC
’	O
s	O
desire	O
to	O
launch	O
a	O
petroyuan	O
to	O
replace	O
the	O
dollar	O
.	O
(	O
perhaps	O
it	O
might	O
be	O
backed	O
by	O
gold	O
,	O
although	O
there	O
isn	O
’	O
t	O
that	O
much	O
gold	O
available	O
in	O
the	O
world	O
to	O
do	O
that	O
.	O
)	O
also	O
as	O
noted	O
,	O
there	O
’	O
s	O
china	LOC
’	O
s	O
“	O
one	O
belt	O
,	O
one	O
road	O
initiative	O
”	O
to	O
consider	O
.	O
this	O
epic	O
project	O
is	O
aimed	O
at	O
linking	O
beijing	LOC
to	O
berlin	LOC
.	O
it	O
would	O
mirror	O
the	O
old	O
silk	O
road	O
of	O
marco	PERS
polo	PERS
,	O
as	O
well	O
as	O
the	O
seafaring	O
exploits	O
of	O
the	O
giant	O
eunuch	O
mariner	O
known	O
as	O
zheng	O
he	O
.	O
china	LOC
has	O
a	O
new	O
“	O
string	O
of	O
pearls	O
,	O
”	O
from	O
shanghai	LOC
to	O
victoria	LOC
bay	LOC
in	O
hong	LOC
kong	LOC
,	O
myanmar	LOC
,	O
pakistan	LOC
,	O
sri	LOC
lanka	LOC
and	O
djibouti	LOC
.	O
china	LOC
controls	O
the	O
panama	LOC
canal	O
through	O
its	O
front	O
company	O
,	O
hutchinson	ORG
whampoa	ORG
.	O
china	LOC
is	O
also	O
seeking	O
to	O
build	O
new	O
panama-style	O
canals	O
through	O
thailand	LOC
and	O
nicaragua	LOC
.	O
china	LOC
has	O
launched	O
the	O
world	O
’	O
s	O
first	O
quantum	O
(	O
secure	O
)	O
satellite	O
,	O
built	O
the	O
world	O
’	O
s	O
largest	O
radio	O
telescope	O
,	O
files	O
the	O
most	O
patents	O
worldwide	O
and	O
seems	O
flush	O
enough	O
with	O
cash	O
to	O
build	O
both	O
high-speed	O
railways	O
and	O
mysterious	O
ghost	O
cities	O
.	O
china	LOC
also	O
has	O
plans	O
to	O
build	O
a	O
lunar	O
colony	O
and	O
(	O
in	O
competition	O
with	O
india	LOC
)	O
mine	O
helium-3	O
from	O
the	O
moon	O
.	O
this	O
is	O
not	O
your	O
father	O
’	O
s	O
china	LOC
,	O
your	O
grandfather	O
’	O
s	O
china	LOC
or	O
even	O
the	O
china	LOC
of	O
1997	O
,	O
when	O
hong	LOC
kong	LOC
was	O
returned	O
by	O
great	LOC
britain	LOC
.	O
as	O
napoleon	O
once	O
remarked	O
,	O
“	O
let	O
china	LOC
sleep	O
,	O
for	O
when	O
she	O
awakens	O
,	O
let	O
the	O
nations	O
tremble.	O
”	O
a	O
changing	O
world	O
the	O
financial	O
leadership	O
of	O
the	O
world	O
underwent	O
tremendous	O
changes	O
in	O
1971	O
,	O
when	O
president	O
nixon	PERS
took	O
the	O
u.s.	LOC
off	O
of	O
the	O
gold	O
standard	O
.	O
another	O
seminal	O
change	O
came	O
in	O
1974	O
,	O
when	O
the	O
u.s.	LOC
and	O
saudi	ORG
arabia	ORG
entered	O
into	O
a	O
geostrategic	O
alliance	O
to	O
launch	O
the	O
global	O
petrodollar	O
–	O
meaning	O
oil	O
was	O
to	O
be	O
sold	O
in	O
u.s.	LOC
dollars	O
.	O
bloomberg	O
published	O
this	O
excellent	O
article	O
by	O
andrea	PERS
wong	PERS
documenting	O
the	O
birth	O
of	O
the	O
petrodollar	O
.	O
reading	O
“	O
the	O
hidden	O
hand	O
of	O
american	O
hegemony	O
:	O
petrodollar	O
recycling	O
and	O
international	O
markets	O
“	O
by	O
columbia	ORG
university	ORG
’	O
s	O
david	PERS
spiro	PERS
is	O
also	O
highly	O
recommended	O
.	O
what	O
does	O
the	O
future	O
hold	O
for	O
saudi	ORG
aramco	ORG
and	O
saudi	ORG
arabia	ORG
?	O
this	O
is	O
the	O
question	O
of	O
the	O
day	O
.	O
the	O
flags	O
of	O
saudi	ORG
aramco	ORG
and	O
saudi	ORG
arabia	ORG
fly	O
side-by-side	O
(	O
photo	O
by	O
anthony	PERS
c.	PERS
lobaido	PERS
)	O
saudi	ORG
aramco	ORG
is	O
staffed	O
by	O
the	O
best	O
and	O
the	O
brightest	O
.	O
they	O
come	O
to	O
the	O
company	O
from	O
mit	O
,	O
baylor	O
,	O
texas	LOC
a	O
&	O
m	O
,	O
nasa	ORG
,	O
cal	O
tech	O
,	O
stanford	O
and	O
elsewhere	O
.	O
this	O
writer	O
had	O
the	O
honor	O
of	O
carrying	O
out	O
more	O
than	O
200	O
hours	O
of	O
private	O
interviews	O
with	O
scientists	O
working	O
at	O
saudi	ORG
aramco	ORG
’	O
s	O
research	O
and	O
development	O
center	O
.	O
as	O
far	O
back	O
as	O
2014	O
,	O
whispers	O
were	O
traveling	O
around	O
the	O
company	O
that	O
r	O
&	O
d	O
was	O
going	O
to	O
be	O
privatized	O
.	O
this	O
might	O
be	O
the	O
world	O
’	O
s	O
best-funded	O
,	O
private	O
collection	O
of	O
scientists	O
.	O
their	O
research	O
on	O
quantum	O
chemistry	O
and	O
ability	O
to	O
generate	O
patents	O
could	O
be	O
worth	O
untold	O
riches	O
.	O
read	O
my	O
article	O
about	O
these	O
scientists	O
,	O
“	O
space	O
cowboys	O
,	O
”	O
here	O
.	O
saudi	ORG
arabia	ORG
is	O
an	O
interesting	O
place	O
.	O
i	O
found	O
the	O
people	O
there	O
to	O
be	O
lovely	O
and	O
charming	O
.	O
many	O
were	O
against	O
isis	O
.	O
some	O
believe	O
christians	O
and	O
islamic	O
believers	O
should	O
work	O
together	O
to	O
solve	O
world	O
problems	O
.	O
while	O
working	O
for	O
saudi	ORG
aramco	ORG
,	O
i	O
was	O
privy	O
to	O
all	O
kinds	O
of	O
ancillary	O
details	O
.	O
there	O
was	O
the	O
story	O
of	O
a	O
man	O
who	O
stole	O
from	O
saudi	ORG
aramco	ORG
and	O
moved	O
to	O
the	O
caribbean	O
–	O
only	O
to	O
have	O
saudi	ORG
aramco	ORG
buy	O
the	O
local	O
bank	O
where	O
he	O
’	O
d	O
hidden	O
his	O
stolen	O
gains	O
.	O
there	O
was	O
the	O
“	O
med	O
ring	O
”	O
theory	O
,	O
in	O
which	O
saudi	ORG
aramco	ORG
scientists	O
would	O
perfect	O
solar	O
storage	O
technology	O
to	O
be	O
strategically	O
placed	O
inside	O
the	O
nations	O
ringing	O
the	O
mediterranean	LOC
sea	LOC
.	O
basically	O
,	O
this	O
would	O
enable	O
infinite	O
solar	O
acquisition	O
,	O
which	O
would	O
then	O
be	O
sold	O
to	O
europe	LOC
during	O
the	O
summers	O
and	O
winters	O
in	O
times	O
of	O
peak	O
need	O
.	O
we	O
were	O
also	O
told	O
stories	O
of	O
how	O
during	O
the	O
early	O
days	O
of	O
the	O
cold	O
war	O
,	O
the	O
cia	O
had	O
positioned	O
assets	O
inside	O
saudi	ORG
aramco	ORG
(	O
and	O
elsewhere	O
)	O
to	O
sabotage	O
the	O
company	O
in	O
case	O
the	O
soviet	ORG
union	ORG
invaded	O
.	O
read	O
about	O
the	O
latter	O
here	O
and	O
here	O
.	O
in	O
the	O
coming	O
decades	O
,	O
i	O
believe	O
saudi	ORG
aramco	ORG
and	O
saudi	ORG
arabia	ORG
will	O
adapt	O
,	O
survive	O
and	O
thrive	O
.	O
as	O
noted	O
,	O
saudi	ORG
aramco	ORG
is	O
staffed	O
by	O
the	O
elite	O
of	O
u.s.	LOC
,	O
western	O
and	O
global	O
society	O
.	O
sure	O
,	O
it	O
’	O
s	O
far	O
from	O
perfect	O
.	O
yes	O
,	O
sophia	O
the	O
robot	O
is	O
inherently	O
creepy	O
and	O
might	O
kill	O
us	O
all	O
one	O
day	O
,	O
with	O
the	O
help	O
of	O
her	O
robot	O
friends	O
.	O
yes	O
,	O
the	O
war	O
in	O
yemen	LOC
is	O
an	O
abomination	O
.	O
yes	O
,	O
it	O
appears	O
saudi	ORG
arabia	ORG
financed	O
the	O
transfer	O
of	O
(	O
some	O
of	O
)	O
moammar	O
gadhafi	O
’	O
s	O
stolen	O
weapons	O
in	O
libya	LOC
from	O
benghazi	O
to	O
isis	O
in	O
syria	LOC
.	O
(	O
i	O
detailed	O
this	O
horrible	O
story	O
on	O
wnd.com	O
via	O
this	O
article	O
.	O
)	O
yes	O
,	O
there	O
may	O
be	O
links	O
between	O
saudi	ORG
arabia	ORG
and	O
9/11	O
.	O
yes	O
,	O
someone	O
actually	O
firebombed	O
one	O
of	O
the	O
saudi	ORG
aramco	ORG
commuter	O
buses	O
.	O
the	O
average	O
person	O
from	O
the	O
middle	LOC
east	LOC
is	O
decent	O
and	O
wants	O
nothing	O
to	O
do	O
with	O
terrorism	O
(	O
qatar	O
photo	O
by	O
anthony	PERS
c.	PERS
lobaido	PERS
)	O
yes	O
,	O
it	O
’	O
s	O
possible	O
that	O
a	O
petroyuan	O
may	O
replace	O
the	O
petrodollar	O
.	O
china	LOC
might	O
not	O
care	O
that	O
saudi	ORG
aramco	ORG
and	O
saudi	ORG
arabia	ORG
are	O
beholden	O
to	O
the	O
monarchy	O
.	O
china	LOC
will	O
protect	O
its	O
new	O
oil	O
fields	O
if	O
it	O
buys	O
into	O
saudi	ORG
aramco	ORG
.	O
china	LOC
has	O
established	O
a	O
base	O
in	O
djibouti	LOC
,	O
smack	O
in	O
the	O
horn	O
of	O
africa	LOC
.	O
china	LOC
has	O
engaged	O
in	O
large-scale	O
desert	O
maneuvers	O
in	O
the	O
gobi	LOC
desert	LOC
.	O
the	O
same	O
kind	O
of	O
wargames	O
one	O
might	O
need	O
to	O
practice	O
in	O
case	O
of	O
a	O
major	O
war	O
in	O
the	O
middle	LOC
east	LOC
and/or	O
north	O
africa	LOC
.	O
china	LOC
may	O
not	O
like	O
the	O
idea	O
of	O
the	O
monarchy	O
in	O
saudi	ORG
arabia	ORG
playing	O
with	O
nuclear	O
warheads	O
on	O
loan	O
from	O
pakistan	LOC
.	O
china	LOC
might	O
covet	O
the	O
untapped	O
energy	O
riches	O
in	O
the	O
rub	O
al-khali	O
or	O
“	O
empty	O
quarter	O
,	O
”	O
baking	O
in	O
the	O
no-man	O
’	O
s	O
land	O
between	O
yemen	LOC
and	O
saudi	ORG
arabia	ORG
.	O
since	O
october	O
2014	O
,	O
it	O
appears	O
there	O
has	O
been	O
a	O
mysterious	O
curse	O
on	O
saudi	ORG
aramco	ORG
and	O
saudi	ORG
arabia	ORG
.	O
over	O
the	O
past	O
three	O
years	O
,	O
the	O
oil	O
price	O
collapsed	O
,	O
we	O
’	O
ve	O
witnessed	O
the	O
emergence	O
of	O
saudi-related	O
lawsuits	O
,	O
the	O
release	O
of	O
the	O
missing	O
28	O
pages	O
,	O
the	O
defeat	O
of	O
isis	O
in	O
syria	LOC
,	O
delays	O
in	O
the	O
ipo	O
and	O
the	O
outing	O
of	O
saudi	ORG
arabia	ORG
’	O
s	O
alleged	O
role	O
in	O
9/11	O
.	O
one	O
would	O
be	O
remiss	O
not	O
to	O
(	O
again	O
)	O
mention	O
the	O
(	O
all	O
but	O
lost	O
)	O
saudi-led	O
war	O
on	O
yemen	LOC
,	O
the	O
resultant	O
famine	O
of	O
biblical	O
proportions	O
–	O
along	O
with	O
the	O
cholera	O
epidemic	O
.	O
the	O
bombing	O
of	O
yemen	LOC
’	O
s	O
school	O
for	O
the	O
blind	O
,	O
as	O
well	O
as	O
the	O
multiple	O
assaults	O
on	O
the	O
doctors	O
without	O
borders	O
hospitals	O
in	O
that	O
war-torn	O
country	O
,	O
are	O
the	O
fruits	O
of	O
the	O
world	O
’	O
s	O
lowest	O
collection	O
of	O
oxygen-stealing	O
parasites	O
.	O
brave	O
and	O
talented	O
journalists	O
like	O
iona	PERS
craig	PERS
have	O
tried	O
to	O
sound	O
the	O
alarm	O
to	O
a	O
tone-deaf	O
world	O
happy	O
to	O
turn	O
a	O
blind	O
eye	O
to	O
the	O
carnage	O
.	O
yet	O
the	O
truth	O
is	O
out	O
there	O
.	O
as	O
stephen	O
king	O
pointed	O
out	O
–	O
through	O
the	O
mantra	O
of	O
the	O
demon	O
“	O
legion	O
”	O
immortalized	O
within	O
the	O
story	O
architecture	O
of	O
the	O
gospel	O
of	O
mark	O
–	O
in	O
his	O
epic	O
“	O
the	O
storm	O
of	O
the	O
century	O
,	O
”	O
indeed	O
:	O
“	O
your	O
sins	O
will	O
find	O
you	O
out.	O
”	O
for	O
example	O
,	O
paul	O
sperry	O
,	O
a	O
terrific	O
journalist	O
and	O
all-around	O
nice	O
guy	O
,	O
published	O
a	O
story	O
in	O
the	O
new	O
york	O
post	O
headlined	O
,	O
“	O
saudi	ORG
government	O
allegedly	O
funded	O
a	O
dry	O
run	O
for	O
9/11.	O
”	O
read	O
it	O
here	O
.	O
what	O
else	O
don	O
’	O
t	O
we	O
know	O
?	O
does	O
all	O
of	O
this	O
spell	O
the	O
end	O
of	O
the	O
american	O
century	O
and	O
the	O
end	O
of	O
the	O
u.s.-saudi	O
petrodollar	O
?	O
much	O
in	O
the	O
same	O
way	O
that	O
myanmar	LOC
is	O
able	O
to	O
play	O
china	LOC
,	O
the	O
u.k.	LOC
,	O
the	O
u.s.	LOC
and	O
india	LOC
off	O
against	O
one	O
another	O
,	O
so	O
too	O
can	O
saudi	ORG
arabia	ORG
strike	O
a	O
delicate	O
balance	O
between	O
the	O
u.s.	LOC
,	O
russia	LOC
and	O
china	LOC
.	O
maybe	O
the	O
petrodollar	O
will	O
continue	O
.	O
maybe	O
it	O
will	O
collapse	O
.	O
maybe	O
there	O
will	O
be	O
a	O
new	O
petroyuan	O
,	O
rising	O
phoenix-like	O
in	O
its	O
place	O
.	O
maybe	O
there	O
will	O
be	O
a	O
new	O
global	O
basket	O
of	O
currencies	O
from	O
which	O
special	O
drawing	O
rights	O
will	O
emerge	O
.	O
final	O
thoughts	O
hopefully	O
,	O
the	O
saudi	ORG
aramco	ORG
ipo	O
(	O
in	O
any	O
form	O
)	O
won	O
’	O
t	O
gain	O
a	O
great	O
deal	O
of	O
traction	O
at	O
the	O
global	O
pawn	O
shop	O
.	O
my	O
own	O
fear	O
is	O
that	O
once	O
a	O
single	O
chunk	O
of	O
saudi	ORG
aramco	ORG
is	O
pawned	O
off	O
,	O
it	O
will	O
make	O
it	O
that	O
much	O
easier	O
for	O
another	O
,	O
and	O
another	O
,	O
and	O
then	O
another	O
after	O
that	O
–	O
until	O
nothing	O
of	O
the	O
original	O
architecture	O
of	O
the	O
company	O
is	O
left	O
.	O
no	O
transnational	O
corporation	O
since	O
the	O
british	ORG
east	ORG
india	ORG
company	ORG
has	O
been	O
so	O
influential	O
in	O
geostrategic	O
terms	O
.	O
this	O
would	O
be	O
like	O
watching	O
the	O
sinking	O
of	O
a	O
great	O
and	O
mighty	O
ocean-going	O
vessel	O
.	O
i	O
suppose	O
i	O
was	O
very	O
lucky	O
,	O
as	O
a	O
journalist	O
and	O
photographer	O
,	O
to	O
have	O
gotten	O
a	O
glimpse	O
inside	O
of	O
saudi	ORG
aramco	ORG
’	O
s	O
mysterious	O
“	O
black	O
box.	O
”	O
there	O
’	O
s	O
a	O
reason	O
sophia	O
the	O
robot	O
made	O
her	O
grand	O
entrance	O
onto	O
the	O
world	O
stage	O
in	O
saudi	ORG
arabia	ORG
.	O
the	O
nation	O
,	O
and	O
saudi	ORG
aramco	ORG
,	O
are	O
both	O
demonstrating	O
how	O
they	O
’	O
re	O
adjusting	O
to	O
an	O
exponentially	O
changing	O
world	O
to	O
remain	O
a	O
global	O
player	O
,	O
if	O
not	O
leader	O
.	O
with	O
its	O
vast	O
oil	O
wealth	O
,	O
saudi	ORG
arabia	ORG
will	O
continue	O
to	O
purchase	O
technology	O
,	O
human	O
capital	O
,	O
ideas	O
,	O
weapons	O
,	O
public	O
relations	O
gurus	O
and	O
influence	O
on	O
a	O
global	O
scale	O
.	O
with	O
that	O
in	O
mind	O
,	O
it	O
might	O
be	O
a	O
good	O
idea	O
to	O
start	O
studying	O
mandarin	O
–	O
just	O
in	O
case	O
.	O
a	O
woman	O
strolls	O
around	O
a	O
crafts	O
bazaar	O
in	O
nizwa	O
,	O
oman	LOC
(	O
photo	O
by	O
anthony	PERS
c.	PERS
lobaido	PERS
)	O
click	O
here	O
for	O
reuse	O
options	O
!	O
saudi	O
arabia	O
to	O
include	O
low-cost	O
flyadeal	ORG
saudi	ORG
arabian	ORG
airlines	ORG
,	O
(	O
saudia	O
)	O
the	O
kingdom	O
’	O
s	O
flag-carrier	O
,	O
is	O
planning	O
to	O
privatize	O
the	O
main	O
airline	O
and	O
the	O
low-cost	O
carrier	O
flyadeal	ORG
in	O
a	O
single	O
transaction	O
,	O
according	O
to	O
company	O
plans	O
seen	O
by	O
arab	O
news	O
.	O
most	O
of	O
the	O
rest	O
of	O
the	O
saudia	O
aviation	O
business	O
—	O
cargo	O
,	O
maintenance	O
,	O
training	O
,	O
medical	O
and	O
real	O
estate	O
—	O
will	O
be	O
privatized	O
in	O
a	O
series	O
of	O
trade	O
sales	O
and	O
public	O
share	O
offerings	O
.	O
the	O
whole	O
process	O
is	O
aimed	O
to	O
be	O
completed	O
by	O
2020	O
,	O
with	O
an	O
initial	O
public	O
offering	O
of	O
a	O
combined	O
entity	O
saudia	O
and	O
flyadeal	ORG
the	O
most	O
likely	O
option	O
.	O
the	O
saudi	ORG
royal	ORG
fleet	ORG
will	O
not	O
be	O
part	O
of	O
the	O
privatise	O
plan	O
,	O
according	O
to	O
the	O
plans	O
.	O
it	O
is	O
believed	O
the	O
process	O
of	O
“	O
corporatization	O
”	O
—	O
removal	O
from	O
public	O
ownership	O
and	O
establishment	O
as	O
a	O
limited	O
liability	O
company	O
—	O
has	O
already	O
begun	O
.	O
the	O
plans	O
show	O
a	O
new	O
entity	O
,	O
saudi	ORG
arabian	ORG
airlines	ORG
corporation	ORG
(	O
saac	O
)	O
,	O
which	O
could	O
be	O
corporatised	O
into	O
a	O
holding	O
company	O
this	O
year	O
.	O
a	O
saudia	O
spokesperson	O
said	O
:	O
“	O
one	O
significant	O
part	O
of	O
the	O
group	O
’	O
s	O
privatization	O
plan	O
is	O
to	O
incorporate	O
saac	O
to	O
become	O
the	O
group	O
’	O
s	O
parent	O
company	O
.	O
there	O
are	O
no	O
explicit	O
decisions	O
for	O
this	O
yet	O
,	O
but	O
the	O
estimated	O
timeline	O
is	O
by	O
2020.	O
”	O
the	O
privatization	O
of	O
saudia	O
will	O
be	O
a	O
significant	O
event	O
in	O
the	O
kingdom	O
’	O
s	O
national	O
transformation	O
program	O
.	O
although	O
not	O
as	O
valuable	O
in	O
monetary	O
terms	O
as	O
other	O
parts	O
of	O
the	O
national	O
portfolio	O
—	O
like	O
energy	O
and	O
infrastructure	O
assets	O
—	O
offering	O
shares	O
in	O
the	O
national	O
airline	O
will	O
be	O
regarded	O
as	O
a	O
test	O
of	O
the	O
saudi	O
public	O
’	O
s	O
appetite	O
for	O
privatization	O
sales	O
.	O
saudia	O
was	O
identified	O
as	O
one	O
of	O
the	O
“	O
jewels	O
in	O
the	O
crown	O
of	O
the	O
privatization	O
process	O
launched	O
by	O
the	O
national	ORG
center	ORG
for	ORG
privatization	ORG
,	O
the	O
body	O
charged	O
with	O
co-ordinating	O
the	O
kingdom	O
’	O
s	O
$	O
200bn	O
sell-off	O
by	O
the	O
council	ORG
for	ORG
economic	ORG
and	ORG
development	ORG
affairs	ORG
.	O
the	O
inclusion	O
of	O
flyadeal	ORG
in	O
the	O
sell-off	O
plan	O
is	O
also	O
significant	O
.	O
the	O
new	O
airline	O
—	O
launched	O
as	O
part	O
of	O
a	O
liberalization	O
of	O
the	O
saudi	O
aviation	O
industry	O
—	O
has	O
only	O
just	O
been	O
awarded	O
its	O
air	O
operators	O
certificate	O
and	O
taken	O
delivery	O
of	O
its	O
first	O
planes	O
.	O
flyadeal	ORG
’	O
s	O
first	O
route	O
—	O
between	O
riyadh	LOC
and	O
jeddah	O
—	O
started	O
on	O
saturday	O
.	O
the	O
spokesperson	O
added	O
:	O
“	O
the	O
group	O
privatization	O
strategy	O
covers	O
all	O
strategic	O
business	O
units	O
excluding	O
the	O
royal	O
fleet	O
.	O
the	O
plan	O
is	O
to	O
privatise	O
saudia	O
and	O
flyadeal	ORG
together	O
under	O
the	O
group	O
parent	O
company	O
.	O
privatization	O
is	O
already	O
underway	O
in	O
some	O
saudia	O
subsidiaries	O
.	O
“	O
non-core	O
”	O
entities	O
like	O
catering	O
and	O
ground	O
services	O
are	O
already	O
publicly	O
traded	O
,	O
while	O
others	O
such	O
as	O
real	O
estate	O
and	O
the	O
prince	ORG
sultan	ORG
aviation	ORG
academy	ORG
are	O
“	O
under	O
transformation	O
,	O
preparing	O
for	O
privatization	O
,	O
”	O
according	O
to	O
the	O
plans	O
.	O
advisers	O
are	O
believed	O
to	O
have	O
been	O
engaged	O
,	O
but	O
saudia	O
declined	O
to	O
identify	O
them	O
.	O
“	O
the	O
privatization	O
for	O
each	O
business	O
unit	O
involves	O
the	O
use	O
of	O
various	O
external	O
advisers	O
—	O
legal	O
,	O
financial	O
,	O
and	O
strategic	O
—	O
in	O
collaboration	O
with	O
the	O
respective	O
boards	O
and	O
the	O
owners	O
,	O
”	O
the	O
spokesperson	O
said	O
.	O
the	O
privatization	O
process	O
is	O
expected	O
to	O
change	O
the	O
management	O
structure	O
and	O
business	O
culture	O
at	O
saudia	O
in	O
a	O
number	O
of	O
ways	O
,	O
formally	O
breaking	O
up	O
a	O
single	O
corporate	O
entity	O
into	O
multiple	O
companies	O
.	O
its	O
corporate	O
structure	O
will	O
move	O
from	O
“	O
divisional	O
management	O
to	O
a	O
client	O
vendor	O
relationship	O
,	O
”	O
and	O
from	O
a	O
“	O
single	O
marketing	O
model	O
to	O
an	O
alliance	O
marketing	O
model.	O
”	O
there	O
will	O
also	O
be	O
an	O
impact	O
on	O
saudia	O
’	O
s	O
information	O
technology	O
capability	O
.	O
the	O
main	O
saudia	O
airline	O
—	O
founded	O
in	O
1945	O
—	O
has	O
a	O
fleet	O
of	O
141	O
aircraft	O
and	O
recently	O
launched	O
its	O
87th	O
destination	O
with	O
a	O
route	O
to	O
mauritius	LOC
.	O
earlier	O
this	O
year	O
it	O
was	O
named	O
the	O
“	O
most	O
improved	O
airline	O
”	O
at	O
the	O
skytrax	ORG
world	O
airline	O
awards	O
.	O
a	O
new	O
top	O
executive	O
team	O
of	O
director	O
general	O
saleh	PERS
bin	PERS
nasser	PERS
al-jasser	PERS
and	O
ceo	O
jaan	PERS
albrecht	PERS
has	O
been	O
in	O
place	O
since	O
last	O
year	O
.	O
source	O
:	O
arab	O
news	O
private	O
equity	O
groups	O
see	O
saudi	LOC
arabia	LOC
as	O
a	O
deep	O
as	O
head	O
of	O
investment	O
banking	O
at	O
emirates	ORG
investment	ORG
bank	ORG
(	O
eib	ORG
)	O
,	O
one	O
of	O
the	O
uae	LOC
’	O
s	O
best-known	O
financial	O
services	O
groups	O
,	O
husam	PERS
kutaifan	PERS
’	O
s	O
resume	O
ticks	O
most	O
of	O
the	O
appropriate	O
boxes	O
in	O
the	O
current	O
middle	LOC
east	LOC
investment	O
scene	O
.	O
he	O
has	O
experience	O
of	O
privatization	O
—	O
an	O
essential	O
part	O
of	O
saudi	LOC
arabia	LOC
’	O
s	O
transformation	O
plans	O
—	O
from	O
his	O
early	O
banking	O
days	O
in	O
his	O
native	O
jordan	O
;	O
and	O
he	O
worked	O
in	O
the	O
kingdom	O
for	O
the	O
investment	O
banking	O
arm	O
of	O
financial	O
services	O
group	O
samba	ORG
during	O
the	O
boom	O
years	O
ahead	O
of	O
the	O
global	O
financial	O
crisis	O
.	O
with	O
eib	ORG
,	O
he	O
has	O
direct	O
access	O
to	O
the	O
clients	O
who	O
will	O
be	O
key	O
players	O
in	O
helping	O
the	O
saudi	O
plans	O
work	O
,	O
as	O
well	O
as	O
getting	O
involved	O
in	O
the	O
other	O
ambitious	O
initial	O
public	O
offerings	O
(	O
ipos	O
)	O
in	O
the	O
region	O
:	O
big	O
investing	O
institutions	O
,	O
family	O
groups	O
and	O
high	O
net	O
worth	O
individuals	O
(	O
hnwis	O
)	O
that	O
will	O
be	O
looking	O
to	O
take	O
up	O
the	O
shares	O
in	O
any	O
state	O
sell-offs	O
in	O
the	O
region	O
.	O
i	O
met	O
kutaifan	O
on	O
the	O
day	O
that	O
news	O
broke	O
that	O
a	O
strategically	O
repositioned	O
version	O
of	O
saudi	LOC
arabia	LOC
’	O
s	O
national	O
transformation	O
program	O
(	O
ntp	O
)	O
2020	O
was	O
being	O
issued	O
by	O
the	O
government	O
to	O
recalibrate	O
the	O
plan	O
for	O
diversification	O
away	O
from	O
oil	O
dependency	O
and	O
public	O
spending	O
.	O
“	O
i	O
think	O
flexibility	O
is	O
a	O
good	O
thing	O
.	O
it	O
would	O
be	O
the	O
first	O
time	O
saudi	LOC
arabia	LOC
has	O
amended	O
such	O
a	O
long-term	O
plan	O
,	O
but	O
if	O
it	O
helps	O
manage	O
expectations	O
in	O
the	O
markets	O
and	O
in	O
the	O
country	O
,	O
that	O
’	O
s	O
“	O
our	O
clients	O
are	O
saying	O
‘	O
finally	O
we	O
can	O
plan	O
with	O
some	O
certainty.	O
’	O
it	O
’	O
s	O
good	O
to	O
have	O
a	O
dose	O
of	O
reality	O
in	O
the	O
plan	O
,	O
that	O
definitely	O
helps	O
.	O
we	O
’	O
ll	O
have	O
to	O
see	O
how	O
much	O
of	O
an	O
adjustment	O
takes	O
place	O
,	O
but	O
i	O
think	O
all	O
the	O
main	O
elements	O
will	O
remain	O
as	O
part	O
of	O
the	O
