davos	LOC
2012	O
live	O
:	O
growth	O
predictions	O
set	O
the	O
scene	O
for	O
a	O
gloomy	O
summit	O
full	O
text	O
7.43pm	O
:	O
apologies	O
for	O
the	O
delay	O
in	O
posting	O
this	O
-	O
we	O
've	O
been	O
having	O
some	O
technical	O
problems	O
.	O
here	O
's	O
a	O
summary	O
of	O
the	O
main	O
developments	O
:	O
�	O
commentators	O
were	O
almost	O
completely	O
in	O
agreement	O
:	O
this	O
is	O
a	O
sombre	O
,	O
subdued	O
davos	LOC
.	O
the	O
mood	O
is	O
one	O
of	O
trepidation	O
,	O
with	O
the	O
global	O
economic	O
crisis	O
far	O
from	O
over	O
.	O
�	O
two	O
early	O
stars	O
of	O
the	O
summit	O
were	O
economist	O
nouriel	PERS
roubini	PERS
and	O
veteran	O
investor	O
george	PERS
soros	PERS
.	O
roubini	PERS
was	O
unequivocal	O
:	O
``	O
the	O
policy	O
response	O
is	O
making	O
the	O
recession	O
worse	O
''	O
.	O
soros	PERS
warned	O
``	O
the	O
euro	O
must	O
survive	O
because	O
the	O
alternative	O
,	O
a	O
break-up	O
,	O
would	O
cause	O
a	O
meltdown	O
that	O
europe	LOC
and	O
the	O
world	O
ca	O
n't	O
afford	O
''	O
.	O
�	O
protestors	O
from	O
the	O
occupy	O
movement	O
made	O
sure	O
their	O
message	O
was	O
heard	O
,	O
despite	O
being	O
banished	O
from	O
the	O
summit	O
site	O
itself	O
.	O
�	O
angela	PERS
merkel	PERS
used	O
her	O
speech	O
to	O
echo	O
themes	O
she	O
raised	O
in	O
an	O
interview	O
published	O
by	O
six	O
european	O
newspapers	O
,	O
including	O
the	O
guardian	O
.	O
she	O
called	O
for	O
closer	O
political	O
union	O
in	O
the	O
eu	LOC
,	O
and	O
urged	O
that	O
austerity	O
must	O
be	O
accompanied	O
by	O
structural	O
reform	O
.	O
thanks	O
for	O
reading	O
and	O
for	O
your	O
comments	O
below	O
.	O
we	O
'll	O
be	O
back	O
again	O
tomorrow	O
.	O
5.29pm	O
:	O
and	O
now	O
for	O
the	O
other	O
side	O
of	O
davos	LOC
-	O
things	O
picked	O
up	O
on	O
the	O
fringes	O
of	O
the	O
summit	O
,	O
rather	O
than	O
in	O
the	O
grand	O
surroundings	O
of	O
the	O
conference	O
hall	O
.	O
jane	PERS
martinson	PERS
sent	O
me	O
this	O
interesting	O
tidbit	O
,	O
having	O
bumped	O
into	O
media	O
maverick	O
arianna	PERS
huffington	PERS
.	O
arianna	PERS
huffington	PERS
,	O
at	O
davos	LOC
'til	O
the	O
bitter	O
end	O
'	O
this	O
week	O
spent	O
time	O
in	O
the	O
belvedere	ORG
hotel	ORG
's	O
google	ORG
bar	O
defending	O
her	O
eponymous	O
media	O
company	O
's	O
controversial	O
decision	O
to	O
hire	O
anne	PERS
sinclair	PERS
,	O
the	O
wife	O
of	O
disgraced	O
politician	O
dsk	O
.	O
'just	O
look	O
on	O
facebook	ORG
in	O
france	LOC
.	O
she	O
had	O
a	O
huge	O
impact	O
.	O
all	O
the	O
women	O
praising	O
her	O
,	O
saying	O
things	O
like	O
'you	O
helped	O
me	O
get	O
thru	O
my	O
divorce	O
'	O
.	O
i	O
'm	O
making	O
no	O
comment	O
on	O
her	O
decision	O
which	O
led	O
to	O
a	O
very	O
public	O
ordeal	O
.	O
but	O
she	O
is	O
an	O
amazing	O
woman	O
and	O
journalist	O
and	O
she	O
's	O
loving	O
huffington	PERS
post	PERS
.	O
'	O
she	O
added	O
that	O
the	O
two	O
women	O
share	O
a	O
birthday	O
-	O
15	O
july	O
.	O
5.23pm	O
:	O
here	O
's	O
jill	PERS
treanor	PERS
's	O
take	O
on	O
the	O
german	O
chancellor	O
's	O
speech	O
:	O
angela	PERS
merkel	PERS
's	O
interview	O
with	O
the	O
guardian	O
,	O
and	O
other	O
papers	O
,	O
set	O
the	O
tone	O
for	O
her	O
address	O
to	O
the	O
world	O
economic	O
forum	O
in	O
davos	LOC
.	O
she	O
warned	O
that	O
while	O
germany	LOC
was	O
big	O
it	O
could	O
make	O
promises	O
that	O
markets	O
could	O
pounce	O
upon	O
and	O
attack	O
if	O
they	O
were	O
not	O
kept	O
.	O
she	O
pointed	O
to	O
more	O
cooperation	O
in	O
europe	LOC
-	O
more	O
mobility	O
of	O
labour	O
and	O
portability	O
of	O
pensions	O
and	O
such	O
like	O
.	O
she	O
also	O
reiterated	O
that	O
the	O
union	O
could	O
``	O
dare	O
''	O
for	O
``	O
more	O
europe	LOC
''	O
in	O
2012	O
,	O
and	O
set	O
out	O
a	O
vision	O
whereby	O
the	O
european	ORG
commission	ORG
becomes	O
``	O
more	O
and	O
more	O
like	O
a	O
government	O
''	O
.	O
her	O
acknowledgment	O
of	O
the	O
high	O
level	O
of	O
youth	O
unemployment	O
was	O
telling	O
.	O
if	O
she	O
and	O
her	O
eurozone	O
counterparts	O
ca	O
n't	O
create	O
jobs	O
-	O
while	O
imposing	O
austerity	O
-	O
then	O
the	O
euro	O
project	O
will	O
have	O
no	O
meaning	O
for	O
the	O
upcoming	O
generation	O
.	O
5.03pm	O
:	O
merkel	PERS
has	O
now	O
left	O
the	O
stage	O
after	O
fielding	O
questions	O
from	O
a	O
few	O
minutes	O
from	O
professor	O
schwab	PERS
.	O
all	O
in	O
all	O
her	O
comments	O
generated	O
few	O
surprises	O
.	O
she	O
expressed	O
the	O
widely-held	O
view	O
that	O
europe	LOC
lacks	O
the	O
``	O
political	O
structures	O
''	O
to	O
make	O
the	O
euro	O
work	O
properly	O
,	O
and	O
emphasised	O
the	O
need	O
to	O
build	O
some	O
.	O
she	O
also	O
pleaded	O
for	O
patience	O
from	O
the	O
business	O
community	O
:	O
please	O
realise	O
that	O
when	O
you	O
're	O
working	O
in	O
a	O
democracy	O
,	O
that	O
it	O
is	O
a	O
beautiful	O
thing	O
,	O
and	O
please	O
take	O
the	O
long	O
drawn	O
out	O
processes	O
with	O
a	O
certain	O
degree	O
of	O
acceptance	O
.	O
and	O
on	O
behalf	O
of	O
europe	LOC
as	O
a	O
whole	O
,	O
she	O
ended	O
,	O
a	O
little	O
plaintively	O
,	O
with	O
:	O
``	O
please	O
do	O
n't	O
forget	O
us	LOC
when	O
you	O
're	O
thinking	O
of	O
investment	O
.	O
''	O
i	O
hope	O
to	O
have	O
more	O
reaction	O
from	O
jill	PERS
treanor	PERS
,	O
in	O
davos	LOC
,	O
soon	O
.	O
4.37pm	O
:	O
merkel	PERS
is	O
calling	O
for	O
austerity	O
measures	O
to	O
be	O
balanced	O
with	O
structural	O
reform	O
aimed	O
at	O
boosting	O
employment	O
,	O
particularly	O
for	O
euro-area	O
countries	O
.	O
all	O
of	O
this	O
points	O
towards	O
full-throated	O
support	O
for	O
political	O
and	O
fiscal	O
union	O
,	O
as	O
we	O
expected	O
.	O
``	O
we	O
have	O
to	O
be	O
ready	O
to	O
transfer	O
more	O
competencies	O
to	O
europe	LOC
,	O
''	O
she	O
says	O
.	O
``	O
we	O
will	O
have	O
to	O
make	O
more	O
progress	O
[	O
on	O
integration	O
]	O
in	O
the	O
interests	O
of	O
competitiveness	O
and	O
job	O
creation	O
.	O
''	O
my	O
colleague	O
jill	PERS
treanor	PERS
tweets	O
:	O
merkel	PERS
on	O
high	O
youth	O
unemployment	O
:	O
``	O
it	O
's	O
not	O
a	O
great	O
miracle	O
that	O
young	O
people	O
do	O
not	O
think	O
the	O
euro	O
is	O
a	O
good	O
option	O
for	O
them	O
''	O
-	O
jill	PERS
treanor	PERS
(	O
@	O
jilltreanor	O
)	O
january	O
25	O
,	O
2012	O
my	O
colleagues	O
on	O
the	O
business	O
desk	O
suggest	O
this	O
might	O
be	O
better	O
translated	O
as	O
``	O
they	O
do	O
n't	O
think	O
much	O
of	O
the	O
euro	O
and	O
frankly	O
i	O
'm	O
not	O
surprised	O
''	O
.	O
4.24pm	O
:	O
angela	PERS
merkel	PERS
is	O
now	O
speaking	O
,	O
so	O
keep	O
an	O
eye	O
on	O
that	O
live	O
feed	O
below	O
.	O
in	O
his	O
introduction	O
klaus	PERS
schwab	PERS
called	O
the	O
german	O
chancellor	O
a	O
``	O
tower	O
of	O
strength	O
''	O
.	O
merkel	PERS
,	O
for	O
her	O
part	O
says	O
:	O
what	O
is	O
needed	O
is	O
a	O
big	O
rethink	O
.	O
let	O
us	LOC
take	O
a	O
moment	O
to	O
reflect	O
what	O
lessons	O
we	O
have	O
learned	O
from	O
the	O
global	O
financial	O
crisis	O
.	O
is	O
it	O
sufficient	O
what	O
we	O
have	O
learned	O
?	O
there	O
's	O
still	O
room	O
for	O
improvement	O
.	O
meanwhile	O
,	O
here	O
's	O
a	O
typically	O
acerbic	O
comment	O
from	O
harvard	O
business	O
review	O
blogger	O
,	O
umair	O
haque	O
,	O
on	O
twitter-sycophancy	O
at	O
the	O
summit	O
:	O
rule	O
:	O
if	O
you	O
tweet	O
breathlessly	O
about	O
superstar	O
politicians	O
you	O
see	O
in	O
the	O
corridors	O
of	O
davos	LOC
,	O
you	O
are	O
why	O
democracy	O
's	O
fucked	O
.	O
-	O
umair	O
haque	O
(	O
@	O
umairh	O
)	O
january	O
25	O
,	O
2012	O
4.06pm	O
:	O
the	O
official	O
opening	O
of	O
the	O
world	O
economic	O
forum	O
summit	O
is	O
now	O
underway	O
,	O
introduced	O
by	O
professor	O
klaus	PERS
schwab	PERS
,	O
who	O
created	O
wef	O
40	O
years	O
ago	O
.	O
the	O
live	O
feed	O
above	O
will	O
bring	O
you	O
all	O
the	O
action	O
,	O
including	O
the	O
much-anticipated	O
speech	O
from	O
german	O
chancellor	O
,	O
angela	PERS
merkel	PERS
.	O
3.57pm	O
:	O
here	O
's	O
an	O
opportunity	O
for	O
you	O
to	O
ask	O
some	O
questions	O
:	O
associated	O
press	O
are	O
hosting	O
a	O
debate	O
tomorrow	O
at	O
14:30	O
uk	LOC
time	O
.	O
the	O
motion	O
is	O
'are	O
the	O
democratic	O
institutions	O
of	O
the	O
20th	O
century	O
fit	O
for	O
the	O
21st	O
?	O
'	O
-	O
very	O
much	O
in	O
keeping	O
with	O
the	O
summit	O
's	O
humbled	O
,	O
reflective	O
mode	O
.	O
they	O
're	O
using	O
facebook	ORG
to	O
ask	O
for	O
ideas	O
as	O
to	O
what	O
they	O
can	O
ask	O
panellists	O
including	O
tunisian	ORG
politician	O
rachid	PERS
ghannouchi	PERS
,	O
republican	O
congressman	O
david	PERS
t	PERS
dreier	PERS
,	O
pakistani	O
foreign	O
minister	O
hina	PERS
rabbani	PERS
khar	PERS
and	O
executive	O
director	O
of	O
human	ORG
rights	ORG
watch	ORG
kenneth	ORG
roth	ORG
.	O
3.21pm	O
:	O
nobel-prize	O
winning	O
economist	O
joseph	PERS
stiglitz	PERS
has	O
been	O
talking	O
to	O
delegates	O
about	O
the	O
future	O
of	O
his	O
discipline	O
.	O
he	O
's	O
urged	O
economists	O
to	O
learn	O
from	O
the	O
insights	O
of	O
other	O
fields	O
:	O
political	O
science	O
,	O
sociology	O
and	O
psychology	O
,	O
rather	O
than	O
the	O
other	O
way	O
around	O
.	O
economics	O
has	O
behaved	O
as	O
an	O
imperialistic	O
science	O
by	O
trying	O
to	O
impose	O
its	O
models	O
to	O
other	O
fields	O
.	O
he	O
's	O
also	O
said	O
that	O
10	O
years	O
is	O
an	O
optimistic	O
estimate	O
of	O
how	O
long	O
it	O
will	O
take	O
to	O
recover	O
from	O
the	O
current	O
crisis	O
.	O
3.03pm	O
:	O
however	O
politically	O
unacceptable	O
it	O
might	O
be	O
to	O
raise	O
the	O
prospect	O
of	O
a	O
breakup	O
of	O
the	O
euro	O
(	O
though	O
merkel	PERS
came	O
near	O
to	O
admitting	O
it	O
would	O
be	O
a	O
close	O
run	O
thing	O
today	O
)	O
,	O
hard-nosed	O
financiers	O
are	O
n't	O
willing	O
to	O
simply	O
cross	O
their	O
fingers	O
.	O
economist	O
megan	PERS
greene	PERS
chillingly	O
tweets	O
:	O
rt	O
@	O
jeremywarneruk	O
:	O
#	O
davos	LOC
all	O
bankers	O
i	O
've	O
seen	O
here	O
say	O
they	O
have	O
detailed	O
contingency	O
plans	O
for	O
euro	O
breakup	O
.	O
``	O
how	O
could	O
i	O
not	O
''	O
,	O
says	O
one	O
-	O
megan	PERS
greene	PERS
(	O
@	O
economistmeg	O
)	O
january	O
25	O
,	O
2012	O
2.44pm	O
:	O
an	O
interesting	O
post	O
over	O
on	O
reuters	O
from	O
finance	O
blogger	O
felix	PERS
salmon	PERS
in	O
which	O
he	O
says	O
``	O
by	O
far	O
of	O
the	O
most-talked-about-person-in-davos	O
...	O
at	O
least	O
when	O
it	O
comes	O
to	O
people	O
in	O
my	O
earshot	O
,	O
is	O
george	PERS
soros	PERS
''	O
.	O
in	O
articulating	O
some	O
of	O
the	O
delegate	O
's	O
worst	O
fears	O
,	O
soros	PERS
is	O
turning	O
into	O
the	O
emblematic	O
man	O
of	O
davos	LOC
2012	O
,	O
which	O
is	O
shaping	O
up	O
to	O
be	O
a	O
rather	O
discomfiting	O
event	O
.	O
salmon	PERS
writes	O
:	O
the	O
financial	O
crisis	O
concentrated	O
minds	O
and	O
was	O
seen	O
as	O
a	O
big	O
problem	O
to	O
be	O
addressed	O
and	O
even	O
maybe	O
solved	O
.	O
but	O
the	O
current	O
breakdown	O
of	O
trust	O
in	O
global	O
institutions	O
cuts	O
at	O
the	O
heart	O
of	O
the	O
world	O
economic	O
forum	O
's	O
founding	O
principle	O
-	O
that	O
if	O
you	O
get	O
a	O
bunch	O
of	O
important	O
people	O
together	O
in	O
the	O
same	O
place	O
,	O
they	O
can	O
actually	O
make	O
a	O
difference	O
.	O
there	O
are	O
fewer	O
heads	O
of	O
state	O
here	O
than	O
there	O
normally	O
are	O
;	O
even	O
bill	PERS
clinton	PERS
is	O
giving	O
davos	LOC
a	O
miss	O
this	O
year	O
.	O
and	O
a	O
theme	O
running	O
through	O
many	O
of	O
the	O
discussions	O
so	O
far	O
seems	O
to	O
be	O
the	O
question	O
of	O
how	O
one	O
manages	O
chaos	O
,	O
in	O
a	O
world	O
where	O
the	O
risk	O
of	O
a	O
chaotic	O
breakup	O
of	O
the	O
european	LOC
union	LOC
can	O
be	O
ignored	O
no	O
longer	O
.	O
2.21pm	O
:	O
angela	PERS
merkel	PERS
's	O
speech	O
,	O
due	O
to	O
begin	O
at	O
around	O
16:00	O
uk	LOC
time	O
,	O
is	O
likely	O
to	O
be	O
the	O
pivotal	O
moment	O
of	O
this	O
year	O
's	O
davos	LOC
summit	O
,	O
given	O
the	O
looming	O
european	O
debt	O
crisis	O
.	O
what	O
's	O
she	O
going	O
to	O
say	O
?	O
the	O
bbc	O
reports	O
that	O
she	O
will	O
``	O
urge	O
the	O
17	O
countries	O
that	O
use	O
the	O
euro	O
to	O
deal	O
with	O
fundamental	O
problems	O
underlying	O
the	O
crisis	O
''	O
.	O
further	O
clues	O
come	O
in	O
the	O
interview	O
merkel	PERS
gave	O
to	O
six	O
european	O
newspapers	O
,	O
including	O
the	O
guardian	O
,	O
today	O
.	O
in	O
it	O
,	O
she	O
underlines	O
the	O
need	O
for	O
closer	O
political	O
and	O
fiscal	O
union	O
,	O
the	O
so-called	O
``	O
fiscal	O
compact	O
''	O
:	O
we	O
will	O
only	O
be	O
able	O
to	O
strengthen	O
our	O
common	O
currency	O
if	O
we	O
co-ordinate	O
our	O
policies	O
more	O
closely	O
and	O
are	O
prepared	O
to	O
gradually	O
give	O
up	O
more	O
powers	O
to	O
the	O
eu	LOC
.	O
1.56pm	O
:	O
peter	PERS
mandelson	PERS
,	O
former	O
uk	LOC
cabinet	O
minister	O
and	O
eu	LOC
trade	O
commissioner	O
,	O
is	O
exactly	O
the	O
kind	O
of	O
person	O
you	O
'd	O
expect	O
to	O
find	O
at	O
davos	LOC
,	O
at	O
home	O
among	O
the	O
elite	O
.	O
but	O
it	O
seems	O
he	O
did	O
n't	O
get	O
the	O
kind	O
of	O
reception	O
he	O
'd	O
been	O
hoping	O
for	O
at	O
an	O
event	O
hosted	O
by	O
law	O
firm	O
clifford	ORG
chance	ORG
.	O
juliet	PERS
samuel	PERS
,	O
a	O
banking	O
reporter	O
at	O
city	ORG
am	ORG
tweets	O
:	O
mandelson	PERS
both	O
clapped	O
and	O
hissed	O
at	O
clifford	PERS
chance	PERS
davos	PERS
event	O
-	O
juliet	PERS
samuel	PERS
(	O
@	O
citysamuel	O
)	O
january	O
25	O
,	O
2012	O
quizzed	O
by	O
my	O
colleague	O
,	O
graeme	PERS
wearden	PERS
,	O
she	O
followed	O
that	O
up	O
with	O
:	O
@	O
graemewearden	O
yep	O
hissed	O
.	O
for	O
blaming	O
banks	O
for	O
sovereign	O
debt	O
crisis	O
(	O
his	O
reasoning	O
not	O
clear	O
)	O
-	O
juliet	PERS
samuel	PERS
(	O
@	O
citysamuel	O
)	O
january	O
25	O
,	O
2012	O
there	O
's	O
more	O
on	O
this	O
mini-spat	O
from	O
kamal	O
ahmed	O
,	O
sunday	O
telegraph	O
business	O
editor	O
,	O
who	O
was	O
at	O
the	O
same	O
session	O
:	O
fight	O
!	O
fight	O
!	O
peter	PERS
mandelson	PERS
lays	O
into	O
gerard	PERS
lyons	PERS
on	O
prediction	O
that	O
euro	O
will	O
break	O
up	O
.	O
``	O
we	O
do	O
n't	O
need	O
lessons	O
from	O
bankers	O
''	O
#	O
davos	LOC
-	O
kamal	O
ahmed	O
(	O
@	O
kamalahmed1	O
)	O
january	O
25	O
,	O
2012	O
1.21pm	O
:	O
protesters	O
from	O
occupy	O
wef	O
,	O
who	O
have	O
captured	O
international	O
attention	O
by	O
building	O
igloos	O
near	O
the	O
site	O
of	O
the	O
global	O
gathering	O
in	O
davos	LOC
,	O
have	O
pulled	O
off	O
another	O
eye-catching	O
stunt	O
.	O
they	O
've	O
released	O
large	O
red	O
balloons	O
carrying	O
a	O
banner	O
that	O
reads	O
:	O
``	O
hey	O
wef	O
!	O
where	O
are	O
the	O
other	O
6.9999	O
billion	O
leaders	O
?	O
''	O
which	O
they	O
hope	O
will	O
float	O
over	O
vips	O
gathered	O
inside	O
the	O
summit	O
cordon	O
.	O
1.05pm	O
:	O
more	O
from	O
jill	PERS
treanor	PERS
,	O
who	O
's	O
been	O
listen	O
to	O
dr	O
doom	PERS
(	O
or	O
,	O
if	O
you	O
prefer	O
,	O
mr	O
gloom	PERS
)	O
.	O
need	O
a	O
bit	O
more	O
gloom	PERS
?	O
where	O
else	O
to	O
go	O
but	O
a	O
session	O
on	O
the	O
``	O
seeds	O
of	O
dystopia	O
''	O
.	O
mr	O
gloom	PERS
himself	O
,	O
nouriel	PERS
roubini	PERS
,	O
is	O
concerned	O
about	O
the	O
disagreements	O
among	O
the	O
world	O
's	O
nations	O
on	O
solving	O
the	O
crisis	O
.	O
his	O
list	O
is	O
endless	O
but	O
begins	O
with	O
'europe	O
says	O
austerity	O
.	O
us	LOC
says	O
stimulus	O
'	O
.	O
on	O
the	O
eurozone	O
,	O
he	O
warns	O
:	O
'the	O
policy	O
response	O
is	O
making	O
the	O
recession	O
worse	O
.	O
what	O
europe	LOC
needs	O
is	O
less	O
austerity	O
and	O
more	O
growth	O
.	O
'	O
philip	PERS
jennings	PERS
,	O
the	O
leader	O
of	O
the	O
global	O
union	O
uni	O
,	O
is	O
blunter	O
:	O
'the	O
eurozone	O
is	O
going	O
too	O
far	O
'	O
.	O
his	O
concern	O
is	O
not	O
just	O
about	O
austerity	O
but	O
about	O
the	O
attitude	O
to	O
workers	O
,	O
particularly	O
in	O
those	O
states	O
where	O
unelected	O
politicans	O
are	O
in	O
charge	O
.	O
'technocrat	O
governments	O
are	O
playing	O
with	O
political	O
gunpowder	O
.	O
this	O
is	O
a	O
warning	O
,	O
'	O
says	O
jennings	PERS
,	O
who	O
also	O
warned	O
that	O
there	O
needs	O
to	O
be	O
a	O
wake-up	O
call	O
about	O
the	O
levels	O
of	O
inequality	O
around	O
the	O
world	O
.	O
the	O
american	O
dream	O
is	O
over	O
,	O
he	O
aruges	O
,	O
because	O
workers	O
have	O
been	O
denied	O
their	O
rights	O
-	O
just	O
6	O
%	O
are	O
covered	O
by	O
collective	O
agreements	O
.	O
'if	O
you	O
take	O
away	O
a	O
worker	O
's	O
voice	O
from	O
the	O
table	O
,	O
do	O
n't	O
be	O
surprised	O
by	O
the	O
consequences	O
you	O
see	O
,	O
'	O
he	O
says	O
,	O
adding	O
that	O
one	O
in	O
three	O
of	O
the	O
people	O
on	O
the	O
planet	O
are	O
unemployed	O
.	O
salil	O
shetty	O
,	O
the	O
london-based	O
secretary	O
general	O
of	O
amnesty	ORG
international	ORG
,	O
agrees	O
.	O
he	O
warns	O
of	O
'explosions	O
'	O
of	O
people	O
furious	O
at	O
the	O
inequalities	O
.	O
'the	O
biggest	O
risk	O
'	O
is	O
failed	O
leadership	O
,	O
says	O
shetty	O
.	O
'seems	O
as	O
if	O
they	O
've	O
been	O
sleeping	O
at	O
the	O
wheel	O
'	O
.	O
jennings	PERS
reckons	O
that	O
,	O
to	O
many	O
,	O
society	O
'looks	O
like	O
a	O
winner	O
take	O
all	O
with	O
the	O
rules	O
rigged	O
to	O
favour	O
the	O
few	O
'	O
.	O
he	O
is	O
also	O
concerned	O
about	O
the	O
levels	O
of	O
homelessness	O
-	O
'if	O
you	O
ca	O
n't	O
provide	O
education	O
,	O
the	O
seeds	O
of	O
dystopia	O
have	O
aready	O
been	O
planted	O
'	O
.	O
'we	O
are	O
anxious	O
to	O
break	O
out	O
of	O
this	O
...	O
'	O
says	O
jennings	PERS
,	O
adding	O
the	O
lack	O
of	O
union	O
recognition	O
is	O
'1984	O
and	O
brave	O
new	O
world-ish'	O
12.39pm	O
:	O
who	O
is	O
n't	O
at	O
the	O
davos	LOC
summit	O
?	O
there	O
's	O
been	O
some	O
comment	O
that	O
the	O
chinese	O
government	O
has	O
failed	O
to	O
send	O
any	O
high-level	O
officials	O
for	O
the	O
first	O
time	O
in	O
30	O
years	O
.	O
but	O
neither	O
the	O
bank	ORG
of	ORG
england	ORG
nor	O
the	O
federal	O
reserve	O
have	O
booked	O
rooms	O
in	O
the	O
belvedere	ORG
either	O
.	O
so	O
how	O
important	O
is	O
actually	O
being	O
there	O
?	O
``	O
if	O
china	LOC
can	O
miss	O
davos	LOC
,	O
why	O
ca	O
n't	O
others	O
?	O
''	O
asks	O
professor	O
simon	PERS
evenett	PERS
,	O
of	O
the	O
university	ORG
of	ORG
st	ORG
gallen	ORG
,	O
in	O
switzerland	LOC
.	O
evenett	PERS
makes	O
a	O
tongue-in-cheek	O
call	O
for	O
merkel	PERS
to	O
forget	O
the	O
opening	O
speech	O
this	O
evening	O
and	O
withdraw	O
from	O
the	O
summit	O
.	O
like	O
the	O
chinese	O
,	O
perhaps	O
mrs	O
merkel	PERS
will	O
want	O
to	O
skip	O
her	O
keynote	O
speech	O
to	O
davos	LOC
.	O
she	O
's	O
bound	O
to	O
get	O
tons	O
of	O
unsolicited	O
advice	O
,	O
especially	O
after	O
the	O
imf	ORG
endorsed	O
measures	O
far	O
beyond	O
berlin	LOC
's	O
latest	O
thinking	O
.	O
perhaps	O
mrs	O
merkel	PERS
will	O
signal	O
a	O
further	O
evolution	O
of	O
her	O
position	O
,	O
making	O
a	O
little	O
clearer	O
what	O
the	O
real	O
deal	O
is	O
on	O
the	O
table	O
between	O
eurozone	O
governments	O
.	O
12.33pm	O
:	O
delegates	O
are	O
now	O
engaging	O
in	O
a	O
'world	O
economic	O
brainstorm	O
'	O
in	O
the	O
main	O
congress	O
hall	O
.	O
here	O
are	O
some	O
of	O
the	O
one-liners	O
:	O
making	O
money	O
is	O
not	O
good	O
enough	O
#	O
wefbrainstormmobile.twitter.com/	O
#	O
!	O
/	O
-	O
manju	O
(	O
@	O
george_manju	O
)	O
january	O
25	O
,	O
2012	O
'we	O
saw	O
an	O
incredible	O
demise	O
in	O
trust	O
in	O
government	O
this	O
year	O
.	O
governments	O
have	O
gone	O
into	O
paralysis	O
.	O
go	O
and	O
lead	O
'	O
#	O
wef	O
#	O
wefbrainstorm	O
-	O
world	O
economic	O
forum	O
(	O
@	O
wef	O
)	O
january	O
25	O
,	O
2012	O
how	O
do	O
we	O
define	O
social	O
value	O
so	O
business	O
can	O
develop	O
a	O
wider	O
concept	O
of	O
'return	O
'	O
from	O
their	O
social	O
initiatives	O
#	O
wefbrainstorm	O
-	O
rapelang	O
rabana	O
(	O
@	O
rapelangrabana	O
)	O
january	O
25	O
,	O
2012	O
we	O
need	O
to	O
redefine	O
capitalism	O
:	O
new	O
,	O
innovative	O
business	O
models	O
are	O
needed	O
for	O
a	O
sustainable	O
future	O
#	O
wefbrainstorm	O
#	O
wef	O
-	O
cristina	PERS
riesen	PERS
(	O
@	O
cristinariesen	O
)	O
january	O
25	O
,	O
2012	O
12.14pm	O
:	O
jill	PERS
treanor	PERS
has	O
been	O
attempting	O
to	O
buttonhole	O
delegates	O
,	O
though	O
lots	O
of	O
them	O
are	O
remaining	O
tight-lipped	O
.	O
she	O
managed	O
to	O
catch	O
up	O
with	O
one	O
or	O
two	O
people	O
with	O
reasonably	O
upbeat	O
takes	O
on	O
the	O
crisis	O
:	O
lots	O
of	O
high	O
profile	O
business	O
figures	O
to	O
bump	O
into	O
here	O
in	O
davos	LOC
,	O
but	O
not	O
all	O
of	O
them	O
want	O
to	O
quoted	O
.	O
but	O
john	PERS
studzinski	PERS
,	O
the	O
senior	O
managing	O
director	O
of	O
venture	O
capitalists	O
blackstone	O
,	O
one-time	O
hsbc	ORG
banker	O
and	O
15-year	O
davos	LOC
veteran	O
,	O
was	O
happy	O
to	O
talk	O
about	O
the	O
state	O
of	O
the	O
economy	O
.	O
it	O
turns	O
out	O
he	O
is	O
relatively	O
upbeat	O
.	O
'the	O
global	O
economy	O
is	O
at	O
a	O
point	O
of	O
enlightened	O
inflection	O
,	O
'	O
he	O
said	O
.	O
he	O
reckons	O
things	O
will	O
turn	O
out	O
relatively	O
positively	O
for	O
the	O
us	LOC
economy	O
,	O
brazil	LOC
will	O
grow	O
at	O
6	O
%	O
and	O
that	O
siemens	ORG
results	O
show	O
that	O
the	O
backbone	O
of	O
the	O
eurozone	O
economy	O
,	O
germany	LOC
,	O
is	O
strong	O
.	O
it	O
is	O
impossible	O
to	O
get	O
away	O
from	O
the	O
significance	O
of	O
the	O
greek	O
restructuring	O
talks	O
,	O
even	O
in	O
davos	LOC
.	O
dionysia-theodora	PERS
avgerinopoulou	PERS
,	O
here	O
as	O
a	O
young	O
global	O
leader	O
,	O
is	O
a	O
greek	O
mp	O
who	O
reckons	O
the	O
talks	O
are	O
'going	O
pretty	O
well	O
'	O
.	O
'the	O
critical	O
point	O
is	O
how	O
high	O
the	O
coupon	O
[	O
interest	O
rate	O
]	O
is	O
going	O
to	O
be	O
on	O
the	O
new	O
bonds	O
,	O
'	O
she	O
told	O
me	O
.	O
as	O
we	O
know	O
,	O
3	O
%	O
is	O
the	O
key	O
level	O
.	O
'we	O
're	O
going	O
to	O
be	O
very	O
close	O
to	O
that	O
.	O
the	O
point	O
is	O
that	O
we	O
also	O
really	O
want	O
voluntary	O
participation	O
[	O
from	O
the	O
existing	O
bond	O
holders	O
]	O
.	O
'	O
she	O
's	O
looking	O
forward	O
to	O
tomorrow	O
when	O
there	O
is	O
a	O
debate	O
on	O
the	O
olympics	O
-	O
she	O
is	O
from	O
that	O
part	O
of	O
greece	LOC
.	O
11.44am	O
:	O
delegates	O
are	O
now	O
enjoying	O
a	O
lunch	O
session	O
with	O
george	PERS
soros	PERS
.	O
just	O
having	O
a	O
spot	O
of	O
lunch	O
with	O
george	PERS
soros	PERS
,	O
as	O
you	O
do	O
in	O
#	O
davos	LOC
#	O
wef	O
-	O
markus	PERS
karlsson	PERS
(	O
@	O
markusf24	O
)	O
january	O
25	O
,	O
2012	O
let	O
's	O
hope	O
what	O
he	O
has	O
to	O
say	O
does	O
n't	O
provoke	O
indigestion	O
:	O
the	O
euro	O
must	O
survive	O
because	O
the	O
alternative	O
,	O
a	O
break-up	O
,	O
would	O
cause	O
a	O
meltdown	O
that	O
europe	LOC
and	O
the	O
world	O
ca	O
n't	O
afford	O
.	O
larry	PERS
elliott	PERS
is	O
in	O
attendance	O
and	O
sent	O
my	O
colleague	O
graeme	PERS
wearden	PERS
his	O
reaction	O
.	O
11.40am	O
:	O
more	O
roubini	PERS
:	O
he	O
's	O
just	O
given	O
an	O
interview	O
to	O
cnbc	O
,	O
and	O
the	O
results	O
are	O
here	O
.	O
the	O
headline	O
is	O
that	O
europe	LOC
needs	O
'massive	O
monetary	O
easing	O
'	O
to	O
get	O
out	O
of	O
its	O
debt	O
crisis	O
-	O
in	O
other	O
words	O
,	O
the	O
european	ORG
central	ORG
bank	ORG
needs	O
to	O
step	O
in	O
and	O
effectively	O
print	O
money	O
,	O
something	O
that	O
angela	PERS
merkel	PERS
has	O
been	O
lobbying	O
hard	O
to	O
prevent	O
.	O
if	O
this	O
does	O
n't	O
happen	O
,	O
roubini	PERS
suggests	O
,	O
greece	LOC
will	O
be	O
likely	O
to	O
abandon	O
the	O
euro	O
in	O
a	O
year	O
and	O
a	O
half	O
.	O
11.17am	O
:	O
we	O
're	O
still	O
waiting	O
for	O
roubini	PERS
to	O
take	O
the	O
stand	O
.	O
in	O
the	O
meantime	O
,	O
richard	PERS
quest	PERS
found	O
him	O
living	O
up	O
to	O
his	O
nickname	O
,	O
dr	O
doom	PERS
:	O
nouriel	PERS
#	O
roubini	PERS
just	O
told	O
me	O
at	O
#	O
davo	O
eurozone	O
is	O
a	O
slow	O
motion	O
train	O
wreck	O
.	O
headingtowards	O
depression	O
if	O
action	O
not	O
taken	O
-	O
richard	PERS
quest	PERS
(	O
@	O
richardquest	O
)	O
january	O
25	O
,	O
2012	O
11.14am	O
:	O
commenter	O
dwearing	O
reminds	O
us	LOC
that	O
there	O
's	O
another	O
global	O
forum	O
taking	O
place	O
right	O
now	O
,	O
designed	O
expressly	O
to	O
provide	O
an	O
alternative	O
to	O
davos	LOC
.	O
the	O
world	O
social	O
forum	O
,	O
in	O
the	O
southern	O
brazilian	O
city	O
of	O
porto	LOC
alegre	LOC
(	O
no	O
snow	O
there	O
)	O
,	O
has	O
attracted	O
around	O
15,000	O
activists	O
.	O
the	O
forum	O
co-ordinator	O
told	O
afp	O
:	O
``	O
the	O
forum	O
was	O
born	O
to	O
challenge	O
the	O
arrogance	O
of	O
the	O
neo-liberals	O
in	O
davos	LOC
.	O
we	O
said	O
clearly	O
that	O
we	O
wanted	O
another	O
world	O
.	O
now	O
we	O
must	O
build	O
the	O
ways	O
,	O
the	O
alternatives	O
.	O
''	O
the	O
brazilian	O
president	O
,	O
dilma	PERS
rousseff	PERS
,	O
is	O
expected	O
to	O
attend	O
.	O
10.56am	O
:	O
a	O
snippet	O
here	O
from	O
jill	PERS
treanor	PERS
,	O
who	O
has	O
been	O
at	O
the	O
summit	O
's	O
opening	O
press	O
conference	O
.	O
in	O
constrast	O
to	O
jeff	PERS
jarvis	PERS
,	O
she	O
says	O
:	O
all	O
the	O
participants	O
here	O
in	O
davos	LOC
are	O
keen	O
to	O
prove	O
they	O
are	O
doing	O
their	O
bit	O
to	O
behave	O
'responsibly	O
'	O
.	O
at	O
a	O
press	O
conference	O
,	O
vikram	PERS
pandit	PERS
,	O
the	O
boss	O
of	O
citigroup	ORG
,	O
reckoned	O
that	O
only	O
yesterday	O
the	O
bank	O
had	O
turned	O
down	O
a	O
customer	O
looking	O
to	O
do	O
a	O
deal	O
with	O
``	O
excessive	O
amounts	O
of	O
leverage	O
''	O
and	O
``	O
in	O
a	O
darwinian	O
world	O
''	O
the	O
client	O
was	O
now	O
looking	O
for	O
other	O
banks	O
to	O
take	O
on	O
the	O
deal	O
.	O
10.34am	O
:	O
here	O
's	O
digital	O
journalism	O
guru	O
jeff	PERS
jarvis	PERS
's	O
take	O
on	O
the	O
apparent	O
lack	O
of	O
contrition	O
from	O
the	O
global	O
financial	O
elite	O
.	O
for	O
the	O
third	O
year	O
in	O
a	O
row	O
at	O
davos	LOC
,	O
i	O
've	O
seen	O
bankers	O
refuse	O
to	O
accept	O
responsibility	O
for	O
their	O
role	O
in	O
the	O
crisis	O
.	O
#	O
wef	O
-	O
jeff	PERS
jarvis	PERS
(	O
@	O
jeffjarvis	O
)	O
january	O
25	O
,	O
2012	O
as	O
dire	O
economic	O
news	O
continues	O
to	O
roll	O
in	O
,	O
the	O
summit	O
is	O
likely	O
to	O
become	O
a	O
lightning	O
rod	O
for	O
resentment	O
-	O
more	O
so	O
given	O
that	O
the	O
effects	O
on	O
real	O
economies	O
have	O
been	O
felt	O
much	O
more	O
keenly	O
by	O
ordinary	O
people	O
over	O
the	O
last	O
year	O
.	O
10.24am	O
:	O
the	O
occupy	O
movement	O
is	O
making	O
its	O
presence	O
felt	O
at	O
the	O
summit	O
,	O
albeit	O
20	O
minutes	O
walk	O
from	O
any	O
of	O
the	O
conference	O
venues	O
.	O
the	O
protesters	O
,	O
many	O
of	O
whom	O
are	O
drawn	O
from	O
the	O
swiss	O
young	O
socialists	O
party	O
,	O
have	O
built	O
igloos	O
rather	O
than	O
pitch	O
tents	O
.	O
reuters	O
filmed	O
them	O
inside	O
their	O
chilly-looking	O
shelters	O
.	O
10.16am	O
:	O
nouriel	PERS
roubini	PERS
will	O
be	O
making	O
a	O
much-anticipated	O
speech	O
at	O
midday	O
-	O
11am	O
uk	LOC
time	O
.	O
i	O
will	O
speak	O
mid-day	O
at	O
the	O
wef	O
in	O
davos	LOC
at	O
the	O
session	O
on	O
``	O
global	O
risks	O
2012	O
:	O
the	O
seeds	O
of	O
dystopia	O
''	O
-	O
nouriel	PERS
roubini	PERS
(	O
@	O
nouriel	PERS
)	O
january	O
25	O
,	O
2012	O
he	O
's	O
the	O
economist	O
widely	O
seen	O
as	O
having	O
predicted	O
the	O
global	O
crash	O
(	O
and	O
dubbed	O
'dr	O
doom	PERS
'	O
as	O
a	O
result	O
)	O
.	O
9.52am	O
:	O
larry	PERS
elliott	PERS
's	O
sent	O
us	LOC
his	O
initial	O
thoughts	O
.	O
the	O
full	O
story	O
's	O
here	O
,	O
and	O
below	O
are	O
some	O
excerpts	O
.	O
the	O
theme	O
that	O
seems	O
to	O
be	O
emerging	O
is	O
one	O
of	O
profound	O
self-scrutiny	O
by	O
the	O
global	O
elite	O
,	O
but	O
doubt	O
that	O
any	O
serious	O
change	O
will	O
be	O
implemented	O
.	O
four	O
years	O
into	O
a	O
brutal	O
recession	O
that	O
has	O
left	O
200	O
million	O
unemployed	O
around	O
the	O
world	O
,	O
and	O
with	O
protest	O
movements	O
occupying	O
public	O
spaces	O
in	O
western	O
cities	O
,	O
there	O
is	O
clearly	O
some	O
soul-searching	O
going	O
on	O
.	O
today	O
's	O
programme	O
in	O
davos	LOC
kicked	O
off	O
with	O
a	O
debate	O
on	O
whether	O
20th	O
century	O
capitalism	O
is	O
failing	O
21st	O
century	O
society	O
.	O
a	O
report	O
on	O
the	O
risks	O
facing	O
the	O
world	O
in	O
2012	O
,	O
to	O
be	O
debated	O
later	O
today	O
,	O
is	O
titled	O
the	O
seeds	O
of	O
dystopia	O
.	O
it	O
notes	O
that	O
many	O
of	O
the	O
indicators	O
of	O
economic	O
and	O
societal	O
health	O
are	O
going	O
in	O
the	O
wrong	O
direction	O
.	O
so	O
,	O
the	O
good	O
news	O
in	O
davos	LOC
is	O
that	O
the	O
right	O
questions	O
are	O
starting	O
to	O
be	O
asked	O
.	O
the	O
extent	O
of	O
the	O
unease	O
about	O
today	O
's	O
toxic	O
mix	O
of	O
unemployment	O
and	O
inequality	O
was	O
demonstrated	O
in	O
a	O
straw	O
poll	O
of	O
those	O
attending	O
the	O
debate	O
on	O
capitalism	O
.	O
it	O
showed	O
that	O
40	O
%	O
thought	O
it	O
was	O
failing	O
21st	O
century	O
society	O
and	O
20	O
%	O
thought	O
it	O
was	O
n't	O
.	O
the	O
bad	O
news	O
is	O
that	O
the	O
appetite	O
for	O
reform	O
is	O
not	O
really	O
there	O
.	O
9.35am	O
:	O
and	O
we	O
've	O
just	O
had	O
uk	LOC
gdp	O
figures	O
in	O
for	O
q4	O
(	O
the	O
last	O
three	O
months	O
)	O
of	O
2011	O
:	O
-0.2	O
%	O
.	O
jill	PERS
treanor	PERS
,	O
in	O
davos	LOC
,	O
tweeted	O
the	O
following	O
reaction	O
:	O
larry	PERS
elliott	PERS
,	O
at	O
#	O
davos	LOC
,	O
tells	O
me	O
the	O
uk	LOC
gdp	O
figs	O
are	O
``	O
extremely	O
weak	O
''	O
and	O
a	O
sign	O
of	O
potential	O
double	O
dip	O
#	O
business	O
-	O
jill	PERS
treanor	PERS
(	O
@	O
jilltreanor	O
)	O
january	O
25	O
,	O
2012	O
it	O
's	O
very	O
unwelcome	O
news	O
for	O
british	O
politicians	O
at	O
the	O
summit	O
,	O
including	O
the	O
chancellor	O
,	O
george	PERS
osborne	PERS
.	O
9.32am	O
:	O
a	O
quick	O
write-up	O
from	O
ap	O
of	O
that	O
time	O
debate	O
on	O
capitalism	O
.	O
apparently	O
david	PERS
rubenstein	PERS
,	O
the	O
co-founder	O
of	O
the	O
carlyle	ORG
group	ORG
,	O
said	O
:	O
capitalism	O
may	O
be	O
the	O
worst	O
form	O
of	O
systems	O
,	O
except	O
for	O
every	O
other	O
system	O
.	O
his	O
co-panellist	O
,	O
sharan	O
burrow	O
,	O
said	O
``	O
we	O
've	O
lost	O
a	O
moral	O
compass	O
''	O
and	O
warned	O
of	O
social	O
unrest	O
.	O
9.18am	O
:	O
my	O
colleague	O
jane	PERS
martinson	PERS
,	O
the	O
guardian	O
's	O
women	O
's	O
editor	O
,	O
sends	O
a	O
blogpost	O
from	O
the	O
summit	O
.	O
despite	O
efforts	O
to	O
increase	O
diversity	O
,	O
it	O
seems	O
``	O
davos	LOC
man	O
''	O
still	O
dominates	O
.	O
to	O
register	O
for	O
this	O
week	O
's	O
world	O
economic	O
forum	O
in	O
davos	LOC
,	O
delegates	O
fill	O
in	O
a	O
profile	O
page	O
pre-set	O
with	O
the	O
silhouette	O
of	O
a	O
shadowy	O
man	O
.	O
a	O
year	O
after	O
imposing	O
a	O
quota	O
on	O
the	O
biggest	O
companies	O
to	O
encourage	O
more	O
women	O
to	O
attend	O
,	O
the	O
image	O
still	O
fits	O
the	O
gender	O
profile	O
of	O
more	O
than	O
80	O
%	O
of	O
delegates	O
.	O
despite	O
the	O
quota	O
,	O
just	O
17	O
%	O
of	O
the	O
gathering	O
of	O
world	O
business	O
,	O
political	O
and	O
campaign	O
are	O
women	O
.	O
this	O
percentage	O
is	O
the	O
highest	O
yet	O
in	O
the	O
40-odd	O
years	O
of	O
the	O
event	O
,	O
up	O
from	O
16	O
%	O
in	O
2011	O
and	O
just	O
9	O
%	O
in	O
2002	O
,	O
but	O
it	O
still	O
gives	O
a	O
handy	O
guide	O
to	O
the	O
headway	O
women	O
have	O
made	O
in	O
penetrating	O
the	O
top	O
of	O
the	O
business	O
,	O
political	O
and	O
media	O
elite	O
.	O
9.06am	O
:	O
the	O
time	O
magazine	O
debate	O
is	O
underway	O
in	O
davos	LOC
(	O
live	O
feed	O
above	O
)	O
.	O
its	O
title	O
-	O
is	O
capitalism	O
failing	O
?	O
-	O
once	O
again	O
chimes	O
with	O
the	O
mood	O
among	O
global	O
policymakers	O
,	O
who	O
are�shaken	O
and	O
casting	O
about	O
for	O
solutions	O
.	O
below	O
is	O
a	O
live	O
feed	O
of	O
the	O
debate	O
,	O
which	O
is	O
chaired	O
by	O
the	O
time	O
international	O
editor	O
,	O
jim	PERS
frederick	PERS
.	O
panellists	O
include	O
sharan	O
burrow	O
,	O
the	O
general	O
secretary	O
of	O
the	O
international	ORG
trade	ORG
union	ORG
confederation	O
in	O
brussels	LOC
,	O
and	O
brian	PERS
t	PERS
moynihan	PERS
,	O
the	O
ceo	O
of	O
bank	ORG
of	ORG
america	ORG
.	O
8.43am	O
:	O
news	O
yesterday	O
that	O
the	O
imf	ORG
was	O
revising	O
its	O
growth	O
figures	O
drastically	O
downwards	O
have	O
cast	O
a	O
pall	O
over	O
davos	LOC
,	O
as	O
larry	PERS
elliott	PERS
explains	O
.	O
it	O
will	O
focus	O
minds	O
at	O
the	O
summit	O
,	O
which	O
is	O
the	O
fifth	O
since	O
the	O
global	O
crisis	O
began	O
.	O
the	O
health	O
of	O
european	O
economies	O
will	O
be	O
a	O
major	O
preoccupation	O
.	O
writing	O
in	O
the	O
wall	O
street	O
journal	O
,	O
stephen	PERS
fidler	PERS
says	O
:	O
the	O
travails	O
of	O
the	O
eurozone	O
seem	O
likely	O
to	O
dominate	O
discussions	O
among	O
the	O
politicians	O
,	O
bankers	O
and	O
senior	O
company	O
executives	O
.	O
some	O
will	O
have	O
questions	O
of	O
great	O
moment	O
,	O
seeking	O
to	O
ascertain	O
,	O
for	O
example	O
,	O
whether	O
the	O
german	O
chancellor	O
,	O
angela	PERS
merkel	PERS
,	O
is	O
softening	O
her	O
opposition	O
to	O
further	O
strengthening	O
of	O
the	O
eurozone	O
's	O
bailout	O
fund	O
.	O
some	O
will	O
seek	O
enlightenment	O
on	O
narrower	O
matters	O
,	O
such	O
as	O
whether	O
they	O
can	O
expect	O
struggling	O
eurozone	O
governments	O
to	O
delay	O
payments	O
for	O
goods	O
and	O
services	O
their	O
companies	O
provide	O
.	O
on	O
a	O
more	O
positive	O
note	O
,	O
he	O
adds	O
:	O
``	O
the	O
general	O
gloom	PERS
about	O
europe	LOC
should	O
be	O
tempered	O
by	O
the	O
more	O
positive	O
mood	O
in	O
emerging	O
economies	O
-	O
even	O
if	O
growth	O
has	O
slowed	O
slightly	O
from	O
recent	O
years	O
.	O
''	O
8.41am	O
:	O
welcome	O
to	O
the	O
guardian	O
's	O
liveblog	O
from	O
the	O
first	O
day	O
of	O
the	O
world	O
economic	O
forum	O
summit	O
in	O
the	O
swiss	O
resort	O
of	O
davos	LOC
.	O
the	O
centrepiece	O
of	O
today	O
's	O
schedule	O
is	O
angela	PERS
merkel	PERS
's	O
opening	O
speech	O
,	O
scheduled	O
for	O
16:30	O
uk	LOC
time	O
.	O
beyond	O
that	O
,	O
there	O
will	O
be	O
meetings	O
and	O
sessions	O
throughout	O
the	O
day	O
-�that	O
curious	O
mix	O
of	O
the	O
official	O
and	O
the	O
fringe	O
for	O
which	O
davos	LOC
is	O
famous	O
.	O
we	O
'll	O
be	O
taking	O
in	O
the	O
highlights	O
with	O
help	O
from	O
guardian	O
writers	O
and	O
editors	O
at	O
the	O
event	O
:	O
alan	PERS
rusbridger	PERS
,	O
larry	PERS
elliott	PERS
,	O
jill	PERS
treanor	PERS
and	O
jane	PERS
martinson	PERS
.	O
orientation	O
first	O
:	O
larry	PERS
's	O
davos	LOC
a-z	O
on	O
the	O
summit	O
goes	O
all	O
the	O
way	O
from	O
anti-globalisation	O
to	O
zoellick	O
.	O
and	O
there	O
's	O
our	O
davos	LOC
keyword	O
page	O
for	O
all	O
the	O
latest	O
news	O
articles	O
.	O
jane	PERS
,	O
jill	PERS
and	O
larry	PERS
also	O
gathered	O
together	O
the	O
thoughts	O
of	O
delegates	O
including	O
cherie	PERS
blair	PERS
,	O
bill	PERS
gates	PERS
and	O
pascal	PERS
lamy	PERS
on	O
the	O
eve	O
of	O
the	O
summit	O
.	O
read	O
them	O
here	O
.	O
and	O
if	O
you	O
're	O
interested	O
in	O
the	O
ongoing	O
eurozone	O
crisis	O
,	O
my	O
colleague	O
graeme	PERS
wearden	PERS
is	O
anchoring	O
a	O
liveblog	O
with	O
all	O
the	O
latest	O
developments	O
here	O
.	O
wo	O
anlegern	O
enteignung	O
droht	O
;	O
die	O
schwellenländer	O
überholen	O
den	O
westen	O
.	O
viele	O
anleger	O
ignorieren	O
politische	O
risiken	O
die	O
schwellenländer	O
erleben	O
derzeit	O
ihr	O
rendezvous	O
mit	O
der	O
weltgeschichte	O
.	O
in	O
diesem	O
jahr	O
wird	O
die	O
wirtschaftskraft	O
aller	O
aufstrebenden	O
nationen	O
größer	O
sein	O
als	O
die	O
der	PERS
industriestaaten	PERS
.	O
das	O
ist	O
einmalig	O
in	O
der	O
neueren	O
geschichte	O
.	O
entsprechend	O
selbstbewusst	O
präsentieren	O
sich	O
china	LOC
,	O
mexiko	O
oder	O
indien	O
auf	O
der	O
weltbühne	O
,	O
entsprechend	O
gieren	O
die	O
anleger	O
nach	O
aktien	O
und	O
anleihen	O
der	O
emerging	O
markets	O
,	O
wollen	O
sie	O
doch	O
am	O
aufstieg	O
mitverdienen	O
.	O
nicht	O
weniger	O
als	O
vier	O
milliarden	O
euro	O
haben	O
beispielsweise	O
deutsche	O
sparer	O
im	O
vergangenen	O
jahr	O
in	O
schwellenländer-fonds	O
gepumpt	O
.	O
augenfällig	O
wurde	O
die	O
neue	O
rangordnung	O
auch	O
beim	O
diesjährigen	O
weltwirtschaftsforum	O
in	O
davos	LOC
.	O
das	O
alpendorf	O
war	O
plakatiert	O
mit	O
werbung	O
von	O
mexiko	O
,	O
indien	O
oder	O
china	LOC
.	O
und	O
die	O
davoser	O
busse	O
und	O
schatzalp-bahn	O
priesen	O
aserbaidschan	O
als	O
„land	O
der	O
zukunft	O
.	O
''	O
doch	O
unter	O
der	O
investmentelite	O
auf	O
dem	O
davoser	O
forum	O
war	O
die	O
stimmung	O
schon	O
deutlich	O
differenzierter	O
.	O
zwar	O
herrschte	O
weitgehend	O
einigkeit	O
,	O
dass	O
sich	O
an	O
den	O
schwellenländer-märkten	O
trotz	O
der	O
teilweise	O
sehr	O
hohen	O
kursgewinne	O
noch	O
keine	O
spekulationsblase	O
gebildet	O
hat	O
.	O
doch	O
investoren	O
müssten	O
nunmehr	O
selektiver	O
vorgehen	O
,	O
wollten	O
sie	O
keine	O
bösen	O
überraschungen	O
erleben	O
.	O
„anleger	O
übersehen	O
die	O
politischen	O
risiken	O
der	O
schwellenländer	O
''	O
,	O
sagte	O
bill	PERS
browder	PERS
,	O
gründer	O
von	O
hermitage	ORG
capital	ORG
management	ORG
,	O
der	O
das	O
geld	O
seiner	O
kunden	O
in	O
den	O
schwellenländern	O
investiert	O
.	O
in	O
sämtlichen	O
emerging	O
markets	O
seien	O
die	O
rechtsstaatlichen	O
normen	O
weit	O
weniger	O
stark	O
verankert	O
als	O
in	O
den	O
westlichen	O
industriestaaten	PERS
.	O
für	O
aktionäre	O
seien	O
insbesondere	O
mangelnde	O
eigentumsrechte	O
eine	O
reale	O
gefahr	O
.	O
„viele	O
investoren	O
investieren	O
nach	O
ihren	O
westlichen	O
prämissen	O
''	O
,	O
hat	O
browder	PERS
beobachtet	O
.	O
„sie	O
treffen	O
konzernchefs	O
aus	O
china	LOC
oder	O
russland	O
.	O
wenn	O
diese	O
einen	O
schicken	O
anzug	O
tragen	O
und	O
ein	O
smartes	O
auftreten	O
an	O
den	O
tag	O
legen	O
,	O
und	O
deren	O
aktien	O
an	O
der	O
börse	O
günstig	O
bewertet	O
sind	O
,	O
greifen	O
sie	O
zu	O
.	O
dass	O
die	O
manager	O
aber	O
ganz	O
schnell	O
von	O
einer	O
regierung	O
entmachtet	O
oder	O
unternehmenswerte	O
kurzerhand	O
verstaatlicht	O
werden	O
können	O
,	O
kommt	O
vielen	O
anlegern	O
nicht	O
in	O
den	O
sinn	O
.	O
''	O
browder	PERS
hat	O
für	O
seine	O
investments	O
einige	O
länder	O
ganz	O
ausgeklammert	O
.	O
beispielsweise	O
hält	O
er	O
russland	O
aus	O
politischen	O
risikogesichtspunkten	O
nicht	O
für	O
investierbar	O
,	O
ebenso	O
wenig	O
wie	O
algerien	O
oder	O
somalia	LOC
.	O
aber	O
auch	O
um	O
china	LOC
macht	O
der	O
erfolgreiche	O
investor	O
einen	O
bogen	O
.	O
all	O
diese	O
länder	O
würden	O
nicht	O
seinen	O
transparenzanforderungen	O
entsprechen	O
.	O
dagegen	O
hält	O
browder	PERS
große	O
stücke	O
auf	O
taiwan	LOC
,	O
korea	LOC
,	O
indien	O
oder	O
die	O
türkei	O
.	O
gerade	ORG
ankara	ORG
habe	O
in	O
den	O
vergangenen	O
jahren	O
erfolgreich	O
die	O
inflation	O
bekämpft	O
,	O
die	O
verschuldung	O
zurückgefahren	O
und	O
damit	O
bei	O
den	O
investoren	O
politische	O
glaubwürdigkeit	O
erzielt	O
.	O
ian	PERS
bremmer	PERS
,	O
gründer	O
der	O
denkfabrik	ORG
eurasia	ORG
group	ORG
,	O
hat	O
die	O
schwellenländer	O
gar	O
auf	O
seine	O
liste	O
der	O
„globalen	O
risiken	O
2013	O
''	O
ganz	O
nach	O
oben	O
gesetzt	O
.	O
investoren	O
sähen	O
die	O
emerging	O
markets	O
zu	O
unkritisch	O
,	O
probleme	O
wie	O
mangelnde	O
politische	O
stabilität	O
würden	O
ausgeblendet	O
.	O
„die	O
risiken	O
eines	O
investments	O
in	O
china	LOC
sind	O
um	O
dimensionen	O
größer	O
als	O
eines	O
in	O
den	O
usa	LOC
''	O
,	O
sagt	O
bremmer	PERS
.	O
er	O
ist	O
skeptisch	O
vor	O
allem	O
für	O
russland	O
oder	O
auch	O
die	O
ukraine	LOC
.	O
russlands	O
ministerpräsident	O
dmitri	O
medwedjew	O
habe	O
in	O
davos	LOC
den	O
schwächsten	O
eindruck	O
aller	O
staatenlenker	O
hinterlassen	O
.	O
„wir	O
müssen	O
aufhören	O
,	O
schwellenländer	O
als	O
gruppe	O
zu	O
sehen	O
,	O
und	O
sollten	O
dazu	O
übergehen	O
,	O
jedes	O
land	O
einzeln	O
zu	O
analysieren	O
''	O
,	O
fordert	O
der	O
politische	O
analyst	O
bremmer	PERS
.	O
eine	O
differenzierung	O
zeigt	O
sich	O
bereits	O
an	O
der	O
börse	O
.	O
während	O
der	O
türkische	O
aktienmarkt	O
seit	O
anfang	O
2012	O
rund	O
70	O
prozent	O
zugelegt	O
hat	O
,	O
schaffte	O
es	O
die	O
börse	O
in	O
johannesburg	O
gerade	O
mal	O
auf	O
17	O
prozent	O
.	O
ukraine-investoren	O
sitzen	O
gar	O
auf	O
verlusten	O
von	O
rund	O
40	O
prozent	O
.	O
das	O
beispiel	O
südafrika	O
zeigt	O
,	O
welche	O
risiken	O
selbst	O
weit	O
entwickelte	O
schwellenländer	O
aufweisen	O
.	O
nach	O
monatelangen	O
teils	O
blutigen	O
streiks	O
in	O
der	O
minenindustrie	O
hat	O
die	O
regierung	O
in	O
pretoria	LOC
damit	O
gedroht	O
,	O
einzelnen	O
konzernen	O
die	O
lizenz	O
zu	O
entziehen	O
,	O
was	O
einer	O
enteignung	O
gleichkommt	O
.	O
daraufhin	O
sind	O
viele	O
investoren	O
aus	O
dem	O
land	O
geflüchtet	O
,	O
der	O
südafrikanische	O
rand	O
hat	O
deutlich	O
an	O
wert	O
verloren	O
und	O
fitch	O
hat	O
das	O
land	O
zurückgestuft	O
.	O
die	O
drohung	O
in	O
südafrika	O
ist	O
kein	O
einzelfall	O
.	O
bereits	O
im	O
vergangenen	O
jahr	O
hatte	O
die	O
regierung	O
in	O
argentinien	O
unternehmen	O
verstaatlicht	O
und	O
damit	O
anleger	O
geschädigt	O
.	O
schwellenländer-anleger	O
tun	O
daher	O
gut	O
daran	O
,	O
ihr	O
geld	O
nicht	O
in	O
einzelnen	O
nationen	O
anzulegen	O
,	O
sondern	O
über	O
fonds	O
zu	O
streuen	O
.	O
aktiv	O
verwaltete	O
aktienfonds	O
bieten	O
potenzial	O
.	O
denn	O
gute	O
fondslenker	O
schaffen	O
es	O
,	O
die	O
indizes	O
zu	O
schlagen	O
,	O
weil	O
sie	O
wie	O
in	O
davos	LOC
die	O
staatenlenker	O
und	O
firmenchefs	O
treffen	O
und	O
sich	O
so	O
die	O
risiken	O
aus	O
nächster	O
nähe	O
anschauen	O
können	O
.	O
sorrell	O
sounds	O
alarm	O
on	O
cut	O
in	O
corporation	O
tax	O
;	O
taxation	O
sir	O
martin	PERS
sorrell	PERS
has	O
warned	O
that	O
george	PERS
osborne	PERS
's	O
decision	O
to	O
cut	O
corporation	O
tax	O
to	O
20	O
per	O
cent	O
in	O
the	O
budget	O
might	O
not	O
be	O
enough	O
to	O
persuade	O
some	O
companies	O
from	O
diverting	O
uk	LOC
profit	O
offshore	O
.	O
``	O
it	O
's	O
become	O
a	O
question	O
of	O
moral	O
choice	O
,	O
''	O
said	O
wpp	O
boss	O
sir	O
martin	PERS
.	O
the	O
68-year-old	O
argued	O
that	O
an	O
international	O
company	O
can	O
still	O
minimise	O
its	O
uk	LOC
taxes	O
by	O
charging	O
royalty	O
and	O
procurement	O
fees	O
to	O
another	O
branch	O
of	O
the	O
company	O
overseas	O
.	O
``	O
you	O
have	O
to	O
make	O
a	O
decision	O
about	O
how	O
aggressive	O
you	O
want	O
to	O
be	O
,	O
within	O
the	O
law	O
.	O
''	O
sir	O
martin	PERS
added	O
that	O
the	O
uk	LOC
government	ORG
could	O
not	O
clamp	O
down	O
on	O
tax	O
avoidance	O
on	O
its	O
own	O
.	O
``	O
it	O
's	O
a	O
global	O
issue	O
,	O
''	O
he	O
said	O
.	O
wpp	O
returned	O
to	O
the	O
uk	LOC
this	O
year	O
after	O
a	O
spell	O
of	O
having	O
its	O
headquarters	O
in	O
dublin	LOC
.	O
sorrell	O
warns	O
cut	O
in	O
tax	O
may	O
not	O
halt	O
firms	O
'	O
offshore	O
move	O
sir	O
martin	PERS
sorrell	PERS
has	O
warned	O
that	O
george	PERS
osborne	PERS
's	O
decision	O
to	O
cut	O
corporation	O
tax	O
to	O
20	O
per	O
cent	O
in	O
the	O
budget	O
may	O
not	O
be	O
enough	O
to	O
persuade	O
some	O
companies	O
from	O
diverting	O
uk	LOC
profit	O
offshore	O
.	O
``	O
it	O
's	O
become	O
a	O
question	O
of	O
moral	O
choice	O
,	O
''	O
said	O
wpp	O
boss	O
sir	O
martin	PERS
.	O
the	O
68-year-old	O
told	O
the	O
independent	O
that	O
an	O
international	O
company	O
can	O
still	O
minimise	O
its	O
uk	LOC
taxes	O
by	O
charging	O
royalty	O
and	O
procurement	O
fees	O
to	O
another	O
branch	O
of	O
the	O
company	O
overseas	O
.	O
``	O
you	O
have	O
to	O
make	O
a	O
decision	O
about	O
how	O
aggressive	O
you	O
want	O
to	O
be	O
,	O
within	O
the	O
law	O
.	O
''	O
however	O
,	O
the	O
advertising	O
chief	O
,	O
who	O
brought	O
wpp	O
back	O
to	O
the	O
uk	LOC
this	O
year	O
after	O
a	O
spell	O
in	O
dublin	LOC
,	O
suggested	O
that	O
mr	O
osborne	PERS
's	O
declaration	O
in	O
the	O
budget	O
that	O
he	O
wanted	O
to	O
name	O
and	O
shame	O
tax	O
avoiders	O
could	O
present	O
a	O
threat	O
for	O
corporations	O
.	O
``	O
in	O
return	O
for	O
reducing	O
the	O
rate	O
,	O
do	O
they	O
[	O
the	O
government	O
]	O
expect	O
companies	O
to	O
pay	O
that	O
rate	O
?	O
''	O
he	O
asked	O
.	O
wpp	O
has	O
been	O
close	O
to	O
the	O
tax	O
avoidance	O
issue	O
as	O
its	O
public	O
relations	O
subsidiary	O
rlm	ORG
finsbury	ORG
advised	O
starbucks	ORG
after	O
it	O
was	O
revealed	O
the	O
coffee	O
giant	O
paid	O
just	O
£8m	O
in	O
uk	LOC
corporation	O
tax	O
on	O
£3bn	O
of	O
sales	O
over	O
14	O
years	O
.	O
starbucks	ORG
volunteered	O
to	O
pay	O
£10m	O
in	O
tax	O
for	O
the	O
next	O
two	O
years	O
following	O
a	O
public	O
outcry	O
.	O
sir	O
martin	PERS
added	O
that	O
the	O
uk	LOC
government	ORG
could	O
not	O
clamp	O
down	O
on	O
tax	O
avoidance	O
on	O
its	O
own	O
.	O
``	O
it	O
's	O
a	O
global	O
issue	O
,	O
''	O
he	O
said	O
.	O
american	O
tech	O
firms	O
including	O
google	ORG
,	O
amazon	ORG
and	O
apple	ORG
have	O
come	O
under	O
fire	O
for	O
funnelling	O
some	O
of	O
their	O
revenues	O
from	O
the	O
uk	LOC
and	O
elsewhere	O
in	O
europe	LOC
via	O
low-tax	O
jurisdictions	O
such	O
as	O
ireland	LOC
and	O
luxembourg	LOC
.	O
anti-hunger	O
campaign	O
'if	O
'	O
launches	O
with	O
call	O
for	O
g8	O
to	O
act	O
full	O
text	O
a	O
coalition	O
of	O
100	O
uk	LOC
development	O
charities	O
and	O
faith	O
groups	O
will	O
on	O
wednesday	O
launch	O
a	O
major	O
campaign	O
to	O
lobby	O
david	PERS
cameron	PERS
,	O
the	O
prime	O
minister	O
,	O
to	O
use	O
britain	LOC
's	O
presidency	O
of	O
the	O
g8	O
to	O
leverage	O
action	O
on	O
ending	O
global	O
hunger	O
.	O
the	O
if	O
campaign	O
is	O
the	O
largest	O
coalition	O
of	O
its	O
kind	O
since	O
make	O
poverty	O
history	O
in	O
2005	O
,	O
the	O
last	O
time	O
britain	LOC
held	O
the	O
g8	O
presidency	O
.	O
but	O
this	O
time	O
,	O
organisers	O
are	O
pushing	O
for	O
more	O
radical	O
change	O
.	O
although	O
pegged	O
around	O
hunger	O
and	O
malnutrition	O
,	O
the	O
campaign	O
focuses	O
more	O
on	O
addressing	O
the	O
underlying	O
causes	O
of	O
hunger	O
,	O
such	O
as	O
``	O
land	O
grabs	O
''	O
,	O
tax	O
avoidance	O
and	O
a	O
lack	O
of	O
transparency	O
over	O
investments	O
in	O
poor	O
countries	O
.	O
as	O
well	O
as	O
more	O
money	O
for	O
nutrition	O
programmes	O
and	O
small-scale	O
farming	O
,	O
the	O
coalition	O
,	O
which	O
includes	O
oxfam	O
,	O
save	O
the	O
children	O
,	O
one	O
,	O
christian	O
aid	O
and	O
tearfund	O
,	O
is	O
calling	O
on	O
the	O
uk	LOC
government	O
to	O
close	O
loopholes	O
that	O
allow	O
companies	O
to	O
dodge	O
paying	O
tax	O
in	O
poor	O
countries	O
;	O
stop	O
international	O
land	O
deals	O
that	O
are	O
detrimental	O
to	O
people	O
and	O
the	O
environment	O
,	O
and	O
lobby	O
the	O
world	ORG
bank	ORG
to	O
review	O
the	O
impact	O
of	O
its	O
funding	O
for	O
such	O
deals	O
;	O
launch	O
a	O
convention	O
on	O
tax	O
transparency	O
at	O
the	O
g8	O
to	O
``	O
reinvigorate	O
the	O
global	O
challenge	O
to	O
tax	O
havens	O
''	O
;	O
and	O
force	O
governments	O
and	O
investors	O
to	O
be	O
more	O
open	O
about	O
their	O
investments	O
in	O
poor	O
countries	O
.	O
it	O
also	O
wants	O
the	O
uk	LOC
government	O
to	O
bring	O
forward	O
legislation	O
to	O
enshrine	O
the	O
commitment	O
to	O
spend	O
0.7	O
%	O
of	O
gni	O
on	O
aid	O
.	O
cameron	PERS
has	O
already	O
promised	O
to	O
put	O
hunger	O
,	O
tax	O
and	O
transparency	O
on	O
the	O
agenda	O
at	O
the	O
g8	O
.	O
despite	O
huge	O
strides	O
in	O
reducing	O
poverty	O
and	O
hunger	O
over	O
the	O
past	O
10	O
years	O
-	O
the	O
un	ORG
is	O
confident	O
the	O
millennium	O
development	O
goal	O
to	O
halve	O
the	O
number	O
of	O
people	O
experiencing	O
hunger	O
can	O
be	O
achieved	O
by	O
2015	O
-	O
one	O
in	O
eight	O
people	O
go	O
to	O
bed	O
hungry	O
every	O
night	O
,	O
and	O
each	O
year	O
2.3	O
million	O
children	O
die	O
from	O
malnutrition	O
.	O
in	O
a	O
report	O
published	O
to	O
coincide	O
with	O
the	O
launch	O
,	O
enough	O
food	O
for	O
everyone	O
if	O
,	O
campaigners	O
estimate	O
that	O
28	O
%	O
of	O
children	O
in	O
developing	O
countries	O
are	O
underweight	O
or	O
stunted	O
.	O
land	O
deals	O
have	O
been	O
particularly	O
damaging	O
to	O
food	O
security	O
,	O
as	O
around	O
two-thirds	O
of	O
investors	O
export	O
what	O
they	O
grow	O
or	O
use	O
land	O
to	O
cultivate	O
crops	O
for	O
biofuels	O
rather	O
than	O
for	O
local	O
consumption	O
.	O
more	O
than	O
half	O
of	O
global	O
land	O
acquisitions	O
are	O
estimated	O
to	O
be	O
used	O
for	O
biofuel	O
crops	O
rather	O
than	O
food	O
.	O
according	O
to	O
the	O
report	O
,	O
land	O
used	O
to	O
produce	O
eu	LOC
biofuels	O
in	O
2008	O
could	O
have	O
been	O
used	O
to	O
grow	O
enough	O
food	O
to	O
feed	O
127	O
million	O
people	O
.	O
campaigners	O
are	O
calling	O
on	O
the	O
uk	LOC
to	O
follow	O
positive	O
words	O
about	O
the	O
impact	O
of	O
tax	O
avoidance	O
on	O
poor	O
countries	O
with	O
effective	O
action	O
.	O
the	O
campaign	O
,	O
which	O
is	O
backed	O
by	O
desmond	PERS
tutu	PERS
and	O
bill	PERS
gates	PERS
,	O
kicks	O
off	O
on	O
wednesday	O
evening	O
with	O
events	O
across	O
the	O
uk	LOC
.	O
celebrities	O
,	O
including	O
the	O
actor	O
bill	PERS
nighy	PERS
,	O
athlete	O
and	O
tv	O
presenter	O
colin	PERS
jackson	PERS
and	O
singer	O
baaba	O
maal	O
,	O
are	O
expected	O
to	O
attend	O
the	O
london	LOC
launch	O
.	O
organisers	O
hope	O
to	O
reach	O
20	O
million	O
people	O
in	O
the	O
uk	LOC
through	O
the	O
campaign	O
,	O
and	O
will	O
tap	O
into	O
existing	O
civil	O
society	O
networks	O
around	O
the	O
world	O
that	O
are	O
already	O
campaigning	O
on	O
these	O
issues	O
.	O
further	O
events	O
are	O
expected	O
to	O
take	O
place	O
leading	O
up	O
to	O
the	O
g8	O
in	O
june	O
,	O
including	O
demonstrations	O
in	O
london	LOC
and	O
northern	LOC
ireland	LOC
over	O
the	O
weekend	O
of	O
the	O
summit	O
.	O
the	O
campaign	O
is	O
expected	O
to	O
continue	O
into	O
the	O
autumn	O
to	O
incorporate	O
world	O
food	O
day	O
and	O
lobby	O
the	O
un	ORG
general	O
assembly	O
in	O
september	O
,	O
when	O
a	O
new	O
set	O
of	O
post-2015	O
development	O
goals	O
are	O
due	O
to	O
be	O
discussed	O
.	O
organisers	O
hope	O
the	O
if	O
campaign	O
will	O
emulate	O
the	O
success	O
of	O
make	O
poverty	O
history	O
,	O
which	O
mobilised	O
millions	O
of	O
people	O
around	O
the	O
world	O
.	O
however	O
,	O
the	O
global	O
economic	O
downturn	O
and	O
aid	O
fatigue	O
may	O
lessen	O
the	O
impact	O
.	O
make	O
poverty	O
history	O
,	O
which	O
called	O
for	O
more	O
aid	O
,	O
debt	O
cancellation	O
and	O
trade	O
justice	O
,	O
did	O
achieve	O
results	O
.	O
the	O
g8	O
promised	O
an	O
extra	O
$	O
48bn	O
a	O
year	O
in	O
aid	O
by	O
2010	O
and	O
$	O
1bn	O
a	O
year	O
of	O
debt	O
was	O
dropped	O
for	O
18	O
of	O
the	O
most	O
highly	O
indebted	O
countries	O
,	O
and	O
renewed	O
its	O
commitment	O
to	O
spend	O
0.7	O
%	O
of	O
gni	O
on	O
aid	O
.	O
but	O
critics	O
argued	O
that	O
what	O
was	O
achieved	O
did	O
not	O
go	O
far	O
enough	O
and	O
,	O
years	O
later	O
,	O
some	O
of	O
these	O
commitments	O
have	O
still	O
to	O
be	O
translated	O
into	O
action	O
.	O
the	O
uk	LOC
is	O
expected	O
to	O
achieve	O
0.7	O
%	O
this	O
year	O
.	O
max	PERS
lawson	PERS
,	O
head	O
of	O
advocacy	O
and	O
public	O
policy	O
at	O
oxfam	O
gb	O
,	O
said	O
:	O
``	O
the	O
issues	O
that	O
we	O
are	O
pushing	O
,	O
tax	O
dodging	O
and	O
land	O
grabs	O
in	O
particular	O
,	O
are	O
more	O
radical	O
than	O
the	O
agenda	O
of	O
make	O
poverty	O
history	O
,	O
which	O
was	O
debt	O
cancellation	O
,	O
which	O
was	O
broadly	O
accepted	O
by	O
governments	O
.	O
''	O
he	O
added	O
that	O
action	O
by	O
the	O
g8	O
on	O
tax	O
and	O
land	O
grabs	O
could	O
have	O
a	O
major	O
impact	O
.	O
``	O
there	O
are	O
clear	O
unilateral	O
steps	O
the	O
uk	LOC
government	O
could	O
take	O
,	O
for	O
example	O
closing	O
down	O
tax	O
loopholes	O
,	O
where	O
the	O
uk	LOC
has	O
a	O
lot	O
of	O
influence	O
.	O
beyond	O
that	O
we	O
need	O
to	O
see	O
leadership	O
from	O
the	O
g8	O
.	O
on	O
the	O
issues	O
of	O
biofuels	O
,	O
if	O
europe	LOC
and	O
the	O
us	LOC
decide	O
to	O
act	O
,	O
that	O
would	O
fix	O
the	O
problem	O
globally	O
.	O
''	O
western	O
economics	O
are	O
not	O
for	O
us	LOC
,	O
say	O
developing	O
nations	O
;	O
eurozone	O
crisis	O
and	O
rising	O
debts	O
point	O
to	O
failure	O
,	O
writes	O
philip	O
aldrick	O
davos	LOC
2013	O
2013	O
telegraph.co.uk/davos	O
western	O
leaders	O
will	O
be	O
told	O
their	O
economic	O
model	O
has	O
failed	O
when	O
they	O
gather	O
this	O
week	O
for	O
the	O
annual	O
world	O
economic	O
forum	O
in	O
davos	LOC
.	O
;	O
the	O
crisis	O
in	O
the	O
eurozone	O
,	O
the	O
us	LOC
``	O
fiscal	O
cliff	O
''	O
,	O
japan	LOC
's	O
latest	O
public	O
spending	O
stimulus	O
programme	O
,	O
weak	O
growth	O
and	O
rocketing	O
national	O
debts	O
will	O
be	O
used	O
as	O
evidence	O
that	O
the	O
path	O
to	O
stable	O
longterm	O
prosperity	O
is	O
not	O
the	O
one	O
that	O
has	O
been	O
trodden	O
by	O
the	O
west	O
over	O
the	O
past	O
quarter	O
of	O
a	O
century	O
.	O
;	O
developing	O
nations	O
will	O
put	O
the	O
case	O
against	O
the	O
western	O
model	O
as	O
1,500	O
politicians	O
,	O
business	O
leaders	O
,	O
economists	O
,	O
environmentalists	O
,	O
philanthropists	O
and	O
actors	O
debate	O
potential	O
solutions	O
to	O
the	O
world	O
's	O
economic	O
woes	O
at	O
the	O
swiss	O
ski	O
resort	O
.	O
the	O
theme	O
of	O
this	O
year	O
's	O
meeting	O
is	O
``	O
resilient	O
dynamism	O
''	O
,	O
a	O
philosophy	O
that	O
the	O
wef	ORG
's	O
founder	O
klaus	PERS
schwab	PERS
described	O
as	O
moving	O
on	O
from	O
agonising	O
about	O
current	O
problems	O
to	O
looking	O
``	O
at	O
the	O
future	O
in	O
a	O
much	O
more	O
positive	O
way	O
''	O
.	O
;	O
he	O
has	O
called	O
for	O
a	O
``	O
spirit	O
of	O
global	O
citizenship	O
''	O
and	O
co-operation	O
to	O
restore	O
dwindling	O
public	O
faith	O
in	O
politics	O
and	O
business	O
.	O
``	O
there	O
is	O
a	O
fatigue	O
now	O
in	O
globalism	O
,	O
even	O
a	O
backlash	O
,	O
''	O
he	O
said	O
.	O
``	O
the	O
future	O
of	O
the	O
world	O
economy	O
is	O
based	O
on	O
restoring	O
trust	O
in	O
our	O
leaders	O
.	O
''	O
;	O
growth	O
will	O
be	O
the	O
key	O
issue	O
on	O
the	O
agenda	O
,	O
but	O
the	O
environment	O
,	O
food	O
security	O
,	O
energy	O
and	O
technology	O
will	O
be	O
important	O
themes	O
.	O
other	O
topics	O
under	O
discussion	O
will	O
include	O
the	O
arab	O
spring	O
,	O
the	O
future	O
of	O
digital	O
infrastructure	O
and	O
the	O
role	O
of	O
women	O
in	O
the	O
economy	O
.	O
;	O
the	O
continuing	O
threat	O
of	O
a	O
break	O
up	O
of	O
the	O
single	O
currency	O
bloc	O
is	O
likely	O
to	O
smoulder	O
in	O
the	O
background	O
of	O
much	O
of	O
the	O
economic	O
discussion	O
.	O
german	O
chancellor	O
angela	PERS
merkel	PERS
and	O
her	O
finance	O
minister	O
wolfgang	PERS
schaeuble	PERS
are	O
attending	O
,	O
as	O
are	O
italy	LOC
's	O
outgoing	O
prime	O
minister	O
mario	PERS
monti	PERS
and	O
mario	PERS
draghi	PERS
,	O
president	O
of	O
the	O
european	ORG
central	ORG
bank	ORG
.	O
a	O
number	O
of	O
open	O
debates	O
on	O
the	O
euro	O
are	O
scheduled	O
,	O
with	O
mr	O
draghi	PERS
poised	O
to	O
steal	O
the	O
limelight	O
.	O
;	O
discussion	O
is	O
likely	O
to	O
be	O
more	O
upbeat	O
than	O
recently	O
as	O
reforms	O
in	O
spain	LOC
,	O
portugal	LOC
and	O
italy	LOC
begin	O
to	O
take	O
effect	O
.	O
the	O
countries	O
are	O
becoming	O
more	O
competitive	O
,	O
although	O
growth	O
remains	O
dismal	O
.	O
;	O
britain	LOC
's	O
relationship	O
with	O
europe	LOC
will	O
also	O
be	O
a	O
live	O
debate	O
,	O
with	O
david	PERS
cameron	PERS
and	O
george	PERS
osborne	PERS
both	O
due	O
to	O
speak	O
on	O
thursday	O
.	O
;	O
a	O
number	O
of	O
panel	O
discussions	O
will	O
touch	O
on	O
the	O
subject	O
of	O
fixing	O
the	O
west	O
.	O
incoming	O
bank	ORG
of	ORG
england	ORG
governor	O
mark	PERS
carney	PERS
,	O
international	ORG
monetary	ORG
fund	ORG
managing	O
director	O
christine	PERS
lagarde	PERS
and	O
mr	O
schaeuble	PERS
will	O
be	O
reviewing	O
the	O
global	O
economic	O
outlook	O
on	O
saturday	O
.	O
;	O
before	O
then	O
,	O
economic	O
luminaries	O
such	O
as	O
former	O
monetary	ORG
policy	ORG
committee	ORG
member	O
adam	PERS
posen	PERS
and	O
harvard	O
's	O
ken	PERS
rogoff	PERS
will	O
search	O
for	O
a	O
new	O
``	O
way	O
forward	O
''	O
in	O
economics	O
and	O
``	O
sustainable	O
growth	O
''	O
,	O
and	O
former	O
us	LOC
treasury	O
secretary	O
larry	PERS
summers	PERS
will	O
set	O
out	O
a	O
future	O
for	O
capitalism	O
.	O
two	O
separate	O
debates	O
have	O
been	O
arranged	O
on	O
central	O
bank	O
policy	O
,	O
and	O
whether	O
a	O
new	O
structure	O
will	O
be	O
needed	O
for	O
the	O
new	O
economy	O
.	O
;	O
china	LOC
will	O
be	O
a	O
dominant	O
presence	O
,	O
with	O
a	O
large	O
delegation	O
and	O
several	O
speakers	O
attempting	O
to	O
make	O
sure	O
their	O
ideas	O
are	O
heard	O
.	O
one	O
message	O
likely	O
to	O
be	O
made	O
loud	O
and	O
clear	O
is	O
that	O
the	O
developing	O
world	O
will	O
not	O
be	O
making	O
the	O
same	O
welfare	O
,	O
pension	O
and	O
spending	O
promises	O
as	O
those	O
seen	O
in	O
the	O
west	O
.	O
;	O
tax	O
avoidance	O
and	O
the	O
libor	O
scandals	O
have	O
fuelled	O
a	O
growing	O
distrust	O
of	O
business	O
,	O
the	O
resolution	O
of	O
which	O
will	O
be	O
a	O
key	O
topic	O
.	O
unilever	ORG
chief	O
executive	O
paul	PERS
polman	PERS
has	O
said	O
that	O
companies	O
now	O
have	O
to	O
demonstrate	O
that	O
they	O
are	O
working	O
for	O
the	O
greater	O
good	O
of	O
society	O
.	O
panels	O
have	O
been	O
convened	O
on	O
leadership	O
and	O
values	O
as	O
well	O
as	O
``	O
the	O
evolving	O
role	O
of	O
business	O
''	O
and	O
``	O
banks	O
in	O
the	O
real	O
economy	O
''	O
.	O
;	O
wpp	O
chief	O
executive	O
sir	O
martin	PERS
sorrell	PERS
,	O
standard	O
chartered	O
boss	O
peter	PERS
sands	PERS
and	O
douglas	PERS
flint	PERS
,	O
the	O
hsbc	ORG
chairman	O
,	O
will	O
be	O
representing	O
the	O
uk	LOC
.	O
;	O
equality	O
is	O
another	O
persistent	O
theme	O
at	O
davos	LOC
.	O
in	O
its	O
recent	O
global	O
risks	O
survey	O
,	O
the	O
wef	ORG
identified	O
income	O
disparity	O
as	O
one	O
of	O
the	O
obstacles	O
to	O
sustainable	O
growth	O
and	O
the	O
topic	O
is	O
up	O
for	O
discussion	O
among	O
leading	O
economists	O
.	O
oxfam	O
claimed	O
at	O
the	O
weekend	O
that	O
the	O
world	O
's	O
richest	O
100	O
people	O
earned	O
enough	O
last	O
year	O
to	O
end	O
extreme	O
poverty	O
for	O
the	O
world	O
's	O
poorest	O
people	O
four	O
times	O
over	O
.	O
an	O
``	O
explosion	O
in	O
extreme	O
wealth	O
''	O
was	O
hindering	O
efforts	O
to	O
tackle	O
poverty	O
,	O
it	O
added	O
.	O
power	O
brokers	O
;	O
mark	PERS
carney	PERS
since	O
being	O
announced	O
as	O
the	O
surprise	O
choice	O
to	O
become	O
the	O
new	O
bank	ORG
of	ORG
england	ORG
governor	O
from	O
the	O
end	O
of	O
june	O
,	O
mark	PERS
carney	PERS
has	O
given	O
little	O
away	O
-	O
other	O
than	O
suggesting	O
economic	O
output	O
should	O
be	O
an	O
official	O
target	O
rather	O
than	O
inflation	O
.	O
any	O
pronouncements	O
made	O
at	O
davos	LOC
,	O
therefore	O
,	O
will	O
be	O
seized	O
upon	O
as	O
his	O
blueprint	O
for	O
fixing	O
britain	LOC
's	O
broken	O
banking	O
system	O
over	O
his	O
five	O
years	O
in	O
charge	O
.	O
as	O
chair	O
of	O
the	O
financial	ORG
stability	ORG
board	O
,	O
the	O
former	O
goldman	ORG
sachs	ORG
banker	O
is	O
perceived	O
as	O
a	O
pragmatic	O
economist	O
in	O
tune	O
with	O
the	O
postcrisis	O
culture	O
of	O
regulated	O
ethical	O
banking	O
.	O
;	O
lloyd	PERS
blankfein	PERS
this	O
year	O
's	O
appearance	O
at	O
davos	LOC
will	O
mark	O
the	O
first	O
time	O
the	O
goldman	ORG
sachs	ORG
chairman	O
and	O
chief	O
executive	O
has	O
attended	O
the	O
summit	O
since	O
the	O
start	O
of	O
the	O
financial	O
crisis	O
in	O
2008	O
.	O
joined	O
by	O
his	O
number	O
two	O
,	O
gary	O
cohn	O
,	O
goldman	ORG
's	O
chief	O
is	O
not	O
due	O
to	O
speak	O
at	O
davos	LOC
,	O
but	O
his	O
planned	O
appearance	O
is	O
being	O
taken	O
by	O
some	O
as	O
a	O
bellwether	O
for	O
global	O
banking	O
.	O
with	O
blankfein	O
at	O
the	O
table	O
,	O
economists	O
can	O
be	O
reassured	O
the	O
power	O
broker	O
is	O
committed	O
to	O
the	O
summit	O
's	O
programme	O
of	O
generating	O
stable	O
growth	O
.	O
;	O
mario	PERS
draghi	PERS
the	O
president	O
of	O
the	O
european	ORG
central	ORG
bank	ORG
will	O
bring	O
to	O
davos	LOC
the	O
new	O
mood	O
of	O
optimism	O
over	O
europe	LOC
's	O
future	O
that	O
has	O
started	O
to	O
sustain	O
shoots	O
in	O
2013	O
.	O
draghi	PERS
is	O
not	O
billed	O
as	O
a	O
speaker	O
,	O
but	O
his	O
reports	O
of	O
an	O
improving	O
european	O
currency	O
will	O
have	O
enormous	O
influence	O
on	O
those	O
banking	O
leaders	O
who	O
absorb	O
his	O
reports	O
from	O
the	O
centre	O
of	O
europe	LOC
's	O
debt	O
crisis	O
.	O
this	O
month	O
,	O
draghi	PERS
told	O
a	O
frankfurt	LOC
conference	O
that	O
any	O
chance	O
of	O
a	O
member	O
state	O
leaving	O
the	O
eu	LOC
is	O
a	O
remote	O
possibility	O
.	O
;	O
david	PERS
cameron	PERS
when	O
the	O
prime	O
minister	O
arrived	O
in	O
davos	LOC
last	O
year	O
,	O
he	O
launched	O
an	O
attack	O
on	O
europe	LOC
for	O
failing	O
to	O
deal	O
with	O
its	O
financial	O
crisis	O
,	O
warning	O
that	O
the	O
euro	O
did	O
not	O
have	O
the	O
qualities	O
of	O
a	O
successful	O
single	O
currency	O
.	O
this	O
year	O
,	O
the	O
theme	O
of	O
britain	LOC
's	O
fractious	O
relations	O
with	O
the	O
eu	LOC
will	O
continue	O
to	O
dominate	O
his	O
address	O
,	O
after	O
last	O
friday	O
's	O
postponed	O
speech	O
in	O
which	O
he	O
planned	O
to	O
tackle	O
``	O
growing	O
frustration	O
''	O
with	O
the	O
eu	LOC
.	O
front	O
:	O
the	O
week	O
ahead	O
:	O
inequality	O
is	O
on	O
the	O
davos	LOC
agenda	O
,	O
says	O
larry	O
elliott	O
>	O
=for	O
51	O
weeks	O
of	O
the	O
year	O
,	O
davos	LOC
is	O
just	O
another	O
swiss	O
mountain	O
resort	O
,	O
an	O
architecturally	O
drab	O
strip	O
town	O
5,000	O
feet	O
up	O
in	O
the	O
alps	O
.	O
but	O
at	O
the	O
end	O
of	O
january	O
the	O
world	O
's	O
movers	O
and	O
shakers	O
arrive	O
for	O
five	O
days	O
of	O
chin-wagging	O
,	O
deal-making	O
and	O
partying	O
at	O
the	O
annual	O
get-together	O
of	O
the	O
world	O
economic	O
forum	O
.	O
the	O
2,500	O
participants	O
this	O
year	O
include	O
almost	O
40	O
heads	O
of	O
state	O
and	O
government	O
,	O
finance	O
ministers	O
,	O
central	O
bank	O
governors	O
,	O
scientists	O
,	O
artists	O
,	O
trade	O
unionists	O
,	O
anti-poverty	O
campaigners	O
and	O
,	O
of	O
course	O
,	O
the	O
highest	O
concentration	O
of	O
billionaires	O
on	O
the	O
planet	O
.	O
angela	PERS
merkel	PERS
,	O
david	PERS
cameron	PERS
and	O
russian	O
prime	O
minister	O
dmitry	PERS
medvedev	PERS
are	O
among	O
the	O
keynote	O
speakers	O
.	O
mali	LOC
,	O
the	O
middle	LOC
east	LOC
,	O
europe	LOC
's	O
debt	O
crisis	O
and	O
the	O
us	LOC
fiscal	O
cliff	O
will	O
be	O
on	O
the	O
agenda	O
.	O
george	PERS
osborne	PERS
is	O
due	O
to	O
be	O
in	O
town	O
when	O
britain	LOC
's	O
fourth-quarter	O
growth	O
figures	O
are	O
released	O
on	O
friday	O
.	O
on	O
the	O
basis	O
of	O
the	O
latest	O
evidence	O
,	O
it	O
may	O
be	O
more	O
bad	O
news	O
for	O
the	O
chancellor	O
.	O
>	O
=expect	O
coverage	O
of	O
the	O
43rd	O
meeting	O
of	O
the	O
forum	O
to	O
be	O
peppered	O
with	O
references	O
to	O
thomas	PERS
mann	PERS
,	O
who	O
put	O
davos	LOC
on	O
the	O
map	O
with	O
his	O
book	O
the	O
magic	O
mountain	O
.	O
the	O
story	O
,	O
set	O
in	O
a	O
sanitorium	O
treating	O
patients	O
suffering	O
from	O
tuberculosis	O
,	O
provides	O
an	O
appropriate	O
metaphor	O
for	O
the	O
global	O
economy	O
still	O
ailing	O
nearly	O
five	O
years	O
after	O
the	O
collapse	O
of	O
lehman	ORG
brothers	ORG
.	O
is	O
global	O
capitalism	O
going	O
through	O
a	O
prolonged	O
period	O
of	O
convalescence	O
or	O
is	O
it	O
suffering	O
from	O
an	O
incurable	O
sickness	O
?	O
most	O
of	O
the	O
chief	O
executives	O
and	O
policy-makers	O
will	O
,	O
unsurprisingly	O
,	O
opt	O
for	O
the	O
former	O
but	O
the	O
davos	LOC
mood	O
is	O
much	O
more	O
sombre	O
than	O
it	O
was	O
in	O
the	O
boom	O
years	O
before	O
the	O
crash	O
.	O
now	O
the	O
biggest	O
global	O
risk	O
is	O
deemed	O
to	O
be	O
rising	O
inequality	O
.	O
>	O
=ian	O
fleming	O
was	O
another	O
author	O
familiar	O
with	O
the	O
town	O
.	O
in	O
his	O
novel	O
on	O
her	O
majesty	O
's	O
secret	O
service	O
,	O
bond	O
flies	O
up	O
the	O
davos	LOC
valley	O
to	O
blofeld	O
's	O
mountain-top	O
lair	O
by	O
helicopter	O
-	O
the	O
mode	O
of	O
transport	O
favoured	O
by	O
world	O
leaders	O
and	O
those	O
masters	O
of	O
the	O
universe	O
who	O
are	O
not	O
just	O
rich	O
but	O
seriously	O
loaded	O
.	O
for	O
lesser	O
mortals	O
,	O
there	O
are	O
two	O
choices	O
:	O
road	O
or	O
rail	O
.	O
the	O
journey	O
by	O
coach	O
or	O
limo	O
is	O
quicker	O
,	O
but	O
the	O
three-hour	O
train	O
ride	O
is	O
a	O
real	O
delight	O
.	O
the	O
last	O
hour	O
on	O
the	O
mountain	O
track	O
from	O
landquart	O
is	O
one	O
of	O
the	O
great	O
rail	O
experiences	O
,	O
particularly	O
in	O
late	O
afternoon	O
when	O
the	O
sun	O
is	O
setting	O
over	O
the	O
alps	O
.	O
needless	O
to	O
say	O
,	O
the	O
trains	O
keep	O
running	O
when	O
it	O
is	O
snowing	O
.	O
>	O
=there	O
was	O
a	O
time	O
when	O
organised	O
labour	O
was	O
not	O
welcome	O
at	O
davos	LOC
,	O
which	O
as	O
recently	O
as	O
the	O
1990s	O
was	O
an	O
employers-only	O
affair	O
.	O
union	O
leaders	O
used	O
to	O
hold	O
a	O
press	O
conference	O
in	O
the	O
hotel	O
next	O
to	O
the	O
conference	O
centre	O
but	O
are	O
now	O
included	O
as	O
part	O
of	O
the	O
family	O
along	O
with	O
development	O
charities	O
such	O
as	O
oxfam	O
and	O
thinktanks	O
such	O
as	O
the	O
new	ORG
economics	ORG
foundation	ORG
.	O
philip	PERS
jennings	PERS
,	O
general	O
secretary	O
of	O
the	O
global	O
union	O
uni	O
,	O
says	O
union	O
concerns	O
are	O
taken	O
seriously	O
by	O
klaus	PERS
schwab	PERS
,	O
the	O
man	O
who	O
founded	O
the	O
wef	O
in	O
1971	O
and	O
still	O
presides	O
over	O
its	O
annual	O
meeting	O
.	O
despite	O
lacking	O
only	O
the	O
white	O
cat	O
to	O
be	O
a	O
blofeld	O
lookalike	O
,	O
schwab	PERS
champions	O
what	O
he	O
calls	O
inclusive	O
globalisation	O
.	O
>	O
=some	O
,	O
though	O
,	O
are	O
more	O
included	O
than	O
others	O
.	O
status	O
in	O
davos	LOC
is	O
denoted	O
by	O
your	O
badge	O
:	O
full	O
participants	O
get	O
a	O
white	O
badge	O
with	O
a	O
blue	O
line	O
;	O
their	O
spouses	O
get	O
a	O
plain	O
white	O
badge	O
.	O
journalists	O
who	O
are	O
deemed	O
to	O
be	O
reporters	O
rather	O
than	O
media	O
leaders	O
have	O
an	O
orange	O
badge	O
,	O
it	O
's	O
purple	O
for	O
technicians	O
and	O
green	O
for	O
the	O
entourage	O
that	O
cameron	PERS
and	O
the	O
other	O
bigwigs	O
will	O
have	O
in	O
tow	O
.	O
traditionally	O
,	O
the	O
sign	O
that	O
you	O
have	O
really	O
made	O
it	O
is	O
a	O
hologram	O
on	O
your	O
full	O
participants	O
badge	O
:	O
this	O
gets	O
you	O
access	O
to	O
an	O
igwel	O
(	O
``	O
informal	O
gathering	O
of	O
world	O
economic	O
leaders	O
''	O
)	O
,	O
the	O
behind-closed-doors	O
sessions	O
where	O
the	O
real	O
davos	LOC
business	O
is	O
done	O
.	O
>	O
=the	O
theme	O
of	O
this	O
year	O
's	O
meeting	O
is	O
dynamic	O
resilience	O
,	O
which	O
,	O
if	O
it	O
means	O
anything	O
at	O
all	O
,	O
suggests	O
companies	O
should	O
hope	O
for	O
the	O
best	O
and	O
prepare	O
for	O
the	O
worst	O
.	O
sd	O
shibulal	O
(	O
shibu	O
)	O
,	O
chief	O
executive	O
of	O
the	O
indian-based	O
multinational	O
infosys	O
,	O
said	O
:	O
``	O
in	O
the	O
backdrop	O
of	O
a	O
challenging	O
macro-economic	O
environment	O
,	O
business	O
leaders	O
are	O
grappling	O
with	O
the	O
need	O
to	O
drive	O
growth	O
and	O
profitability	O
.	O
the	O
most	O
recent	O
global	O
economic	O
turmoil	O
is	O
not	O
the	O
first	O
of	O
its	O
kind	O
and	O
it	O
will	O
certainly	O
not	O
be	O
the	O
last	O
.	O
in	O
fact	O
,	O
the	O
frequency	O
of	O
their	O
occurrence	O
is	O
only	O
likely	O
to	O
increase	O
in	O
the	O
years	O
ahead	O
.	O
changing	O
business	O
cycles	O
are	O
here	O
to	O
stay	O
.	O
''	O
jennings	PERS
says	O
there	O
are	O
two	O
big	O
problems	O
:	O
businesses	O
are	O
hoarding	O
their	O
cash	O
and	O
consumers	O
do	O
n't	O
have	O
enough	O
money	O
to	O
spend	O
.	O
``	O
the	O
magic	O
mountain	O
is	O
full	O
of	O
dead	O
money	O
.	O
there	O
is	O
a	O
trillion	O
dollars	O
on	O
corporate	O
balance	O
sheets	O
doing	O
nothing	O
,	O
''	O
said	O
jennings	PERS
.	O
the	O
answer	O
to	O
a	O
lack	O
of	O
global	O
demand	O
is	O
simple	O
,	O
he	O
insisted	O
:	O
``	O
give	O
the	O
world	O
a	O
pay	O
rise	O
.	O
''	O
>	O
=once	O
the	O
day	O
's	O
formal	O
business	O
is	O
over	O
,	O
the	O
main	O
action	O
shifts	O
to	O
the	O
belvedere	O
hotel	O
for	O
party	O
time	O
.	O
in	O
previous	O
years	O
-	O
before	O
their	O
tax-avoiding	O
exploits	O
won	O
them	O
the	O
reputation	O
of	O
robber	O
barons	O
in	O
chinos	O
-	O
the	O
hottest	O
ticket	O
was	O
the	O
google	ORG
bash	O
on	O
the	O
friday	O
night	O
.	O
this	O
year	O
,	O
participants	O
can	O
rub	O
shoulders	O
with	O
charlize	O
theron	O
at	O
a	O
global	O
fund	O
event	O
in	O
support	O
of	O
a	O
push	O
to	O
fight	O
aids	O
,	O
tb	O
and	O
malaria	O
or	O
improve	O
their	O
minds	O
over	O
port	O
and	O
stilton	O
with	O
the	O
alumni	O
of	O
oxford	ORG
university	ORG
.	O
davos	LOC
:	O
what	O
can	O
we	O
expect	O
from	O
world	O
leaders	O
'	O
trip	O
up	O
the	O
magic	O
mountain	O
?	O
full	O
text	O
·	O
for	O
51	O
weeks	O
of	O
the	O
year	O
,	O
davos	LOC
is	O
just	O
another	O
swiss	O
mountain	O
resort	O
,	O
an	O
architecturally	O
drab	O
strip	O
town	O
5,000	O
feet	O
up	O
in	O
the	O
alps	O
.	O
but	O
at	O
the	O
end	O
of	O
january	O
the	O
world	O
's	O
movers	O
and	O
shakers	O
arrive	O
for	O
five	O
days	O
of	O
chin-wagging	O
,	O
deal-making	O
and	O
partying	O
at	O
the	O
annual	O
get-together	O
of	O
the	O
world	O
economic	O
forum	O
.	O
the	O
2,500	O
participants	O
this	O
year	O
include	O
almost	O
40	O
heads	O
of	O
state	O
and	O
government	O
,	O
finance	O
ministers	O
,	O
central	O
bank	O
governors	O
,	O
scientists	O
,	O
artists	O
,	O
trade	O
unionists	O
,	O
anti-poverty	O
campaigners	O
and	O
,	O
of	O
course	O
,	O
the	O
highest	O
concentration	O
of	O
billionaires	O
on	O
the	O
planet	O
.	O
angela	PERS
merkel	PERS
,	O
david	PERS
cameron	PERS
and	O
dmitry	O
medvedev	O
are	O
among	O
the	O
keynote	O
speakers	O
.	O
mali	LOC
,	O
the	O
middle	LOC
east	LOC
,	O
europe	LOC
's	O
debt	O
crisis	O
and	O
the	O
us	LOC
fiscal	O
cliff	O
will	O
be	O
on	O
the	O
agenda	O
.	O
george	PERS
osborne	PERS
is	O
due	O
to	O
be	O
in	O
town	O
when	O
britain	LOC
's	O
fourth-quarter	O
growth	O
figures	O
are	O
released	O
on	O
friday	O
.	O
on	O
the	O
basis	O
of	O
the	O
latest	O
evidence	O
,	O
it	O
may	O
be	O
more	O
bad	O
news	O
for	O
the	O
chancellor	O
.	O
·	O
expect	O
coverage	O
of	O
the	O
43rd	O
meeting	O
of	O
the	O
world	O
economic	O
forum	O
to	O
be	O
peppered	O
with	O
references	O
to	O
thomas	PERS
mann	PERS
,	O
who	O
put	O
davos	LOC
on	O
the	O
map	O
with	O
his	O
book	O
the	O
magic	O
mountain	O
.	O
the	O
story	O
,	O
set	O
in	O
a	O
sanitorium	O
treating	O
patients	O
suffering	O
from	O
tuberculosis	O
,	O
provides	O
an	O
appropriate	O
metaphor	O
for	O
the	O
global	O
economy	O
still	O
ailing	O
more	O
than	O
four-and-a-half	O
years	O
after	O
the	O
collapse	O
of	O
lehman	ORG
brothers	ORG
.	O
is	O
global	O
capitalism	O
going	O
through	O
prolonged	O
period	O
of	O
convalescence	O
or	O
is	O
it	O
suffering	O
from	O
a	O
incurable	O
sickness	O
?	O
most	O
of	O
the	O
chief	O
executives	O
and	O
policy-makers	O
will	O
,	O
unsurprisingly	O
,	O
opt	O
for	O
the	O
former	O
but	O
the	O
davos	LOC
mood	O
is	O
much	O
more	O
sombre	O
than	O
it	O
was	O
in	O
the	O
boom	O
years	O
before	O
the	O
crash	O
and	O
the	O
biggest	O
global	O
risk	O
is	O
deemed	O
to	O
be	O
rising	O
inequality	O
.	O
·	O
ian	O
fleming	O
was	O
another	O
author	O
familiar	O
with	O
the	O
town	O
.	O
in	O
his	O
novel	O
on	O
her	O
majesty	O
's	O
secret	O
service	O
,	O
bond	O
flies	O
up	O
the	O
davos	LOC
valley	O
to	O
blofeld	O
's	O
mountain-top	O
lair	O
by	O
helicopter	O
-	O
the	O
mode	O
of	O
transport	O
favoured	O
by	O
world	O
leaders	O
and	O
those	O
masters	O
of	O
the	O
universe	O
who	O
are	O
not	O
just	O
rich	O
but	O
seriously	O
loaded	O
.	O
for	O
lesser	O
mortals	O
,	O
there	O
are	O
two	O
choices	O
:	O
road	O
or	O
rail	O
.	O
the	O
journey	O
by	O
coach	O
or	O
limo	O
is	O
quicker	O
,	O
but	O
the	O
three-hour	O
train	O
ride	O
is	O
a	O
real	O
delight	O
.	O
the	O
last	O
hour	O
on	O
the	O
mountain	O
track	O
from	O
landquart	O
is	O
one	O
of	O
the	O
great	O
rail	O
experiences	O
,	O
particularly	O
in	O
late	O
afternoon	O
when	O
the	O
sun	O
is	O
setting	O
over	O
the	O
alps	O
.	O
needless	O
to	O
say	O
,	O
the	O
trains	O
keep	O
running	O
when	O
it	O
is	O
snowing	O
.	O
·	O
there	O
was	O
a	O
time	O
when	O
organised	O
labour	O
was	O
not	O
welcome	O
at	O
davos	LOC
,	O
which	O
as	O
recently	O
as	O
the	O
1990s	O
was	O
an	O
employers-only	O
affair	O
.	O
union	O
leaders	O
used	O
to	O
hold	O
a	O
press	O
conference	O
in	O
the	O
hotel	O
next	O
to	O
the	O
conference	O
centre	O
but	O
are	O
now	O
included	O
as	O
part	O
of	O
the	O
family	O
along	O
with	O
development	O
charities	O
such	O
as	O
oxfam	O
and	O
thinktanks	O
such	O
as	O
the	O
new	ORG
economics	ORG
foundation	ORG
.	O
jennings	PERS
says	O
union	O
concerns	O
are	O
taken	O
seriously	O
by	O
klaus	PERS
schwab	PERS
,	O
the	O
man	O
who	O
founded	O
the	O
wef	O
in	O
1971	O
and	O
still	O
presides	O
over	O
its	O
annual	O
meeting	O
.	O
despite	O
lacking	O
only	O
the	O
white	O
cat	O
to	O
be	O
a	O
blofeld	O
lookalike	O
,	O
schwab	PERS
champions	O
what	O
he	O
calls	O
inclusive	O
globalisation	O
.	O
·	O
some	O
,	O
though	O
,	O
are	O
more	O
included	O
than	O
others	O
.	O
status	O
in	O
davos	LOC
is	O
denoted	O
by	O
your	O
badge	O
:	O
full	O
participants	O
get	O
a	O
white	O
badge	O
with	O
a	O
blue	O
line	O
;	O
their	O
spouses	O
get	O
a	O
plain	O
white	O
badge	O
.	O
journalists	O
who	O
are	O
deemed	O
to	O
be	O
reporters	O
rather	O
than	O
media	O
leaders	O
have	O
an	O
orange	O
badge	O
;	O
it	O
's	O
purple	O
for	O
technicians	O
and	O
green	O
for	O
the	O
entourage	O
that	O
cameron	PERS
and	O
the	O
other	O
bigwigs	O
will	O
have	O
in	O
tow	O
.	O
traditionally	O
,	O
the	O
sign	O
that	O
you	O
have	O
really	O
made	O
it	O
is	O
a	O
hologram	O
on	O
your	O
full	O
participants	O
badge	O
:	O
this	O
gets	O
you	O
access	O
to	O
an	O
igwel	O
(	O
an	O
informal	O
gathering	O
of	O
world	O
economic	O
leaders	O
)	O
,	O
the	O
behind-closed-doors	O
sessions	O
where	O
the	O
real	O
davos	LOC
business	O
is	O
done	O
.	O
·	O
the	O
theme	O
of	O
this	O
year	O
's	O
meeting	O
is	O
dynamic	O
resilience	O
,	O
which	O
,	O
if	O
it	O
means	O
anything	O
at	O
all	O
,	O
suggests	O
companies	O
should	O
hope	O
for	O
the	O
best	O
and	O
prepare	O
for	O
the	O
worst	O
.	O
sd	O
shibulal	O
(	O
shibu	O
)	O
,	O
chief	O
executive	O
of	O
the	O
indian-based	O
multinational	O
infosys	O
,	O
said	O
:	O
``	O
in	O
the	O
backdrop	O
of	O
a	O
challenging	O
macro-economic	O
environment	O
,	O
business	O
leaders	O
are	O
grappling	O
with	O
the	O
need	O
to	O
drive	O
growth	O
and	O
profitability	O
.	O
the	O
most	O
recent	O
global	O
economic	O
turmoil	O
is	O
not	O
the	O
first	O
of	O
its	O
kind	O
and	O
it	O
will	O
certainly	O
not	O
be	O
the	O
last	O
.	O
in	O
fact	O
,	O
the	O
frequency	O
of	O
their	O
occurrence	O
is	O
only	O
likely	O
to	O
increase	O
in	O
the	O
years	O
ahead	O
.	O
changing	O
business	O
cycles	O
are	O
here	O
to	O
stay	O
.	O
''	O
phil	PERS
jennings	PERS
,	O
general	O
secretary	O
of	O
the	O
global	O
union	O
uni	O
,	O
says	O
there	O
are	O
two	O
big	O
problems	O
:	O
businesses	O
are	O
hoarding	O
their	O
cash	O
and	O
consumers	O
do	O
n't	O
have	O
enough	O
money	O
to	O
spend	O
.	O
``	O
the	O
magic	O
mountain	O
is	O
full	O
of	O
dead	O
money	O
.	O
there	O
is	O
a	O
trillion	O
dollars	O
on	O
corporate	O
balance	O
sheets	O
doing	O
nothing	O
''	O
,	O
jennings	PERS
says	O
.	O
the	O
answer	O
to	O
a	O
lack	O
of	O
global	O
demand	O
is	O
simple	O
,	O
he	O
insists	O
:	O
``	O
give	O
the	O
world	O
a	O
pay	O
rise	O
''	O
.	O
·	O
once	O
the	O
day	O
's	O
formal	O
business	O
is	O
over	O
,	O
the	O
main	O
action	O
shifts	O
to	O
the	O
belvedere	O
hotel	O
for	O
party	O
time	O
.	O
in	O
previous	O
years	O
-	O
before	O
their	O
tax-avoiding	O
exploits	O
won	O
them	O
the	O
reputation	O
of	O
robber	O
barons	O
in	O
chinos	O
-the	O
hottest	O
ticket	O
was	O
the	O
google	ORG
bash	O
on	O
the	O
friday	O
night	O
.	O
this	O
year	O
,	O
instead	O
of	O
dad-dancing	O
to	O
loud	O
disco	O
music	O
,	O
participants	O
can	O
rub	O
shoulders	O
with	O
charlize	O
theron	O
at	O
a	O
global	O
fund	O
event	O
in	O
support	O
of	O
a	O
push	O
to	O
fight	O
aids	O
,	O
tb	O
and	O
malaria	O
or	O
improve	O
their	O
minds	O
over	O
port	O
and	O
stilton	O
with	O
the	O
alumni	O
of	O
oxford	ORG
university	ORG
.	O
national	O
:	O
special	O
report	O
:	O
fury	O
at	O
corporate	O
tax	O
avoidance	O
leads	O
to	O
call	O
for	O
a	O
global	O
response	O
:	O
anger	O
over	O
the	O
financial	O
affairs	O
of	O
multinationals	O
such	O
as	O
google	ORG
,	O
amazon	LOC
and	O
starbucks	ORG
is	O
gathering	O
momentum	O
at	O
westminster	O
.	O
now	O
the	O
uk	LOC
is	O
poised	O
to	O
lead	O
the	O
debate	O
about	O
international	O
tax	O
reform	O
at	O
next	O
month	O
's	O
g8	O
summit	O
huge	O
orange	O
and	O
green	O
cranes	O
hover	O
over	O
a	O
vast	O
building	O
site	O
at	O
king	O
's	O
cross	O
,	O
london	LOC
.	O
over	O
the	O
next	O
three	O
years	O
,	O
2.4	O
acres	O
of	O
this	O
site	O
will	O
be	O
transformed	O
into	O
a	O
million	O
square	O
feet	O
of	O
an	O
11-storey	O
headquarters	O
for	O
the	O
internet	O
giant	O
google	ORG
,	O
no	O
doubt	O
chock-a-block	O
with	O
colourful	O
big	O
brother-house-style	O
sofas	O
and	O
surreal	O
chill-out	O
zones	O
that	O
mark	O
out	O
its	O
other	O
70	O
offices	O
in	O
40	O
countries	O
.	O
the	O
property	O
deal	O
is	O
estimated	O
to	O
have	O
cost	O
around	O
£	O
1bn	O
and	O
was	O
heralded	O
by	O
the	O
site	O
's	O
development	O
consortium	O
as	O
the	O
``	O
most	O
significant	O
property	O
transaction	O
of	O
recent	O
years	O
''	O
.	O
``	O
this	O
is	O
a	O
big	O
investment	O
by	O
google	ORG
,	O
we	O
're	O
committing	O
further	O
to	O
the	O
uk	LOC
where	O
computing	O
and	O
the	O
web	O
were	O
invented	O
.	O
it	O
's	O
good	O
news	O
for	O
google	ORG
,	O
for	O
london	LOC
and	O
for	O
the	O
uk	LOC
,	O
''	O
said	O
matt	PERS
brittin	PERS
,	O
vice-president	O
for	O
northern	O
and	O
central	O
europe	LOC
,	O
when	O
the	O
purchase	O
was	O
announced	O
in	O
january	O
.	O
like	O
amazon	LOC
,	O
google	ORG
is	O
seeing	O
increasing	O
success	O
in	O
the	O
uk	LOC
where	O
one	O
in	O
every	O
$	O
10	O
of	O
sales	O
is	O
now	O
generated	O
.	O
yet	O
both	O
firms	O
claim	O
they	O
are	O
merely	O
touching	O
down	O
on	O
uk	LOC
soil	O
,	O
without	O
a	O
``	O
permanent	O
establishment	O
''	O
and	O
therefore	O
are	O
not	O
paying	O
tax	O
on	O
profits	O
from	O
billions	O
of	O
£	O
worth	O
of	O
sales	O
made	O
here	O
.	O
on	O
wednesday	O
,	O
google	ORG
won	O
the	O
advertiser	O
of	O
the	O
year	O
trophy	O
at	O
the	O
54th	O
annual	O
clio	O
awards	O
-	O
the	O
oscars	O
for	O
advertising	O
professionals	O
.	O
accepting	O
the	O
award	O
in	O
new	LOC
york	LOC
,	O
robert	PERS
wong	PERS
,	O
chief	O
creative	O
officer	O
of	O
google	ORG
creative	ORG
lab	ORG
,	O
said	O
:	O
``	O
at	O
the	O
highest	O
order	O
,	O
our	O
job	O
is	O
to	O
remind	O
the	O
world	O
what	O
it	O
is	O
they	O
love	O
about	O
google	ORG
.	O
''	O
that	O
popularity	O
has	O
hit	O
a	O
serious	O
snag	O
.	O
the	O
next	O
day	O
the	O
company	O
was	O
branded	O
``	O
evil	O
''	O
by	O
margaret	PERS
hodge	PERS
,	O
chair	O
of	O
the	O
public	O
accounts	O
committee	O
,	O
while	O
this	O
weekend	O
ed	PERS
miliband	PERS
called	O
it	O
``	O
irresponsible	O
''	O
.	O
``	O
if	O
everyone	O
approached	O
their	O
tax	O
affairs	O
as	O
some	O
of	O
these	O
companies	O
have	O
approached	O
theirs	O
we	O
would	O
n't	O
have	O
a	O
health	O
service	O
,	O
we	O
would	O
n't	O
have	O
an	O
education	O
system	O
,	O
''	O
he	O
said	O
.	O
along	O
with	O
amazon	LOC
and	O
,	O
before	O
that	O
,	O
starbucks	ORG
,	O
topshop	O
,	O
boots	O
,	O
vodafone	ORG
,	O
goldman	ORG
sachs	ORG
and	O
greene	O
king	O
,	O
google	ORG
is	O
the	O
latest	O
to	O
have	O
become	O
the	O
target	O
of	O
grassroots	O
hostility	O
towards	O
their	O
aggressive	O
tax	O
avoidance	O
policies	O
.	O
the	O
actions	O
of	O
these	O
corporations	O
are	O
not	O
illegal	O
,	O
nor	O
underhand	O
,	O
but	O
especially	O
when	O
we	O
're	O
all	O
supposed	O
to	O
be	O
in	O
austerity	O
together	O
,	O
jarring	O
horribly	O
with	O
public	O
opinion	O
.	O
something	O
``	O
does	O
n't	O
smell	O
right	O
''	O
,	O
as	O
the	O
guardian	O
's	O
editorial	O
said	O
this	O
weekend	O
,	O
after	O
it	O
ran	O
an	O
account	O
of	O
the	O
extent	O
of	O
amazon	LOC
's	O
dealings	O
in	O
the	O
uk	LOC
,	O
far	O
wider	O
than	O
what	O
its	O
tax	O
lawyers	O
are	O
implying	O
.	O
the	O
debate	O
is	O
now	O
raging	O
over	O
whether	O
these	O
companies	O
are	O
the	O
happy	O
beneficiaries	O
of	O
a	O
tax	O
system	O
knitted	O
with	O
loopholes	O
,	O
or	O
the	O
malicious	O
purveyors	O
of	O
smoke-and-mirror	O
accounting	O
.	O
hm	O
revenue	O
and	O
customs	O
claims	O
the	O
former	O
-	O
public	O
opinion	O
is	O
rolling	O
towards	O
the	O
latter	O
.	O
lin	PERS
homer	PERS
,	O
chief	O
executive	O
of	O
hmrc	O
,	O
claimed	O
the	O
public	O
do	O
n't	O
understand	O
.	O
asked	O
why	O
she	O
was	O
not	O
taking	O
a	O
tougher	O
line	O
with	O
internet	O
giants	O
,	O
she	O
told	O
the	O
public	O
accounts	O
committee	O
:	O
``	O
we	O
see	O
,	O
but	O
understand	O
more	O
fully	O
,	O
some	O
of	O
the	O
information	O
that	O
might	O
seem	O
to	O
the	O
general	O
public	O
to	O
be	O
surprising	O
.	O
''	O
but	O
campaigners	O
say	O
tax	O
collectors	O
and	O
leading	O
politicians	O
have	O
been	O
caught	O
out	O
;	O
too	O
engrossed	O
in	O
austerity	O
plans	O
,	O
they	O
are	O
scrabbling	O
to	O
keep	O
up	O
with	O
people	O
who	O
point	O
out	O
that	O
there	O
are	O
other	O
ways	O
to	O
balance	O
the	O
books	O
.	O
``	O
without	O
a	O
doubt	O
,	O
they	O
are	O
behind	O
the	O
curve	O
,	O
''	O
said	O
richard	PERS
murphy	PERS
,	O
a	O
chartered	O
accountant	O
,	O
economist	O
and	O
founder	O
of	O
tax	O
justice	O
network	O
.	O
``	O
they	O
have	O
all	O
been	O
caught	O
by	O
surprise	O
because	O
this	O
has	O
come	O
from	O
civil	O
society	O
,	O
a	O
campaign	O
that	O
has	O
been	O
going	O
on	O
for	O
almost	O
a	O
decade	O
but	O
has	O
only	O
been	O
picked	O
up	O
by	O
politicians	O
after	O
the	O
banking	O
crisis	O
when	O
they	O
suddenly	O
realised	O
they	O
were	O
desperately	O
short	O
of	O
cash	O
.	O
''	O
he	O
said	O
hmrc	O
had	O
been	O
ducking	O
tax	O
avoidance	O
completely	O
.	O
he	O
said	O
it	O
had	O
powers	O
to	O
tackle	O
any	O
suspect	O
tax	O
returns	O
of	O
foreign-based	O
companies	O
.	O
``	O
if	O
the	O
breach	O
is	O
blatant	O
,	O
then	O
they	O
can	O
act	O
.	O
what	O
we	O
have	O
n't	O
got	O
is	O
politicians	O
who	O
will	O
stand	O
up	O
to	O
this	O
.	O
it	O
's	O
a	O
critical	O
point	O
.	O
if	O
the	O
state	O
will	O
not	O
stand	O
up	O
for	O
its	O
right	O
to	O
tax	O
big	O
corporations	O
then	O
we	O
are	O
in	O
deep	O
trouble	O
.	O
''	O
uk	LOC
uncut	O
began	O
campaigning	O
on	O
the	O
issue	O
in	O
2010	O
and	O
it	O
was	O
its	O
legal	O
challenge	O
that	O
revealed	O
how	O
hmrc	O
waived	O
a	O
£	O
20m	O
bill	O
for	O
goldman	ORG
sachs	ORG
,	O
as	O
well	O
as	O
a	O
£	O
6bn	O
bill	O
to	O
vodafone	ORG
.	O
journalists	O
,	O
tax	O
experts	O
and	O
campaigners	O
have	O
been	O
investigating	O
and	O
exposing	O
the	O
tax	O
scams	O
being	O
perpetrated	O
by	O
big	O
businesses	O
for	O
far	O
longer	O
-	O
pointing	O
out	O
glaring	O
loopholes	O
in	O
britain	LOC
's	O
tax	O
system	O
.	O
when	O
matt	PERS
brittin	PERS
of	O
google	ORG
told	O
the	O
public	O
accounts	O
committee	O
in	O
november	O
2012	O
that	O
google	ORG
did	O
not	O
have	O
a	O
sales	O
presence	O
in	O
the	O
uk	LOC
,	O
it	O
was	O
the	O
news	O
agency	O
reuters	O
that	O
quickly	O
uncovered	O
evidence	O
to	O
the	O
contrary	O
,	O
resulting	O
in	O
brittin	PERS
being	O
recalled	O
in	O
front	O
of	O
the	O
committee	O
on	O
thursday	O
,	O
where	O
his	O
company	O
's	O
behaviour	O
was	O
described	O
as	O
``	O
devious	O
,	O
calculated	O
and	O
,	O
in	O
my	O
view	O
,	O
unethical	O
''	O
by	O
margaret	PERS
hodge	PERS
.	O
``	O
you	O
are	O
a	O
company	O
that	O
says	O
you	O
'do	O
no	O
evil	O
'	O
.	O
and	O
i	O
think	O
that	O
you	O
do	O
do	O
evil	O
,	O
''	O
said	O
hodge	PERS
,	O
referring	O
to	O
google	ORG
's	O
motto	O
,	O
``	O
do	O
n't	O
be	O
evil	O
''	O
.	O
amazon	LOC
may	O
also	O
be	O
recalled	O
,	O
after	O
numerous	O
whistleblowers	O
from	O
among	O
its	O
employees	O
approached	O
journalists	O
to	O
contest	O
official	O
accounts	O
of	O
its	O
trading	O
practices	O
within	O
britain	LOC
.	O
for	O
the	O
moment	O
the	O
government	O
's	O
line	O
is	O
that	O
this	O
is	O
a	O
global	O
problem	O
that	O
can	O
not	O
be	O
solved	O
unilaterally	O
.	O
on	O
monday	O
,	O
google	ORG
's	O
executive	O
chairman	O
,	O
eric	PERS
schmidt	PERS
,	O
will	O
meet	O
david	PERS
cameron	PERS
,	O
a	O
meeting	O
no	O
10	O
insists	O
is	O
not	O
about	O
tax	O
,	O
but	O
to	O
do	O
with	O
schmidt	PERS
's	O
role	O
on	O
the	O
prime	O
minister	O
's	O
business	O
advisory	O
group	O
.	O
labour	O
leader	O
ed	PERS
miliband	PERS
,	O
who	O
is	O
due	O
to	O
give	O
a	O
speech	O
to	O
google	ORG
employees	O
on	O
wednesday	O
,	O
has	O
backed	O
a	O
``	O
country	O
by	O
country	O
''	O
international	O
scheme	O
on	O
tax	O
declaration	O
but	O
says	O
that	O
he	O
is	O
concerned	O
that	O
no	O
firm	O
proposals	O
have	O
so	O
far	O
been	O
put	O
forward	O
for	O
the	O
g8	O
.	O
``	O
you	O
have	O
to	O
have	O
much	O
greater	O
transparency	O
.	O
tax	O
offices	O
have	O
to	O
know	O
country	O
by	O
country	O
how	O
much	O
profit	O
people	O
are	O
making	O
,	O
how	O
much	O
tax	O
they	O
are	O
paying	O
.	O
unless	O
you	O
know	O
that	O
you	O
wo	O
n't	O
get	O
to	O
the	O
bottom	O
of	O
what	O
is	O
happening	O
.	O
you	O
have	O
to	O
deal	O
with	O
tax	O
avoidance	O
schemes	O
.	O
you	O
have	O
to	O
deal	O
with	O
tax	O
havens	O
.	O
``	O
we	O
are	O
saying	O
there	O
has	O
to	O
be	O
a	O
big	O
,	O
big	O
push	O
on	O
this	O
.	O
it	O
has	O
to	O
be	O
done	O
internationally	O
and	O
if	O
it	O
is	O
not	O
done	O
internationally	O
,	O
britain	LOC
should	O
act	O
on	O
its	O
own	O
.	O
''	O
all	O
eyes	O
will	O
be	O
on	O
what	O
,	O
if	O
anything	O
,	O
can	O
be	O
agreed	O
at	O
next	O
month	O
's	O
g8	O
meeting	O
in	O
scotland	LOC
,	O
where	O
,	O
as	O
host	O
of	O
the	O
event	O
,	O
david	PERS
cameron	PERS
has	O
pledged	O
to	O
put	O
tax	O
avoidance	O
at	O
the	O
top	O
of	O
the	O
agenda	O
as	O
he	O
insists	O
it	O
is	O
an	O
issue	O
for	O
international	O
co-operation	O
rather	O
than	O
unilateral	O
action	O
.	O
and	O
it	O
would	O
not	O
be	O
just	O
the	O
wealthy	O
who	O
would	O
be	O
watching	O
the	O
progress	O
of	O
the	O
talks	O
,	O
said	O
melanie	PERS
ward	PERS
,	O
head	O
of	O
advocacy	O
at	O
actionaid	ORG
uk	ORG
.	O
``	O
at	O
the	O
g20	O
summit	O
in	O
2009	O
,	O
gordon	PERS
brown	PERS
led	O
the	O
beginnings	O
of	O
a	O
global	O
crackdown	O
on	O
tax	O
havens	O
and	O
,	O
for	O
the	O
first	O
time	O
,	O
put	O
an	O
emphasis	O
on	O
helping	O
poor	O
countries	O
to	O
deal	O
with	O
the	O
losses	O
to	O
tax	O
havens	O
that	O
cost	O
them	O
three	O
times	O
as	O
much	O
as	O
they	O
receive	O
in	O
aid	O
each	O
year	O
.	O
but	O
in	O
the	O
intervening	O
years	O
,	O
tax	O
dodging	O
died	O
away	O
as	O
a	O
big	O
uk	LOC
issue	O
,	O
''	O
she	O
said	O
.	O
``	O
it	O
's	O
shot	O
back	O
up	O
the	O
agenda	O
with	O
rising	O
public	O
anger	O
over	O
the	O
antics	O
of	O
starbucks	ORG
,	O
google	ORG
,	O
amazon	LOC
and	O
reports	O
of	O
sweetheart	O
deals	O
between	O
the	O
government	O
and	O
goldman	ORG
sachs	ORG
.	O
the	O
uk	LOC
should	O
close	O
tax	O
loopholes	O
,	O
but	O
the	O
truth	O
is	O
that	O
the	O
uk	LOC
is	O
responsible	O
for	O
one	O
in	O
five	O
of	O
the	O
world	O
's	O
tax	O
havens	O
in	O
the	O
form	O
of	O
many	O
of	O
the	O
crown	O
dependencies	O
and	O
overseas	O
territories	O
.	O
these	O
tax	O
havens	O
are	O
a	O
leech	O
,	O
sucking	O
resources	O
from	O
the	O
uk	LOC
and	O
poor	O
countries	O
alike	O
,	O
so	O
action	O
needs	O
to	O
start	O
with	O
pulling	O
them	O
into	O
line	O
.	O
``	O
ultimately	O
,	O
this	O
is	O
a	O
global	O
problem	O
and	O
the	O
solutions	O
are	O
global	O
.	O
that	O
's	O
why	O
david	PERS
cameron	PERS
must	O
lead	O
the	O
g8	O
to	O
deliver	O
an	O
unprecedented	O
assault	O
on	O
tax	O
dodging	O
when	O
it	O
meets	O
next	O
month	O
.	O
this	O
means	O
calling	O
time	O
on	O
tax	O
havens	O
and	O
ensuring	O
that	O
poor	O
countries	O
are	O
at	O
the	O
heart	O
of	O
any	O
new	O
deal	O
to	O
share	O
tax	O
information	O
between	O
countries	O
.	O
``	O
there	O
is	O
a	O
serious	O
risk	O
that	O
a	O
deal	O
will	O
be	O
agreed	O
between	O
rich	O
countries	O
and	O
tax	O
havens	O
that	O
would	O
leave	O
poor	O
countries	O
out	O
in	O
the	O
cold	O
.	O
this	O
would	O
be	O
entirely	O
unacceptable	O
.	O
tax	O
dodging	O
is	O
hurting	O
ordinary	O
people	O
,	O
wherever	O
in	O
the	O
world	O
they	O
live	O
.	O
''	O
richard	PERS
murphy	PERS
said	O
the	O
moral	O
case	O
for	O
international	O
action	O
had	O
already	O
been	O
won	O
.	O
``	O
we	O
now	O
just	O
have	O
to	O
beat	O
off	O
the	O
accountants	O
and	O
businesses	O
who	O
oppose	O
democratic	O
accountability	O
to	O
the	O
state	O
to	O
get	O
it	O
,	O
''	O
he	O
said	O
.	O
on	O
other	O
pages	O
google	ORG
welcomes	O
a	O
debate	O
on	O
tax	O
reform	O
eric	PERS
schmidt	PERS
,	O
comment	O
,	O
page	O
36	O
how	O
our	O
tax	O
inspectors	O
fell	O
for	O
tycoons	O
nick	PERS
cohen	PERS
,	O
comment	O
,	O
page	O
37	O
amazon	LOC
tax	O
arrangements	O
are	O
a	O
work	O
of	O
art	O
david	PERS
mitchell	PERS
,	O
new	O
review	O
,	O
page	O
7	O
captions	O
:	O
margaret	PERS
hodge	PERS
called	O
google	ORG
's	O
behaviour	O
'devious	O
,	O
calculated	O
and	O
.	O
.	O
.	O
unethical	O
'	O
.	O
google	ORG
staff	O
lunch	O
outside	O
its	O
corporate	O
headquarters	O
in	O
california	LOC
,	O
above	O
.	O
alongside	O
other	O
big	O
multinationals	O
,	O
such	O
as	O
starbucks	ORG
,	O
far	O
left	O
,	O
and	O
topshop	O
,	O
left	O
,	O
it	O
has	O
been	O
accused	O
of	O
uk	LOC
tax	O
avoidance	O
on	O
a	O
massive	O
scale	O
.	O
redux	O
,	O
alamy	O
leading	O
article	O
:	O
finance	O
and	O
fairness	O
:	O
time	O
for	O
a	O
moral	O
crusade	O
against	O
tax	O
scams	O
africa	LOC
is	O
on	O
the	O
crest	O
of	O
a	O
global	O
commodities	O
boom	O
.	O
mozambique	LOC
and	O
tanzania	LOC
are	O
emerging	O
as	O
major	O
exporters	O
of	O
natural	O
gas	O
;	O
guinea	LOC
and	O
sierra	LOC
leone	LOC
have	O
iron	O
ore	O
;	O
while	O
in	O
the	O
democratic	O
republic	O
of	O
the	O
congo	LOC
,	O
cobalt	O
mining	O
is	O
booming	O
.	O
strong	O
demand	O
will	O
drive	O
another	O
decade	O
of	O
high	O
prices	O
for	O
africa	LOC
's	O
natural	O
resources	O
.	O
foreign	O
investment	O
is	O
on	O
the	O
rise	O
.	O
but	O
so	O
too	O
are	O
avarice	O
and	O
corruption	O
,	O
on	O
such	O
a	O
scale	O
that	O
instead	O
of	O
enjoying	O
significant	O
investment	O
in	O
healthcare	O
,	O
education	O
and	O
agriculture	O
,	O
africa	LOC
is	O
again	O
being	O
plundered	O
.	O
that	O
is	O
the	O
view	O
of	O
the	O
annual	O
africa	LOC
progress	O
report	O
,	O
published	O
last	O
week	O
,	O
produced	O
by	O
a	O
panel	O
of	O
luminaries	O
led	O
by	O
the	O
former	O
un	ORG
secretary-general	O
kofi	PERS
annan	PERS
.	O
large-scale	O
tax	O
avoidance	O
and	O
evasion	O
,	O
financial	O
transfers	O
,	O
offshore	O
registered	O
companies	O
and	O
secret	O
mining	O
deals	O
cost	O
africa	LOC
£	O
25bn	O
a	O
year	O
,	O
twice	O
as	O
much	O
as	O
it	O
receives	O
in	O
aid	O
.	O
``	O
these	O
are	O
global	O
problems	O
that	O
demand	O
multilateral	O
solutions	O
,	O
''	O
annan	PERS
said	O
last	O
week	O
.	O
the	O
g7	O
leaders	O
'	O
meeting	O
in	O
britain	LOC
yesterday	O
voiced	O
their	O
determination	O
to	O
combat	O
tax	O
avoidance	O
.	O
david	PERS
cameron	PERS
has	O
made	O
tax	O
and	O
transparency	O
key	O
subjects	O
for	O
next	O
month	O
's	O
g8	O
meeting	O
at	O
lough	O
erne	O
,	O
northern	LOC
ireland	LOC
.	O
george	PERS
osborne	PERS
yesterday	O
emphasised	O
how	O
central	O
the	O
issue	O
is	O
to	O
government	O
strategy	O
and	O
,	O
as	O
we	O
report	O
,	O
will	O
pursue	O
his	O
tax-reforming	O
strategy	O
at	O
a	O
meeting	O
of	O
eu	LOC
finance	O
ministers	O
later	O
this	O
week	O
.	O
this	O
is	O
admirable	O
,	O
but	O
a	O
glimpse	O
at	O
the	O
africa	LOC
progress	O
report	O
shows	O
how	O
much	O
work	O
there	O
is	O
to	O
do	O
.	O
and	O
not	O
just	O
in	O
tightening	O
up	O
international	O
legislation	O
,	O
but	O
also	O
in	O
effecting	O
a	O
cultural	O
change	O
in	O
the	O
way	O
the	O
leading	O
firms	O
conduct	O
their	O
business	O
.	O
the	O
scale	O
of	O
greed	O
,	O
the	O
absence	O
of	O
conscience	O
and	O
the	O
stupidity	O
of	O
not	O
investing	O
in	O
the	O
creation	O
of	O
stable	O
future	O
markets	O
in	O
africa	LOC
are	O
laid	O
bare	O
in	O
the	O
report	O
.	O
take	O
the	O
example	O
of	O
the	O
eurasian	ORG
natural	ORG
resources	ORG
corporation	ORG
(	O
enrc	ORG
)	O
in	O
the	O
democratic	O
republic	O
of	O
congo	LOC
(	O
drc	O
)	O
.	O
the	O
ftse	O
100	O
mining	O
company	O
is	O
heavily	O
criticised	O
for	O
``	O
opaque	O
concession	O
trading	O
''	O
.	O
five	O
mining	O
stakes	O
bought	O
by	O
the	O
company	O
in	O
2010-2012	O
were	O
state	O
assets	O
allegedly	O
sold	O
at	O
far	O
less	O
than	O
their	O
true	O
value	O
.	O
the	O
cost	O
in	O
lost	O
revenues	O
to	O
the	O
drc	O
is	O
calculated	O
at	O
$	O
1.3bn	O
-	O
equivalent	O
to	O
its	O
health	O
and	O
education	O
budgets	O
combined	O
.	O
multiple	O
offshore	O
vehicles	O
were	O
deployed	O
to	O
conceal	O
the	O
secretive	O
deals	O
,	O
precisely	O
the	O
sort	O
of	O
lack	O
of	O
transparency	O
that	O
the	O
g8	O
is	O
committed	O
to	O
tackling	O
.	O
the	O
annan	PERS
report	O
also	O
highlights	O
how	O
,	O
in	O
the	O
four	O
years	O
to	O
2009	O
,	O
half-a-million	O
copper	O
mine	O
workers	O
in	O
zambia	LOC
paid	O
a	O
higher	O
rate	O
of	O
tax	O
than	O
the	O
major	O
multinational	O
mining	O
firms	O
that	O
were	O
harvesting	O
billions	O
of	O
dollars	O
in	O
profits	O
.	O
how	O
can	O
this	O
be	O
right	O
?	O
and	O
why	O
has	O
such	O
behaviour	O
become	O
acceptable	O
?	O
the	O
examples	O
are	O
everywhere	O
.	O
in	O
2011	O
,	O
google	ORG
paid	O
just	O
£	O
6m	O
in	O
corporation	O
tax	O
on	O
revenues	O
of	O
£	O
2.5bn	O
in	O
the	O
uk	LOC
.	O
its	O
chairman	O
rightly	O
said	O
that	O
they	O
``	O
comply	O
with	O
the	O
law	O
''	O
.	O
the	O
problem	O
is	O
that	O
our	O
law	O
has	O
not	O
found	O
a	O
way	O
of	O
adequately	O
taxing	O
companies	O
such	O
as	O
google	ORG
.	O
in	O
the	O
meantime	O
,	O
such	O
firms	O
use	O
every	O
conceivable	O
mechanism	O
to	O
avoid	O
paying	O
tax	O
.	O
they	O
then	O
offer	O
a	O
risible	O
justification	O
,	O
such	O
as	O
schmidt	O
did	O
when	O
he	O
said	O
that	O
google	ORG
employs	O
2,000	O
people	O
in	O
britain	LOC
.	O
not	O
good	O
enough	O
.	O
google	ORG
employs	O
people	O
-	O
try	O
making	O
money	O
without	O
doing	O
that	O
-	O
and	O
makes	O
billions	O
in	O
the	O
process	O
,	O
but	O
puts	O
practically	O
nothing	O
back	O
into	O
the	O
country	O
from	O
which	O
it	O
harvests	O
£	O
2.5bn	O
annually	O
.	O
nothing	O
to	O
help	O
finance	O
the	O
education	O
of	O
the	O
next	O
2,000	O
employees	O
from	O
this	O
country	O
.	O
nothing	O
to	O
help	O
maintain	O
the	O
physical	O
infrastructure	O
of	O
a	O
country	O
where	O
it	O
does	O
business	O
.	O
nothing	O
to	O
help	O
subsidise	O
the	O
cultural	O
riches	O
that	O
make	O
this	O
country	O
an	O
attractive	O
place	O
to	O
live	O
and	O
work	O
.	O
nothing	O
to	O
help	O
pay	O
for	O
the	O
judicial	O
,	O
legal	O
and	O
police	O
institutions	O
that	O
make	O
the	O
country	O
a	O
safe	O
and	O
civil	O
place	O
to	O
do	O
business	O
.	O
we	O
as	O
a	O
society	O
-	O
and	O
that	O
includes	O
business	O
behemoths	O
such	O
as	O
google	ORG
-	O
have	O
responsibilities	O
to	O
deal	O
fairly	O
with	O
communities	O
with	O
whom	O
we	O
trade	O
.	O
the	O
pioneers	O
of	O
benevolent	O
capitalism	O
recognised	O
their	O
obligations	O
to	O
help	O
build	O
a	O
decent	O
society	O
from	O
which	O
they	O
profited	O
.	O
but	O
google	ORG
is	O
not	O
alone	O
.	O
last	O
week	O
,	O
it	O
was	O
announced	O
that	O
more	O
than	O
half	O
of	O
britain	LOC
's	O
wealthiest	O
people	O
were	O
hiding	O
billions	O
of	O
£	O
in	O
offshore	O
havens	O
to	O
evade	O
tax	O
,	O
helped	O
by	O
200	O
accountants	O
and	O
advisers	O
.	O
tax	O
evasion	O
is	O
illegal	O
but	O
tax	O
avoidance	O
,	O
finding	O
legitimate	O
loopholes	O
to	O
avoid	O
paying	O
a	O
fair	O
tithe	O
as	O
a	O
citizen	O
,	O
is	O
rampant	O
.	O
last	O
year	O
,	O
a	O
tax	O
justice	O
network	O
(	O
tjn	O
)	O
report	O
revealed	O
that	O
the	O
global	O
super-rich	O
have	O
hidden	O
£	O
13tn	O
of	O
wealth	O
offshore	O
.	O
illumination	O
about	O
the	O
true	O
state	O
of	O
the	O
uk	LOC
's	O
financial	O
affairs	O
has	O
been	O
helped	O
by	O
the	O
work	O
of	O
the	O
public	O
accounts	O
committee	O
,	O
chaired	O
by	O
margaret	PERS
hodge	PERS
,	O
an	O
invaluable	O
fiscal	O
watchdog	O
.	O
last	O
month	O
,	O
it	O
castigated	O
the	O
four	O
large	O
accountancy	O
firms	O
,	O
deloitte	ORG
,	O
ernst	O
and	O
young	O
,	O
kpmg	ORG
and	O
pwc	ORG
,	O
which	O
earned	O
$	O
25bn	O
from	O
advising	O
on	O
tax	O
avoidance	O
.	O
in	O
the	O
1960s	O
,	O
accountants	O
deemed	O
avoidance	O
an	O
undignified	O
practice	O
,	O
acknowledging	O
that	O
tax	O
is	O
a	O
collective	O
obligation	O
to	O
build	O
a	O
decent	O
society	O
.	O
now	O
it	O
is	O
a	O
lucrative	O
business	O
-	O
finding	O
new	O
ways	O
to	O
short-change	O
the	O
chancellor	O
and	O
rip	O
off	O
developing	O
countries	O
.	O
amazon	ORG
in	O
the	O
us	LOC
lobbied	O
effectively	O
for	O
20	O
years	O
to	O
avoid	O
paying	O
the	O
sales	O
tax	O
levied	O
on	O
``	O
bricks	O
and	O
mortar	O
''	O
retailers	O
it	O
competes	O
with	O
and	O
increasingly	O
puts	O
out	O
of	O
business	O
.	O
jacob	PERS
weisberg	PERS
,	O
writing	O
in	O
the	O
financial	O
times	O
,	O
pointed	O
out	O
that	O
we	O
have	O
``	O
a	O
political	O
system	O
so	O
compromised	O
and	O
sclerotic	O
that	O
it	O
can	O
not	O
correct	O
even	O
the	O
most	O
straightforward	O
economic	O
unfairness	O
in	O
a	O
timely	O
fashion	O
''	O
.	O
the	O
average	O
taxpayer	O
can	O
only	O
rage	O
.	O
but	O
what	O
is	O
to	O
be	O
done	O
?	O
globally	O
,	O
changes	O
are	O
under	O
way	O
.	O
from	O
july	O
,	O
for	O
instance	O
,	O
in	O
singapore	LOC
,	O
laundering	O
profits	O
earned	O
from	O
tax	O
evasion	O
will	O
be	O
a	O
crime	O
,	O
while	O
luxembourg	LOC
ends	O
its	O
bank	O
secrecy	O
policy	O
in	O
2105	O
.	O
more	O
is	O
required	O
.	O
the	O
international	O
tax	O
system	O
is	O
a	O
century	O
old	O
and	O
needs	O
radical	O
redesign	O
,	O
not	O
repair	O
.	O
tjn	O
proposes	O
a	O
unitary	O
tax	O
system	O
of	O
transnational	O
corporations	O
,	O
``	O
to	O
tax	O
them	O
according	O
to	O
where	O
their	O
genuine	O
economic	O
activity	O
is	O
,	O
rather	O
than	O
where	O
their	O
tax	O
advisers	O
pretend	O
it	O
is	O
''	O
.	O
the	O
us	LOC
dodd-frank	O
act	O
that	O
requires	O
full	O
disclosure	O
of	O
payments	O
by	O
resource-extraction	O
companies	O
to	O
foreign	O
governments	O
needs	O
to	O
be	O
built	O
on	O
-	O
and	O
comparable	O
eu	LOC
legislation	O
is	O
required	O
.	O
at	O
home	O
,	O
hmrc	O
requires	O
more	O
,	O
not	O
fewer	O
,	O
resources	O
.	O
serious	O
questions	O
too	O
need	O
to	O
be	O
asked	O
of	O
george	PERS
osborne	PERS
's	O
decisions	O
at	O
the	O
last	O
budget	O
that	O
appear	O
to	O
make	O
it	O
even	O
easier	O
for	O
companies	O
to	O
shift	O
their	O
profit	O
into	O
tax	O
haven	O
subsidiaries	O
.	O
tax	O
havens	O
should	O
end	O
.	O
political	O
will	O
,	O
co-ordinated	O
international	O
action	O
,	O
more	O
public	O
education	O
and	O
tax	O
systems	O
that	O
work	O
for	O
all	O
might	O
give	O
africa	LOC
a	O
fresh	O
beginning	O
.	O
we	O
also	O
need	O
to	O
create	O
a	O
new	O
moral	O
consensus	O
that	O
says	O
those	O
companies	O
and	O
individuals	O
who	O
pocket	O
obscene	O
amounts	O
of	O
wealth	O
without	O
paying	O
their	O
civic	O
dues	O
should	O
be	O
denied	O
our	O
custom	O
and	O
treated	O
instead	O
as	O
the	O
freeloading	O
pariahs	O
they	O
are	O
.	O
alex	PERS
prats	PERS
:	O
developing	O
countries	O
have	O
been	O
suffering	O
the	O
effects	O
of	O
aggressive	O
tax	O
avoidance	O
for	O
decades	O
over	O
the	O
last	O
few	O
years	O
,	O
it	O
has	O
been	O
painfully	O
clear	O
that	O
we	O
have	O
a	O
problem	O
-	O
courtesy	O
of	O
starbucks	ORG
,	O
amazon	ORG
,	O
google	ORG
,	O
ikea	ORG
and	O
all	O
the	O
other	O
multinationals	O
which	O
pay	O
laughably	O
little	O
tax	O
in	O
the	O
countries	O
where	O
they	O
are	O
so	O
successful	O
,	O
including	O
the	O
uk	LOC
.	O
the	O
situation	O
is	O
now	O
so	O
serious	O
that	O
even	O
normally	O
conservative	O
world	O
leaders	O
have	O
joined	O
the	O
growing	O
chorus	O
for	O
reform	O
.	O
only	O
this	O
week	O
,	O
david	PERS
cameron	PERS
wrote	O
to	O
his	O
european	O
counterparts	O
,	O
declaring	O
that	O
'tax	O
evasion	O
and	O
aggressive	O
avoidance	O
are	O
global	O
problems	O
that	O
require	O
truly	O
global	O
solutions	O
'	O
and	O
promising	O
a	O
'turning	O
point	O
'	O
against	O
tax	O
evasion	O
when	O
the	O
uk	LOC
hosts	O
a	O
meeting	O
of	O
g8	O
leaders	O
in	O
june	O
.	O
two	O
days	O
later	O
,	O
mps	O
on	O
parliament	O
's	O
influential	O
public	ORG
accounts	ORG
committee	ORG
warned	O
that	O
multinational	O
companies	O
-	O
aided	O
and	O
abetted	O
by	O
the	O
big	O
four	O
accountancy	O
firms	O
-	O
are	O
exploiting	O
loopholes	O
in	O
global	O
rules	O
in	O
order	O
to	O
avoid	O
tax	O
in	O
the	O
countries	O
where	O
they	O
actually	O
do	O
business	O
.	O
'the	O
uk	LOC
must	O
take	O
the	O
lead	O
in	O
demanding	O
the	O
urgent	O
reform	O
of	O
international	O
